<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2004/11/25/thanksgiving/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2004 19:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2952</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[It's Thanksgiving Day, my favorite holiday and a good time to talk about what I'm thankful for.

I'm thankful for my smart, caring, supportive and beautiful (new) wife and my somewhat smart and beautiful dogs who I spend the majority of my waking and sleeping life with and that they stick around even though I don't show them enough how thankful I am for them.

<cite><b>Update:</b> I've received a few comments about how the preceding paragraph shouldn't have lumped my wife and dogs together. Valid point. My intent was to mention the most important things to me in one paragraph. If I had kids, they'd be in there too. But my dogs are my kids. And I write this stuff off-the-cuff; it's not well-edited so there's plenty of mistakes, poorly-communicated thoughts and mis-spoken things said on this site -- if not, it'd be a part-time job to keep this site updated. And I'd like to point out that my wife didn't write a thing about being thankful for me, so there! :)</cite>

I'm thankful that I live in a quiet area surrounded by nature with plenty of privacy and some "interesting" neighbors who show me how fortunate I am.

I'm thankful for the lifestyle Gay &amp; I created together, that we created it <i>together</i> and even more thankful that the end is not in sight. :)

I'm thankful that I get to work at a job that I enjoy every second doing and for the opportunity to build something that is bigger than myself and my immediate existence. And I'm thankful that my job shows me how wonderful human beings can be and that the job's very nature helps me to enjoy life through the simple pleasure of food.

I am thankful that I have good health and, more importantly, the knowledge and ability to maintain that good health (because I want to live to be 300+).

I'm thankful that my family is also in good health and that I am able to communicate with all of them even though I live on the other side of the country (although I don't communicate with them enough).  And I'm thankful that they live on the other side of the country. ;)  (it's a joke!).

I'm thankful for my new in-laws who accepted me into their family without a fight (that I'm aware of). And I'm thankful that my new mother-in-law is so easy-going and doesn't mind a bit that I don't email her enough and enjoys our political arguments as much as she does. And, of course, I'm thankful that she probably won't read this. :)

I'm thankful for our old friends and that we've stayed in contact with them after moving way out to Vashon. And for our new friends on Vashon we've gained since moving here.

And finally, I'm thankful for the beer and wine I get to drink with friends tonight during dinner. :)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2952</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2004-11-25 11:01:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2004-11-25 19:01:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>thanksgiving</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>