<item>
		<title>The Catholic Bishop of Spokane wrote me:</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2006/02/18/the-catholic-bishop-of-spokane-wrote-me-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 21:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=3158</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="border:1px solid #666666;margin:10px;padding:10px;">
YOU MAY HAVE A SEXUAL ABUSE CLAIM AGAINST THE CATHOLIC DIOCESE OF SPOKANE

DID ANY PRIEST OR ANY OTHE PERSON CONNECTED WITH THE CATHOLIC DIOCESE OF SPOKANE, ITS PARISHES, SCHOOLS OR OTHER INSTITUTIONS:

* DO ANYTHING TO YOU SEXUALLY INAPPROPRIATE, OR HAVE YOU DO ANYTHING SEXUALLY INAPPROPRIATE
* TOUCH YOU OR HAVE YOU TOUCH HIM OR HER OR YOURSELF SEXUALLY, WHETHER CLOTHED OR UNCLOTHED
* INAPPROPRIATELY LOOK AT YOUR SEXUAL OR INTIMATE PARTS
* SHOW HIS OR HER SEXUAL OR INTIMATE PARTS TO YOU
* TAKE A SEXUAL OR INAPPROPRIATE PHOTOGRAPH OR VIDEO OF YOU
* INAPPROPRIATELY SHOW YOU ANYTHING SEXUAL, SUCH AS PHOTOGRAPHS, MAGAZINES OR BOOKS
* HAVE SEXUAL INTERCOURSE WITH YOU OR YOU WITH HIM OR HER, WHETHER ORAL, ANAL OR VAGINAL
* HAVE SEXUAL CONTACT WITH YOU OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER
* DO ANYTHING SEXUALLY TO HURT YOU OR CAUSE YOU PAIN AND SUFFERING

<b><a href="http://www.bmcgroup.com/dioceseofspokane">YOU MUST ACT NOW TO PRESERVE YOUR RIGHTS
THE LAST DAY TO FILE CLAIMS IS MARCH 10, 2006</a></b>
</div>

I did attend Catholic school in Spokane.  I'm impressed they tracked me down.  The Catholic Diocese of Spokane is using Bankruptcy protection (don't be fooled the Church is a corporation) to put a quick limit on the people who might come forward with sexual abuse charges, and conveniently, a corporation in bankruptcy protection does not have to suffer the embarrassment of damning testimony at trial.  <a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/html/localnews/2002811879_webspokanesettlement17.html?syndication=rss">However, the strategy is backfiring.  The bankruptcy court has determined that all of the parishes are considered property of the Diocese</a>, that means they can be forced to sell the churches and everything in them to pay off the claims.

Godspeed to the claimants.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3158</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2006-02-18 13:40:32</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2006-02-18 21:40:32</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-catholic-bishop-of-spokane-wrote-me-3</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>