<item>
		<title>Lawn Mower from Home Depot</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2011/09/10/lawn-mower-from-home-depot/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2011 00:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=5997</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The neighbor kid who was mowing our lawn hurt his foot while training for long-distance running, so had to stop mowing the lawn. I don't mind, I like mowing the lawn so it was an excuse for me to get a new lawn mower. I ordered one from homedepot.com because they had free shipping for it and said it'd be here in 3-5 days. It ended up taking 10 days to get here and when it did, it was broken. The bolt that holds the handle was bent, preventing it from being tightened.

<a href="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1259.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5998" title="IMG_1259" src="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1259.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="840" /></a>

<!--more-->I called Home Depot and they said I could just pick a new one up at a local store, which I should have done in the first place.

We took it to the Home Depot in West Seattle that had the same  model and exchanged it. When we got home and opened the box, we discovered mouse poop inside right away. The box was partially opened at the store, so a mouse must've gotten into it. But, of course, it couldn't get out, so it must still be inside. It turned out that there wasn't just one mouse, but 6 mice and 2 were still alive.

<a href="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1260.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5999" title="IMG_1260" src="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/img_1260.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="840" /></a>

How do we get rid of a box with two live mice in it? We can't just throw it away and introduce mice to the house.

Gay called Home Depot and, to their credit, offered to come pick up the box with the mice. We left it out while <a title="Laurelhurst Beach Club" href="http://troyandgay.com/2011/09/10/laurelhurst-beach-club/">we went to the Laurelhurst Beach Club</a> and by the time we got home, it was gone. Thanks Home Depot! (But you really should get rid of your mouse problem.)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>5997</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-10 16:12:11</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-11 00:12:11</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>lawn-mower-from-home-depot</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="our-life"><![CDATA[Our Life]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>email_notification</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315959852]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1315959851]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[47796]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>