<item>
		<title>Social Security for Illegal Immigrants</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2010/05/11/social-security-for-illegal-immigrants/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 15:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=4100</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I got an email this morning from a friend who is notorious for sending this stuff without checking <a href="http://www.snopes.com/politics/immigration/petition.asp">Snopes</a> first. But you don't even need Snopes for things like this, as I'm going to show...

<!--more-->
It begins like this...

<blockquote>SOCIAL SECURITY CHANGES
It does not matter if you personally like or dislike Obama.</blockquote>

Gee, I wonder this the rest of this is going to go. Just that tells you this is intended for people who dislike Obama. It's an out for the Obama-haters to say "Good, I do hate Obama but I won't look like I'm just another Obama-hater when I believe what I'm about to read, and I am going to believe it because Obama must be doing something I don't like". According to Snopes, it originated in 2006 with "Bush" substituted for "Obama", which was just as effective with a different group of imbeciles.

<blockquote>You need to sign this petition and flood his e-mail box with e-mails that tell him that, even if the House passes this bill, he needs to veto it.
</blockquote>

That's for the dummies who think that the President of the US 1) has "an e-mail box",  2) reads every message in it, 3) that he'd set Federal policy based on emails from a bunch of lunatic dimwits who refuse to participate in the democracy and can only muster the energy to forward an email around. But to be fair, I'd bet that 90% of the people who sign this petition make decisions in their lives based on very little or no information, so they assume the President does too.

<blockquote>It is already impossible to live on Social Security alone.  If the government gives benefits to 'illegal' aliens who have never contributed, where does that leave those of us who have paid into Social Security all our working lives?</blockquote>

Good point! This makes sense to people who don't even know that Social Security benefits are given to people with Social Security numbers, the very things that illegal immigrants lack. But that aside, this is the kind of argument  that nitwits take at face value. These are just statements, but dressed-up as facts. And by "dressed-up" I mean that they're written in simple words. You can argue anything this way: "The earth is flat, if it were round we'd all roll off of it", "It was really cold this winter where I live so global warming is a lie", "The oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico was perpetrated by environmentalists to make oil companies look bad".

<blockquote>As stated below, the Senate voted this week to allow 'illegal' aliens access to Social Security benefits.
</blockquote>

Where's the news article about this? Dummies don't need proof of things they want to believe, they just believe them because the very thought makes them angry. If it makes you angry, it must be true, right? And only the dumbest of the dumb don't read the remaining 4 sentences to realize it never is stated below. They've already been sold on the idea that it's true, their brain is mad now, let's keep going...

<blockquote>Attached is an opportunity to sign a petition that requires citizenship for eligibility to that social service.
Instructions are below.  If you don't forward the petition and just stop it, we will lose all these names.
</blockquote>

This is the call to arms. How the entire country has missed this huge news story must be explained as a liberal media trick. But Fox News hasn't even covered it? Come on, half their news isn't even true and they won't even touch this? It must be so obviously false they don't even try. Even they overestimate the intelligence of their audience.

<blockquote>
If you do not want to sign it, please just forward it to everyone you know.
Thank you!
To add your name, click on 'forward'.  Address it to all of your email correspondents, add your name to the list and send it on.
When the petition hits 1,000, send it to comment@whitehouse.gov &lt; http://us.mc1146.mail.yahoo.com/mc/compose?to=comment@whitehouse.gov &gt;;
</blockquote>

There's two clues here that should be obvious. The first is that it follows the old internet rule that any email is a lie that tells you to forward it to everyone you know. It's a joke people play to see how far they can get their email to circulate the globe. There never has been and never will be an email that asks you to do that that is true. Don't forget that.

The second clue is one internet newbies could be excused for missing, especially if their email client didn't expose the URL for the email address. "comment@whitehouse.gov" looks believable (gee, it has .gov rather than the usual .com, it must be legit), but the URL has a mail.yahoo.com address in it, which should tell you that it goes to Yahoo mail, not the President's "e-mail box".

The petition starts...

<blockquote>PETITION for President Obama:
Dear Mr. President:
We, the undersigned, protest the bill that the Senate voted on recently which would allow illegal aliens to access our Social Security.  We demand that you and all Congressional representatives require citizenship as a pre-requisite for social services in the United States .</blockquote>

And ends with a list of over 1000 gullible people.

It even got morphed from "Social Security benefits" to "social services". People who sign this petition are saying they want proof of citizenship before _any_ social service is provided. Imagine a child in an emergency room being asked for proof of citizenship before they save their life. Imagine a policeman asking a woman who was just beaten and raped for her ID card before he wastes precious tax dollars chasing the rapist. Imagine firemen watching your house burn while you run inside looking for  your passport.

The people who signed this petition aren't just stupid, they aren't just people who slept through civics classes in high school and have no understanding of how our government works -- they're assholes. Those are the people who are keeping America down, not immigrants. America was built by immigrants and immigrants, i.e., people who _want_ to come here for opportunity and to work hard, are what make America strong. This "I'm in, now close the door" attitude is un-American and for lazy people. I'd like to see a petition to revoke the US citizenship of everyone who signed this petition.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4100</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-05-11 08:53:20</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-05-11 15:53:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>social-security-for-illegal-immigrants</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1184</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Lee Curry]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>lee@treaclesponge.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>83.244.245.98</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-05-12 06:00:18</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-05-12 13:00:18</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey Troy, I look forward to postings like this from you. Makes great reading and I feel your passion. People who forward viral emails always baffle me. I liken it to marking a dollar bill (actually a £10 note) and seeing if you ever get it back. Even if you did - whoopee doo!

Your assessment of these people is spot on. But it is not just an American thing. There is narrow-mindedness and bigotry everywhere. And where there's bigotry there is viral emails..]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1185</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dottroy@mac.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-05-12 11:26:10</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-05-12 18:26:10</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I try to avoid politics in this era of Palin/Tea-Party hatred and ignorance, which is a few steps below even the era of Bush hatred and ignorance. But I admit I do have a passion for making fun of the stupid things people do.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1814</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Mac]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Domes@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://Xxxxxx@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>101.118.208.90</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-08-12 13:51:35</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-08-12 21:51:35</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[It happens in Australia too.  I think it makes dummies feel 'special']]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1344808295.9008209705352783203125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1344808295]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>