<item>
		<title>Steve Jobs @ Stanford</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/05/24/steve-jobs-stanford/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 17:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/05/24/steve-jobs-stanford/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[If you haven't seen Steve Jobs' commencement speech at Stanford in 2005, I highly recommend it:

[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UF8uR6Z6KLc&amp;rel=0]


<!--more-->

The most important points to me:

bq. You've got to find what you love. And that is as true for your work as it is for your lovers. Your work is going to fill a large part of your life, and the only way to be truly satisfied is to do what you believe is great work. And the only way to do great work is to love what you do. If you haven't found it yet, keep looking. Don't settle. As with all matters of the heart, you'll know when you find it. And, like any great relationship, it just gets better and better as the years roll on. So keep looking until you find it. Don't settle.

That works, my life is proof of it. :)

bq. No one wants to die. Even people who want to go to heaven don't want to die to get there. And yet death is the destination we all share. No one has ever escaped it. And that is as it should be, because Death is very likely the single best invention of Life. It is Life's change agent. It clears out the old to make way for the new. Right now the new is you, but someday not too long from now, you will gradually become the old and be cleared away. Sorry to be so dramatic, but it is quite true.

bq. Your time is limited, so don't waste it living someone else's life. Don't be trapped by dogma -- which is living with the results of other people's thinking. Don't let the noise of others' opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition. They somehow already know what you truly want to become. Everything else is secondary.

Transcript "here":http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2005/june15/jobs-061505.html.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3366</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-05-24 10:02:43</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-05-24 17:02:43</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>steve-jobs-stanford</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>