<item>
		<title>The power of the internet (and Yelp)</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2010/05/20/the-power-of-the-internet-and-yelp/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 22:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=4136</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[We planned to go to the <a href="http://www.alwaysfreshgoodness.com/">Volunteer Park Cafe</a> last night and made a reservation the day before. We ended up not being able to make it so I called to cancel my reservation. I always do this and even call when we're running late for a reservation because it's the right thing to do. I imagine most people don't call and just don't show up so the restaurant is left holding a table too long. I assume that's why I've _always_ been thanked for it. I was surprised, however, when the person I talked to wasn't appreciative and sarcastically said "Thanks for canceling at the super last-minute" ("super last-minute" being three hours before the 7pm reservation). I thought it was such bad form that I posted my <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/volunteer-park-cafe-and-marketplace-seattle#hrid:0xBAegCMomVD2h40esl2BA">first-ever review on Yelp</a> about it.

This afternoon, having seen the review, the manager called me to apologize and explain that it was him I talked to and that  he was having a stressful day. He was very contrite. Little things like that go a long way and I have a lot more respect for someone who can admit that they were wrong and apologize for it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4136</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-05-20 15:35:08</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-05-20 22:35:08</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-power-of-the-internet-and-yelp</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>