<item>
		<title>The War on Reality</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2004/10/22/the-war-on-reality/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2004 18:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2874</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The University of Maryland did a "study":http://www.pipa.org/OnlineReports/Pres_Election_04/Report10_21_04.pdf on the differing realities of Bush and Kerry supporters. Just look at the sheer lunacy of their beliefs:

* *Iraq, WMD &amp; Al Qaeda.* A large majority of Bush supporters believe that before the war Iraq had weapons of mass destruction or a  major program for building them.  A substantial majority of Bush supporters assume that most experts  believe Iraq had WMD and that this was the conclusion of the recently released report by Charles Duelfer.   A large majority of Bush supporters believes that Iraq was providing substantial support to al Qaeda and  that clear evidence of this support has been found.  A large majority believes that most experts also have  this view, and a substantial majority believe that this was the conclusion of the 9/11 Commission.

* *World opinion of the US, the war and Bush.* Only three in ten Bush supporters believe that the majority of people in the world oppose the US going to  war with Iraq, while an overwhelming majority of Kerry supporters have this view.  A majority of Bush  supporters assume that the majority of people in the world would like to see Bush reelected, while a large  majority of Kerry supporters believe the opposite.  Bush supporters also lean toward overestimating  support in Islamic countries for US-led efforts to fight terrorism, while Kerry supporters do not

* *Foreign Policy stances.* Majorities of Bush supporters misperceive his positions on a range of foreign policy issues.  In particular  they assume he supports multilateral approaches and addressing global warming when he has taken strong  contrary positions on issues such as the International Criminal court and the Kyoto Agreement.  A  majority of Kerry supporters have accurate perceptions of Kerry positions on the same issues.


On the bright side, Bush and Kerry supporters both agree on one point:

* Majorities of Bush supporters and Kerry supporters agree that if Iraq did not have WMD or was not  providing support to al Qaeda, the US should not have gone to war with Iraq.

If only Bush supporters had a clue what was going on in the world. As they say, in war, truth is the first casualty.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2874</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2004-10-22 11:01:50</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2004-10-22 18:01:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-war-on-reality</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>