<item>
		<title/>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2003/12/15/2519/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2003 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2519</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been out of the habit of updating this side of the this site. Just been too busy with the holidays, family and work. I work too much and would like to be able to relax and do other things, but I am a computer addict &#8212; there's always one more thing I can build/fix "really quick". It never ends. And I feel guilty when I stop and watch a movie, sit outside with the dogs, read, etc.

I am happy about the <a href="http://www.command-post.org/iraq_index.html">Saddam news</a>. Sunday morning at 4:30am my pager went off because a server was overloaded. So I went to the computer to deal with it and while I was waiting to verify everything was okay, I read <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/bb/viewtopic.zsp?t=55103">a post</a> with the news. I get my world news from a recipe site. ;-)  A few minutes later I went back to bed waking up Gay in the process and told her "they caught Saddam". "They did?! Wow!", she said and fell asleep.

I find lots of reasons to criticize Bush, but at times he impresses me. He impressed me with his handling of 9/11 by exercising restraint (something I couldn't have done at the time), saying all the right things and quickly removing the Taliban from power. And now he's handling Saddam correctly: we didn't kill him, we captured him and Iraq, not us, will be putting him on trial. A fair trial for one of history's "evil-dewars" is  something the world needs, I think. Killing him would have sent the wrong message and would've made him a martyr. Bush just might be able to salvage some respect for the US from the world (and I don't mean respect in the country music anthem "fear equals respect" way).]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2519</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2003-12-15 11:17:46</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2003-12-15 18:17:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>2519</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>