<item>
		<title>My birthday</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2005/11/02/my-birthday-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2005 20:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=3146</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Yesterday was my 36th birthday! Thanks to all the people who sent me birthday wishes. :)  Gay made me a wonderful dinner and my favorite cake (German Chocolate) that I've had every birthday since I can remember. I woke up to a traffic report on the radio on my birthday to hear about how bad the commute traffic was in Seattle -- something along the lines of "expect two to three times longer for your commute this morning" -- that really makes me appreciate something I have taken for granted the last few years: I have no commute!

Speaking of appreciating the little things in life, my recent birthdays remind me of how just 7 years ago I honestly didn't believe I would reach the age of 30. So I'm thankful that I'm getting older. :) It's been a very uncertain beginning to my 30s and I'm still wary of turning 40 in four years, but I am getting comfortable in my 30s and still feel like a kid (and usually act like it). I hope that I still have that feeling when I'm 80.

I've had a great year this year and I got some great presents (camping stuff) that I'm looking forward to using in the spring. But I got the best present a couple weeks early, more on that later. :)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3146</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2005-11-02 12:08:25</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2005-11-02 20:08:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>my-birthday-2</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>489</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Steve Mc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mcadoo_mcadoo@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>203.162.3.148</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-11-18 16:39:49</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-11-19 00:39:49</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Happy birthday, kid.  Forty's scary, but if it's any consolation, based on my experience, approaching 50 is a lot less so (perhaps because it seems to come only a few weeks after 40 does).]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>