<item>
		<title>High Violet</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2010/05/12/high-violet/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=4117</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The National's <em>High Violet</em> was finally released yesterday and I bought it immediately, even though I've been listening to it practically non-stop streaming from the New York Times and, when that ended, from NPR. I haven't listened to an album this repeatedly since Radiohead's 1997 <em>OK Computer</em>, <a href="http://www.time.com/time/2006/100albums/0,27693,OK_Computer,00.html">one of the greatest albums ever made</a> -- to this day, I still listen to a song or two from that album almost every day (they're surprisingly good songs to run to).
<!--more-->

The <a href="http://blog.washingtonpost.com/clicktrack/2010/05/album_review_the_national_high.html">Washington Post</a> has less love for it:
<blockquote>It's methodical and smart, filled with inscrutable but deep-sounding  ruminations on love and loss. Its twisty, intricate rhythms and lush  orchestral passages would take lesser bands years to figure out. It's  carefully made and entirely admirable -- and very, very dull, like an  Arcade Fire album where nothing happens.

Like most National discs, its charms gradually reveal themselves over  repeated listenings, although it might just be the Stockholm syndrome  kicking in. How much you like the National depends on how much you're  determined to like the National, a band that seems to delight in making  it difficult.</blockquote>
But everyone else seems to like music that can't be judged after one listen...

<a href="http://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/14203-high-violet/">Pitchfork</a>:
<blockquote>They could've holed up and recorded an idiosyncratic,  expectation-defying mess. Instead they produced an ornate, fussed-over  record that sounds like no one other than themselves.  Given the amount  of flack they take for being a no-frills bore, simply refining their  sound was arguably the braver option. They miss, occasionally-- the  string-drenched closer, "Vanderlyle Crybaby Geeks", is too decadent for  its own good-- but mostly, they construct gorgeous, structurally sound  vignettes. There are few bands that could craft a song like "Sorrow"--  in which emotion acts as a character and the band turns Berninger's  balladry into a well paced jog-- without stumbling over their own  ambitions.  The guitars on "Afraid of Everyone" actually sound nervous;  "England" speaks of cathedrals over properly magisterial drums. These  are triumphs of form.</blockquote>
<a href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/music_blog/2010/05/album-review-the-nationals-high-violet.html">LA Times</a>:
<blockquote>...The National is ruffled and tufted, sometimes embracing pomp and  circumstance, sometimes turning its back on it cold. ... One of the most stunning pieces on "High Violet" is "England," which opens with steadily mounting orchestration --  rippling piano chords, the low thunder of drums, some pining strings and  lofty horns. At its blustery peak, it threatens to topple from its own  melodrama. The pleasure is in listening to how often the National  scrapes up close to maudlin, only to retreat in the nick of time.</blockquote>
<a href="http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/music/cd_reviews/article7117334.ece">Times Online</a>:
<blockquote>High Violet takes the  journey to its next stage. You listen to tracks such as Sorrow,  Lemonworld,  Conversation 16, to the way Afraid of Everyone's ghostly backing vocals,  its  guitar squiggle -- which counterpoints Berninger's existential,  state-of-America cry of pain -- and Bryan Devendorf's urgent drumming  lift  the song into a different realm, and think: this is what music must do,  this  is what music means. Anything else is froth. A masterpiece.</blockquote>
<a href="http://www.nme.com/reviews/the-national--2/11286">NME</a>:
<blockquote>Goddamn it's taken a while, but with <strong>'High Violet'</strong> <strong>The  National</strong>'s slow and steady evolution can no longer be ignored.  This lot are fully grown-up, coloured in and going overground. And if  the masses aren't ready by now, they probably never will be.</blockquote>
<a href="http://www.sputnikmusic.com/review_36372">Sputnik Music</a>:
<blockquote>There  isn't a bad song on the album, and generally when people say things  like that they seem to imply that there are still a few duds here and  there.  But High Violet is literally free of weak moments... The National should give faith to anyone who has become disillusioned  with indie music, anyone who misses a time where it didn't seem like all  the musicians thought they were better than you and you could actually  relate to the damn words they were singing.  High Violet is another  batch of cement to further supplement The National's already unshakable  concrete career.</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4117</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-05-12 15:55:00</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-05-12 22:55:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>high-violet</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>