<item>
		<title>Worse than Vietnam</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2004/09/26/worse-than-vietnam/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 18:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2823</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/comment/story/0,,1305360,00.html">Sidney Blumenthal has a great piece in The Guardian</a> which includes many quotes from US military's leading strategists and prominent retired generals who all consider the Iraq war lost.
<i>"I see no exit," said Record (professor of strategy at the Air War College). "We've been down that road before. It's called Vietnamisation. The idea that we're going to have an Iraqi force trained to defeat an enemy we can't defeat stretches the imagination. They will be tainted by their very association with the foreign occupier. In fact, we had more time and money in state building in Vietnam than in Iraq."</i>
<i>Retired general William Odom, former head of the National Security Agency:  "I've never seen it so bad between the office of the secretary of defence and the military. There's a significant majority believing this is a disaster. The two parties whose interests have been advanced have been the Iranians and al-Qaida. Bin Laden could argue with some cogency that our going into Iraq was the equivalent of the Germans in Stalingrad. They defeated themselves by pouring more in there. Tragic."</i>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2823</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2004-09-26 11:45:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2004-09-26 18:45:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>worse-than-vietnam</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>