<item>
		<title>Washington Beer</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2006/02/20/3159/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 20:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=3159</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Washington State is trying to get organized about marketing its beers.

<blockquote><p>The crusade to establish Washington-made as a premium microbrew brand is in line for some help from the state Legislature, which appears willing to create a new industry promotional arm called the Washington Beer Commission.</p><p>If lawmakers give the OK, the commission will be officially empowered to levy a modest tax on its producers, put on fund-raising festivals and -- perhaps most important -- give away beer.</p></blockquote>
Washington does have great breweries, <a href="http://maritimebrewery.citysearch.com/">Maritime</a> and <a href="http://www.pikebrewing.com/">Pike Brewing Co</a> and even <a href="http://www.redhook.com/">Red Hook</a>, are great Seattle brewers and brewpubs like <a href="http://www.elysianbrewing.com/">Elysian</a> and <a href="http://www.bigtimebrewery.com/">Big Time</a> makes great beer too. But I have to admit, most of the beers I drink are from Oregon and California because they're better. It's heresy in Seattle to say this, but Seattle's biggies, <a href="http://www.pyramidbrew.com/">Pyramid</a> and <a href="http://www.halesales.com/">Hale's</a>, are not very good breweries, in my opinion -- if your top beer is a Hefeweizen, it's time to find a new brewmaster.

Maybe getting Washington beers noticed will help Washington State brewers to start making better beers when they realize they aren't as good as <a href="http://www.deschutesbrewery.com/splash/default.aspx">Deschutes</a>, <a href="http://www.northcoastbrewing.com/">North Coast</a>, <a href="http://www.sierranevada.com/">Sierra Nevada</a>, etc.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3159</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2006-02-20 12:11:46</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2006-02-20 20:11:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>3159</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>