<item>
		<title>TdF: Contador's 3rd win</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2010/07/25/tdf-contadors-3rd-win/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 18:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=4315</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="centered alignnone size-full wp-image-4316" title="Screen shot 2010-07-25 at 11.25.04 AM" src="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/screen-shot-2010-07-25-at-11-25-04-am1.png" alt="Screen shot 2010-07-25 at 11.25.04 AM" width="343" height="259" />

Another Tour de France is over. It's been a fun one to watch with excitement even on the usually boring flat stages. And I doubt I'll ever hear Phil and Paul argue again like they did over the Contador/Schleck chain controversy.

I've been watching the Tour for 15 or 16 years now and for the first time that I've seen, the winner of the Tour de France is not someone I can say was the strongest in the race. One of the two strongest, but not clearly the strongest.
<!--more-->

Contador won by 39 seconds over Andy Schleck, the exact amount of time he gained on him when <a href="http://troyandgay.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/screen-shot-2010-07-25-at-11-25-04-am1.png2010/07/19/tdf-contador-controversy/">Schleck had a mechanical problem</a> and Contador rode away from him (first claiming he didn't know then apologizing, saying he shouldn't have done it). But the sport is also about the bike, equipment teammates, the coach, the mechanics, etc., and Contador didn't have a mechanical problem at the wrong time, so he wins fair and square. Contador also won the Tour without winning a single stage, which is also a first for me to see. It's generally considered bad form to win without at least one stage win.

Next year should be Schleck's year.

Lance Armstrong's team, Radio Shack, won the team competition. Lance is retiring, but I've heard that before.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4315</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-07-25 11:26:16</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-07-25 18:26:16</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>tdf-contadors-3rd-win</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>