<item>
		<title>Birthday dinner</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2003/11/01/birthday-dinner/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2003 20:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2452</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Gay asked and we received <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/bb/viewtopic.zsp?t=50449&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=0">menu ideas</a> from Recipezaar people. It took a while to decide, so many things looked good. At first, a couple bread puddings were a definite, but as we worked out the other items on the menu, they had to go. Disappointing, but there's always other times for bread pudding. Many other dishes were in the plan, but some had to go due to time constraints (we really should have started the planning yesterday) and to get the right combination of things.

Here's the final plan...

We'll start with a <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/8877">Manhattans</a>, of course, and <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/41126">Chipotle-Barbecued Shrimp with Goat Cheese Cream</a> by <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/browse/getchef.zsp?id=32724">Mean Chef</a>.

Gay picked up some lamb and a rib roast and I chose the rib roast mainly because I wanted some fresh horseradish sauce tonight. So we'll have that with <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/44995">Sauteed Mushrooms with Red Wine</a> by <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/browse/getchef.zsp?id=55655">Just Call Me Martha</a>, <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/addrecipe/temp/index.zsp?bb=t50449p623992">Yorkshire Pudding</a> by <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/browse/getchef.zsp?id=32724">Mean Chef</a> and <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/29309">Warm Pumpkin Spinach and Feta Salad</a> by <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/browse/getchef.zsp?id=29196">Jan S</a> for the side.

And for wine, we have a choice of a 2000 <a href="http://www.quilcedacreek.com/VintageNotes.asp#Red">Quilceda Creek red table wine</a>, a <a href="http://www.stagsleapwinery.com/wines/00cab.html">2000 Stag's Leap Cabernet Sauvignon</a> or a <a href="http://woodwardcanyon.com/TechSheets/98wwcab.htm">1998 Woodward Canyon Cabernet Sauvignon</a>. Not sure how much my 34th birthday is worth.

I always have a German Chocolate Cake for my birthday cake and have ever since I can remember. Last year, I had an incredible one that will be hard to beat but <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/18575">German Chocolate Squares</a> by <a href="http://www.recipezaar.com/browse/getchef.zsp?id=8688">Bev</a> looks promising.

Thanks to everyone who suggested recipes! I wish we could have made more things, but I can't make Gay work that hard or she may ask me to cook for her on her birthday.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2452</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2003-11-01 13:44:36</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2003-11-01 20:44:36</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>birthday-dinner</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>