<item>
		<title>We're hiring!</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2006/01/13/were-hiring-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 18:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=3151</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://recipezaar.com">Recipezaar</a> is looking for a self-starting, well-organized software developer with 3+ years of experience in software development, specifically AJAX technologies (DHTML, XML, Javascript) in a LAMP environment.

If you:
<ul>

	<li>enjoying building and debugging software that millions of people use and love</li>

	<li>are willing to throw out code you wrote because you realized you did it wrong</li>

	<li>think Unix jokes are funny</li>

	<li>like working independently, from the comfort of your own home</li>

	<li>cringe at the thought of working at a large company that requires four meetings to decide anything</li>

	<li>believe cooking is both technology and art</li>

	<li>know the significance of the number 42</li>

	<li>enjoy eating...</li>
</ul>



...then this job might be for you.

<strong>The Details:</strong>

We'd like someone with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 2+ years experience with PHP and SQL (preferably MySQL), Ajax technologies (DHTML, XML/XSL, Javascript) and an interest in hardware and networking. You don't have to be an expert on Apache, but should be willing to become knowledgeable about it. If you don't know what Apache is, forget it. If you know C, you probably understand what happens behind the higher-level scripting languages of the web. That's important. If you know C++, you understand OO principles. If you love C++, you'll fit in.

Recipezaar is a small, dynamic company and requires people who can work independently and manage themselves and their workload efficiently. Small companies require you to wear many hats and be able to adapt quickly to changes and be able to solve problems quickly, and Recipezaar is no different. Being a great chef is not a requirement, but having an interest in helping others to be is. An interest in food and food preparation will make the job more fun.

We are a small distributed company (and we plan to stay that way) focused on building the most powerful web application for cooking and eating and sharing. Recipezaar is profitable and growing at a rapid rate. We're not yet #1 in our market, so if you're the type who likes to work hard to become #1, Recipezaar wants to talk to you.

To apply, send link to your online resume or text version in email (NO ATTACHMENTS, except PDF) to <a href="mailto:jobs@recipezaar.com">jobs@recipezaar.com</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3151</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2006-01-13 10:32:10</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2006-01-13 18:32:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>were-hiring-2</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>