<item>
		<title>Kindle</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/05/11/kindle/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2008 21:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/05/11/kindle/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="centered" src="http://g-ecx.images-amazon.com/images/G/01/digital/fiona/dp/v3-whispernet._V4948240_.jpg" />

I'm really tempted to get an "Amazon Kindle":http://amazon.com/kindle lately. When it first came out I thought it was expensive and pretty crappy and its "reviews":http://gadgets.boingboing.net/2007/11/19/amazon-kindle-ebook-1.html confirmed that. And there was very little content I wanted to read on it (not a big fan of best-seller fiction). And it's not color, all the web sites and magazines I read that I could get on it are in color, so black and white is a step backwards. E-Ink makes "a color version":http://www.eink.com/press/releases/pr86.html, why not give customers a color option? But more and more books that I've bought or are considering reading are available on Kindle now and, with all the traveling we've been doing, not having to pick just two books to take with me would be convenient enough for me to put up with all its flaws.

I've decided to wait for "version 2.0":http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/11/19/enough-about-kindle-10-what-about-kindle-20/ thinking it'll fix a lot of the problems that people have discovered in 1.0, such as "having to put a pad on the case":http://www.amazon.com/gp/customer-media/product-gallery/B000FI73MA/ref=cm_ciu_pdp_images_all to keep it from holding a button down, draining the battery. I'm also hoping that Apple comes out with an e-book reader -- they know how to make great hardware. All they have to do is give me a bigger iPhone and add books to the iTunes store. How hard can that be for them?]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3350</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-05-11 14:20:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-05-11 21:20:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>kindle</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>