<item>
		<title>Washington State Referendum 71</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2009/11/10/washington-state-referendum-71/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 23:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=3845</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Earlier this year, <a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/html/localnews/2009233610_webdomestic18.html">Washington State passed  legislation</a> to bestow equal rights on same-sex couples that married couples have. As it has been in 31 other states, a Christian group called "Protect Marriage" launched an attack on it in Washington by putting it to a popular vote under the guise of "democracy". Referendum 71 was born. A popular vote sounds like American democracy but anyone who went through high school understands (or should understand) that The Constitution of the US was written to, among other things, protect the minority from the tyranny of the majority.

<!--more-->

It's important to note that this law in Washington is not about marriage, it just grants the same legal rights to same-sex couples that married couples are given. So it really has nothing to do with the hot-button word "marriage" -- the Christians simply didn't want people to have equal rights like hospital visitation rights, have access to shared health insurance, rules of inheritance, etc. Besides,  <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/chr_dira.htm">the more religious a person is, the more likely they are to be divorced</a> so if the Christians want to protect marriage, they should stop throwing stones from inside their glass houses.

Washington State residents, however, defeated the bigots and approved Referendum 71, upholding the law. I'm proud to live in the state that is the first to uphold basic civil rights for same-sex couples!

Inter-racial marriage was legalized nationally in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loving_v._Virginia">a Supreme Court decision in 1967</a> but only <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/28417/most-americans-approve-interracial-marriages.aspx">accepted by the majority of the US population as late as 1983</a> and is still only at 77% today. <a href="http://contexts.org/socimages/2009/11/05/support-for-same-sex-marriage-by-age-and-state/">This graph</a> clearly shows that same-sex marriage opposition decreases as older generations die-off, so just as with the end to slavery, civil rights, women being allowed to vote, equal rights for same-sex couples will come to America. The only question is whether people born in the next few generations are embarrassed by their ancestors' bigotry or not.

<strong>Note to gay-bashers who happen upon this blog via Google:</strong> I am not gay. This site is called "TroyandGay" because it is the personal site for two people; one named "Troy" and the other named "Gay", both heterosexuals. We simply support equal rights because we are Americans, we believe in equality for everyone, even people who are not exactly like us and we believe the Constitution should be upheld. So please spout your anti-gay rhetoric to someone who doesn't yet know you're a moron.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3845</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-11-10 16:18:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-11-10 23:18:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>washington-state-referendum-71</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1143</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Beergy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>cronberg@sunwave.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>208.98.218.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-11-11 19:01:57</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-11-12 02:01:57</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Good for  Washinton but other parts of the world are not so understanding or liberal.  Uganda proposes anti-Gay laws.. Their Bill states that homosexuality is"preventable". They propose to punish offenders with 5 years in prison &amp; large fines.  Offenders would be anyone that  abets homosexuality and related practices. They claim that  same sex attraction is a "Mental disorder" and can be changed with treatment!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1144</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dottroy@mac.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-11-12 11:10:47</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-11-12 18:10:47</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[US Christian groups are behind that law too: http://www.splcenter.org/blog/2009/03/06/us-anti-gay-leaders-hold-seminar-in-uganda/

Some Christians oppose the law (but not the idea): http://www.christianpost.com/article/20091103/christians-urged-to-speak-out-against-uganda-s-anti-gay-bill/index.html

Fortunately, these people and their ignorance die off and their less ignorant offspring are more accepting of people who are different.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1145</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Lee Curry]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>lee.curry@storyworldwide.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www,treaclesponge.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>77.44.77.44</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-11-18 08:05:21</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-11-18 15:05:21</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey Troy,
Love your footnote about 'Gay Bashers'! I'm just curious to know what kinda responses you were getting to warrant it!

Lee]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1146</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-11-18 09:15:24</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-11-18 16:15:24</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Just the usual anti-gay rhetoric. People seem to arrive here by googling for "gay something or other" (usually political topics), obviously on the hunt for people supporting gay issues, and find some post here and say something stupid about how I'm pushing the gay agenda, that I'm a bad person, etc.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>