<item>
		<title>Obama-McCain debate Part 2</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/10/08/obama-mccain-debate-part-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/10/08/untitled/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[McCain nailed another debate with "brilliant answers":http://www.cnn.com/2008/POLITICS/10/07/presidential.debate.transcript/ to tough questions....

bq. Now, I have a plan to fix this problem and it has got to do with energy independence. We've got to stop sending $700 billion a year to countries that don't want us very -- like us very much. We have to keep Americans' taxes low. All Americans' taxes low. Let's not raise taxes on anybody today.

Fixing the economy by energy independence. Sounds like a great plan. Energy independence should take 10-20, maybe 40, years, so we'll just have to wait until then to fix today's economy. What's the rush? And throw in a little no tax raises and we'll be set.

bq. We obviously have to stop this spending spree that's going on in Washington. Do you know that we've laid a $10 trillion debt on these young Americans who are here with us tonight, $500 billion of it we owe to China?

Not that you had anything to do with that $10 trillion debt. No sirree, you only came to Washington 26 years ago.

bq. We've got to have a package of reforms and it has got to lead to reform prosperity and peace in the world. And I think that this problem has become so severe, as you know, that we're going to have to do something about home values. You know that home values of retirees continues to decline and people are no longer able to afford their mortgage payments. As president of the United States, Alan, I would order the secretary of the treasury to immediately buy up the bad home loan mortgages in America and renegotiate at the new value of those homes -- at the diminished value of those homes and let people be able to make those -- be able to make those payments and stay in their homes.

Good idea, John. You should do exactly what Henry Paulson and Congress recently agreed to do. But wait until January. And let's call it a bailout plan. Let's have tax-payers pay off people's mortgages for them. To those who call that socialism, just tell 'em you're a maverick! If people don't like the plan, tell them you didn't support it, you just voted for it.

<!--more-->

bq. Is it expensive? Yes. But we all know, my friends, until we stabilize home values in America, we're never going to start turning around and creating jobs and fixing our economy. And we've got to give some trust and confidence back to America. I know how the do that, my friends. And it's my proposal, it's not Sen. Obama's proposal, it's not President Bush's proposal. But I know how to get America working again, restore our economy and take care of working Americans. Thank you.

I'm sure you do know how to do that. Thank goodness you kept it a secret for 26 years and will unleash it on us starting in January. Assuming you get elected, of course. If you don't get elected, well, just keep it a secret for another 4 years.

bq. I like Meg Whitman [former CEO of eBay and current McCain campaign adviser], she knows what it's like to be out there in the marketplace. She knows how to create jobs. Meg Whitman was CEO of a company that started with 12 people and is now 1.3 million people in America make their living off eBay. Maybe somebody here has done a little business with them.

Good choice! eBay just "laid-off 10% of their employees yesterday":http://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/07/technology/07ebay.html?ref=technology, she's great at creating jobs (and "giving leaving executives golden parachutes":http://www.webguild.org/2008/09/ebay-layoffs-executives-to-get-4-years-pay.php)! eBay sure did start with 12 people, 12 people named Pierre Omidyar and, uh, 11 other people no one's ever heard of. Meg came in many years later after eBay was successful and somehow has turned what should be a thriving business in a bad economy into a declining business. That's the kind of leadership we need in the McCain administration. Imagine if she could do for our economy what she did for eBay?!?

bq. I left my campaign and suspended it to go back to Washington to make sure that there were additional protections for the taxpayer in the form of good oversight, in the form of taxpayers being the first to be paid back when our economy recovers -- and it will recover -- and a number of other measures.

When you went to the White House and said nothing and then took the weekend off at your home in Virginia, that's how you made sure there were good forms of oversight in the bailout plan. The Democrats who were working on it all week and through the weekend had nothing to do with getting the plan changed and getting that oversight that Paulson agreed to days before you suspended your campaign. You did a great job on that, John!

bq. The point is -- the point is that we can fix our economy. Americans' workers are the best in the world. They're the fundamental aspect of America's economy. They're the most innovative. They're the best -- they're most -- have best -- we're the best exporters. We're the best importers. They're most effective. They are the best workers in the world.

Exactly. American workers are the best in the world, especially at importing things that are made elsewhere.

bq. And we've got to give them a chance. They've got -- we've got to give them a chance to do their best again. And they are the innocent bystanders here in what is the biggest financial crisis and challenge of our time. We can do it.

You're right, John, it's time for American workers to get off their asses and start working!

bq. Teresa Finch: How can we trust either of you with our money when both parties got -- got us into this global economic crisis?

bq. McCain: Well, Theresa (ph), thank you. And I can see why you feel that cynicism and mistrust, because the system in Washington is broken. And I have been a consistent reformer.

You consistently reformed Washington into the broken system we have today. Nice job.

bq. I know a lot of them that aren't working. One of them is in defense spending, because I've taken on some of the defense contractors. I saved the taxpayers $6.8 billion in a deal for an Air Force tanker that was done in a corrupt fashion.

Totally corrupt. Boeing and Airbus both bid, Airbus won, the Navy was happy with a less-expensive solution that was technically superior, Boeing complained that they didn't win, had their lobbyists stop the deal and then they backed out of the opportunity to re-bid for it. You don't get more corrupt than that, if by "corrupt" you mean "perfectly fair". Now the Navy has no tanker that they needed but you saved money, John.

bq.  So we're going to have to tell the American people that spending is going to have to be cut in America. And I recommend a spending freeze that -- except for defense, Veterans Affairs, and some other vital programs, we'll just have to have across-the-board freeze.

Yes, let's have a spending freeze across the entire federal government. That's a totally rational thing to do. If I'm over budget, I don't bother figuring out where I over-spent, I just stop spending altogether. No food, no utilities, nothing until I get around to figuring out where I over-spent.

bq. And some of those programs may not grow as much as we would like for them to, but we can establish priorities with full transparency, with full knowledge of the American people, and full consultation, not done behind closed doors and shoving earmarks in the middle of the night into programs that we don't even -- sometimes we don't even know about until months later.

Who has time to read all those bills before you vote on them? Certainly not John McCain!

bq. Frankly, I'm not going to tell that person without health insurance that, "I'm sorry, you'll have to wait." I'm going to tell you Americans we'll get to work right away and we'll get to work together, and we can get them all done, because that's what America has been doing.

Right after the spending-freeze is over, of course.

bq. Well, you know, nailing down Sen. Obama's various tax proposals is like nailing Jell-O to the wall.

It's even harder than that, you have to turn on a computer and read his web site.

bq. But he wants to raise taxes.

He wants to raise taxes on the poor souls making $250,000/year and give tax cuts to greedy bastards who make less. John's plan makes so much more sense, don't worry about taxes on the thriving middle-class but cut taxes significantly on those suffering wealthy people. We have to give the wealthy a break for once. If we don't give wealthy people even more tax breaks they're going to give up being wealthy and join the opulent lives of the middle-class.

bq.  Social Security is not that tough. We know what the problems are, my friends, and we know what the fixes are. We've got to sit down together across the table. It's been done before.

Social security is easy-peazy. We fixed it before, we just need to keep fixing it. Over and over again. That's how you know something is fixed right, when it regularly needs fixing.

bq.  So Medicare, it's going to be a little tougher. It's going to be a little tougher because we're talking about very complex and difficult issues.

Medicare,  now that's a doozy. Not at all simple like Social Security that keeps getting broken after John McCain fixes it.

bq. My friends, what we have to do with Medicare is have a commission, have the smartest people in America come together, come up with recommendations, and then, like the base-closing commission idea we had, then we should have Congress vote up or down.

Medicare is tough, but nothing a bureaucratic commission spending several years coming up with recommendations can't fix. We'll just have them decide what to do and leave it to Congress to vote up or down. We need to get John McCain out of Congress and into the White House where he won't have to deal with voting up or down on the recommendations.

bq. Now, how -- what's -- what's the best way of fixing it? Nuclear power. Sen. Obama says that it has to be safe or disposable or something like that.

Safe? Disposable? Obama's crazy! The last thing we should care about with radioactive material is being safe or disposing of it! Stupid liberals always want to avoid collosal disasters. Mavericks don't have time for that wussy pinko stuff.

bq. You know who voted for it? You might never know. That one.

That negro over there who I refuse to even look at. That's who!

bq. But the point is, also, on oil drilling, oil drilling offshore now is vital so that we can bridge the gap. We can bridge the gap between imported oil, which is a national security issue, as well as any other, and it will reduce the price of a barrel of oil, because when people know there's a greater supply, then the cost of that will go down. That's fundamental economics.

Yes, that's fundamental economics. Every economist knows that when supply goes up, prices go down. And when prices go down, demand goes up. And when demand goes up, prices go up. Wait, that'll get us back to where we are today because, as all economists know, prices always reflect equilibrium between supply and demand. That's not going to work, so we'll just have McCain alter the laws of economics: increase supply, lower prices and keep demand constant. Should work out just fine. Just remember you gas-buying consumers: when prices go down, DO NOT buy more of it. When prices go down, it's smart to buy more. When food prices go down, stock up! When TVs go on sale, buy! But gas is different. John McCain will explain how.

bq. And as far as nuclear power is concerned, again, look at the record. Sen. Obama has approved storage and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel.

He approved storage and reprocessing of spend nuclear fuel?! I thought he was against nuclear energy. Oh, I get it, John. Obama is only for storing and disposing of nuclear waste, he's not for creating nuclear energy that causes the waste in the first place. McCain is a wise wise man.

bq. And we need to do all of the things that are necessary to make it more efficient. Let's put health records online, that will reduce medical errors, as they call them.

Some people call them "deaths" and "sicknesses", I'm with you, John -- I prefer to call them "errors".

bq.  If you're a small business person and you don't insure your employees, Sen. Obama will fine you. Will fine you. ... Obviously small business people want to give their employees health insurance. Of course they all want to do that.

Of course they do, that's why they won't do it and get fined by Obama.

bq. Brokaw: Quick discussion. Is health care in America a privilege, a right, or a responsibility?

bq. McCain: I think it's a responsibility, in this respect, in that we should have available and affordable health care to every American citizen, to every family member. And with the plan that -- that I have, that will do that. But government mandates I -- I'm always a little nervous about.

Healthcare isn't a right. American people don't have the right to have good healthcare. They have the right to a good police force, a good fire department, a good education system and a good justice system. But good health? No way. Let the free market decide who lives and dies.

bq.  We went in to Somalia as a peacemaking organization, we ended up trying to be -- excuse me, as a peacekeeping organization, we ended up trying to be peacemakers and we ended up having to withdraw in humiliation.

We should never try to keep the peace if there's a risk we will have to withdraw in humiliation. It's better to let others die than it is to be embarrassed trying to save them. The first rule of CPR lessons: only attempt CPR if you can look good doing it.

bq. So you have to temper your decisions with the ability to beneficially affect the situation and realize you're sending America's most precious asset, American blood, into harm's way.

Just like how we did it in Iraq. We clearly understood our ability to beneficially affect the situation in Iraq. We knew full well that 5,000 Americans would die, that's why we did it. And our plan has worked out just as McCain said it would in 2003: no humiliation whatsoever. If we leave Iraq now, those veterans who don't die will have to live with the humiliation of telling their children that they should have died.

bq. And, again, I know those situations. I've been in them all my life. And I can tell you right now the security of your young men and women who are serving in the military are my first priority right after our nation's security.

That's why McCain consistently votes against Veterans. You can't vote for Veterans benefits and turn around and say veterans are your top priority. You have to make it your top priority to vote against them.

bq.  When you announce that you're going to launch an attack into another country, it's pretty obvious that you have the effect that it had in Pakistan: It turns public opinion against us.

Not at all like when we invaded Iraq without popular public support.

bq. Now, let me just go back with you very briefly. We drove the Russians out with -- the Afghan freedom fighters drove the Russians out of Afghanistan,

Yes, we and good 'ol Osama bin Laden and his Afghan freedom-fighters drove the Russians out. Bin Laden is a great ally.

bq. I'll get Osama bin Laden, my friends. I'll get him. I know how to get him. I'll get him no matter what and I know how to do it.

Yes, you know how to get bin Laden just like you know how to fix the economy. If only we would vote you into the White House so you could finally be free to tell us how to do these things! If we don't elect you President then you should not try to help the country by letting us in on your secrets. Country First!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3496</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-10-08 12:06:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-10-08 19:06:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>obama-mccain-debate-part-2</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>760</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Todd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.191.197.56</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-10-08 22:24:15</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-10-09 05:24:15</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[By reading you blog, I'm having a hard time figuring out your political views this time around. You're voting Republican this year, right?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>761</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Jim]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>james@infinitesynergy.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>97.94.115.129</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-10-08 22:34:25</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-10-09 05:34:25</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Brilliant!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>762</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-10-08 22:38:38</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-10-09 05:38:38</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Absolutely! I think McCain's got some great new ideas and he really knows how to make things happen. And Sarah Palin is on top of every issue.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>