<item>
		<title>Next Time Don't Leave a Note...</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2004/02/26/next-time-dont-leave-a-note/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 23:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2580</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I did a poor job of parallel parking recently, and due to the height of my SUV, I ended up putting a two-inch scratch in the *plastic* strip of someone's 1990 Acura Integra GS Hatchback front bumper, which had many other previous bumper scratches and over 200,000 miles, as well as 6 accidents already registered on the VIN number.  Why do I know so much about the car?  I politely left a note -- mostly out of guilt because there is just no way this person would have even noticed the scratches, not even next summer when they next washed it -- and this person decided this would be a wonderful way to get their next vacation paid for.  They took the car to two body shops who both provided an estimate of more than the trade-in value of the car ($600)!  Naturally, when I offered to make the check out to the repair shop, this person was naturally confused.  We decided on a much smaller check made out directly to them.
If this had happened to me, I would have rejoiced at the fact that there was still good will in the world (and my car is actually still worth a couple of grand), called them and thanked them for their sincerity, told them to forget about it.  Had I been treated *that way*, I probably would have insisted on sending them $50 or something for a dinner out, instead of having to go through this haggling which ultimately teaches you not to be a nice guy.
I would have expected a lot more from a Seattle acupuncturist, but the new age-y ones seem to always be the least giving or understanding.  Thanks for the new impression of humanity...]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2580</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2004-02-26 16:29:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2004-02-26 23:29:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>next-time-dont-leave-a-note</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>