<item>
		<title>Biden-Palin debate</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/10/03/biden-palin-debate/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 20:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/10/03/biden-palin-debate/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Sarah Palin made some great points in the debate:

bq. Fear about, how are we going to afford to send our kids to college? A fear, as small-business owners, perhaps, how we're going to borrow any money to increase inventory or hire more people.

Yeah, when the economy sucks and small-business owners have fewer customers, the biggest worry that they have is how they're going to get more inventory or hire more people. It's an embarrassment of riches for small-business owners all across this great country, also.

bq. John McCain, in referring to the fundamental of our economy being strong, he was talking to and he was talking about the American workforce. And the American workforce is the greatest in this world, with the ingenuity and the work ethic that is just entrenched in our workforce.

bq. That's a positive. That's encouragement. And that's what John McCain meant.

Sure he did. That's why he didn't say that.

bq. Darn right it was the predator lenders, who tried to talk Americans into thinking that it was smart to buy a $300,000 house if we could only afford a $100,000 house. There was deception there, and there was greed and there is corruption on Wall Street. And we need to stop that.

Those darn predatory lenders lending out money to unsuspecting people who they knew could not pay the loan back. While we're at it, what about those predatory tax-payers who give their money to the government? The problem in America is clearly the tax-payers.

<!--more-->

bq. One thing that Americans do at this time, also, though, is let's commit ourselves just every day American people, Joe Six Pack, hockey moms across the nation, I think we need to band together and say never again. Never will we be exploited and taken advantage of again by those who are managing our money and loaning us these dollars. We need to make sure that we demand from the federal government strict oversight of those entities in charge of our investments and our savings and we need also to not get ourselves in debt.

Strict federal government oversight like the oversight that John McCain voted to remove from the banking industry in 1999.

bq. Let's do what our parents told us before we probably even got that first credit card. Don't live outside of our means.

Also let's do what our parents told us. Don't get pregnant at 17.

bq. I do take issue with some of the principle there with that redistribution of wealth principle that seems to be espoused by you. But when you talk about Barack's plan to tax increase affecting only those making $250,000 a year or more, you're forgetting millions of small businesses that are going to fit into that category. So they're going to be the ones paying higher taxes thus resulting in fewer jobs being created and less productivity.

Yeah, every small business owner makes $250,000 a year. Your brother and his wife easily earn $250K/year each at their little gas station in Alaska. Taxing people who make $250K/year is hitting hockey moms all across the nation.

bq. I am because he's got a good health care plan that is detailed. And I want to give you a couple details on that. He's proposing a $5,000 tax credit for families so that they can get out there and they can purchase their own health care coverage.

A $5,000 tax credit for healthcare! Woo hoo! The average family of four costs over $12,000/year in healthcare, most of which is paid for by their employer. Good thing McCain wants to get rid of employer-paid healthcare so people can pay the $12,000 themselves with their $5,000 tax credit. If my math is correct, $12,000 minus $5,000 equals $0. That's what we Republicans call "free". McCain and I are good at the maths.

Besides, what family can't have all their healthcare needs met for $5,000/year? Just the sick ones. Screw 'em, they shouldn't have contracted cancer or diabetes from their parents. Duh! It's genetic, it's not rocket surgery. Healthcare is for healthy people, not sick people.

bq. And that's why Tillerson at Exxon and Mulva at ConocoPhillips, bless their hearts, they're doing what they need to do, as corporate CEOs, but they're not my biggest fans, because what I had to do up there in Alaska was to break up a monopoly up there and say, you know, the people are going to come first and we're going to make sure that we have value given to the people of Alaska with those resources.

Way to go Sarah! Those big oil companies can pay the 270,000 Alaskan households $100/each, or $27 million, if they want to earn billions in profits. They aren't going to be messing with you! Taxing oil companies in Alaska is great. Taxing them in other states, now that's just crazy talk.

bq. It is a crisis. It's a toxic mess, really, on Main Street that's affecting Wall Street.

I know. Poor Wall Street being affected by the toxic mess on Main Street. Wall Street will need less regulation from now on to protect itself from the predatory lenders on Main Street.

bq. It's a nonsensical position that we are in when we have domestic supplies of energy all over this great land. And East Coast politicians who don't allow energy-producing states like Alaska to produce these, to tap into them, and instead we're relying on foreign countries to produce for us.

We need to conserve the oil in foreign countries so that once we run out of our own oil, they have some to give us.

bq. I'm not one to attribute every man -- activity of man to the changes in the climate. There is something to be said also for man's activities, but also for the cyclical temperature changes on our planet.

You betcha! The temperature changes that happen across this great planet every 100 million years or so. We're just in one of those regular climate changes, even though the planet has only been here 4,000 years according to the Bible. Scientists with their "evidence" are Obama supporters.

bq. As governor, I was the first governor to form a climate change sub-cabinet to start dealing with the impacts. We've got to reduce emissions. John McCain is right there with an "all of the above" approach to deal with climate change impacts.

And by producing more oil for gas in our cars and engines, we can reduce emissions. Everyone knows that the more oil we burn, the fewer emissions we will have.

bq. Yes, Sen. McCain does support this. The chant is "drill, baby, drill." And that's what we hear all across this country in our rallies because people are so hungry for those domestic sources of energy to be tapped into.

Americans all across this country want to drill for oil here so we can be more dependent on other nations for oil later. That's how you know Americans are thinkin' like Sarah Palin!

bq. But I also want to clarify, if there's any kind of suggestion at all from my answer that I would be anything but tolerant of adults in America choosing their partners, choosing relationships that they deem best for themselves, you know, I am tolerant and I have a very diverse family and group of friends and even within that group you would see some who may not agree with me on this issue, some very dear friends who don't agree with me on this issue.

Adults in America should be able to choose their partners. I can be _tolerant_ of that. But kids in America should have their parents force them into marriage, and hopefully before the parents are involved in a big election.

bq. We'll know when we're finished in Iraq when the Iraqi government can govern its people and when the Iraqi security forces can secure its people. And our commanders on the ground will tell us when those conditions have been met.

We just sit and wait for the Iraqi government to tell us when we're done. Meanwhile, lets keep paying $10 billion a month and adding to the 5,000 Americans that have died in Iraq. How can anyone argue with that?

bq. And as for who coined that central war on terror being in Iraq, it was the Gen. Petraeus and al Qaeda, both leaders there and it's probably the only thing that they're ever going to agree on, but that it was a central war on terror is in Iraq. You don't have to believe me or John McCain on that. I would believe Petraeus and the leader of al Qaeda.

Why wouldn't you believe what al-Qaeda says? Who are we to distrust those hard-workin' God-fearin' folks? If they say Iraq is where we should be, darn right, we'll stay there! If al-Qaeda was really somewhere else, somewhere weird like in Pakistan or Afghanistan, don't you think they'd let us know?!

bq. Israel is our strongest and best ally in the Middle East. We have got to assure them that we will never allow a second Holocaust.

Hear that all you people who want to allow a second Holocaust?

bq. There have been huge blunders in the war. There have been huge blunders throughout this administration, as there are with every administration.

Except for a McCain administration. McCain has proven throughout this campaign that he never makes big blunders. Also, he won't make blunders when he's President. Also, neither will Sarah Palin.

bq. Our nuclear weaponry here in the U.S. is used as a deterrent. And that's a safe, stable way to use nuclear weaponry.

Yep. Nuclear weapons are safe if you don't shoot them. Also why wouldn't other countries just trust on that? It's not like we ever used atomic bombs in the past. What are they scared of? Why would they worry about defending themselves from us? We would never just go, like, you know, invade another country.

bq. Well, first, McClellan did not say definitively the surge principles would not work in Afghanistan. Certainly, accounting for different conditions in that different country and conditions are certainly different. We have NATO allies helping us for one and even the geographic differences are huge but the counterinsurgency principles could work in Afghanistan. McClellan didn't say anything opposite of that.

Right. Scott McClellan, the former White House press secretary, didn't say anything like that. General McKiernan, the General in Afghanistan, "did though":http://www.signonsandiego.com/uniontrib/20081002/news_1n2afghan.html. But that's a totally different guy, so let's not talk about that.

bq. In my comment there, it was a lame attempt at a joke and yours was a lame attempt at a joke, too, I guess, because nobody got it. Of course we know what a vice president does.

That's why you said several weeks ago that you didn't. It was just a joke. Just like you joked that you didn't know what the Bush Doctrine was or the names of any newspaper or magazine you read regularly. Those are the funniest types of jokes, jokes where you say you don't know something. It's hilarious. I don't know what an astrophysicist does. See? Funny!

bq. But it wasn't just that experience tapped into, it was my connection to the heartland of America. Being a mom, one very concerned about a son in the war, about a special needs child, about kids heading off to college, how are we going to pay those tuition bills? About times and Todd and our marriage in our past where we didn't have health insurance and we know what other Americans are going through as they sit around the kitchen table and try to figure out how are they going to pay out-of-pocket for health care? We've been there also so that connection was important.

Just tell those people to run for Governor of their state and earn a $250,000/year salary. And force the oil companies in your state to hire your husband as a "consultant" so he can really go fishing, his passion, all day and collect a big salary. Not being able to afford healthcare is a problem that is easily-solved, that's why a McCain/Palin wouldn't try to help people to pay for it.

bq. People aren't looking for more of the same. They are looking for change. And John McCain has been the consummate maverick in the Senate over all these years.

Darn right. McCain votes against the Republicans and makes great efforts to agree with Democrats. His greatest accomplishments are those where he sided with Democrats to get things done. That's why you should vote Republican!

bq. We have got to win the wars. We have got to get our economy back on track. We have got to not allow the greed and corruption on Wall Street anymore.

And don't forget those predatory lenders! And have we all forgotten about the prize money from winning the wars?]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3490</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-10-03 13:17:51</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-10-03 20:17:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>biden-palin-debate</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>757</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[faith58]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.162.106.6</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-10-04 19:59:40</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-10-05 02:59:40</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi Troy and Gay
Love your posts about the election and I think if mccain/palin are elected we are in deep trouble. Check this link out You will love it. The kids are adorable.

http://www.bskedsmo.com/misc/palin-governor-02.htm]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>