<item>
		<title>The Fourth Of July</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2003/07/05/the-fourth-of-july/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2003 08:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2212</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I'm not a very patriotic person. I tend to think it's random that I happen to be born within the borders of a specific country. I like to think I'm a citizen of Earth, the Milky Way, whatever, than a citizen of the United States. But I was born here and I've lived here all my life. So I am a citizen. I'm a typical American, be that good or bad. I've spent some time outside the US and I was <i>extremely</i> anti-US policies in my youth and I still have some huge disagreements with our government (and probably always will). But seeing the fireworks and general happiness in people in the US on July 4th makes me feel good and I'm not sure why.

After 9/11, the patriotic-ness in the US surprised me (and probably surprised those siding with the terrorists as well). July 4th of any year will never live up to that feeling, I suppose, but both July 4ths since I've felt like they were little versions of the post-9/11 patriotic-ness. Granted, the meaning of July 4th is probably lost on most Americans and it's more of a chance to drink beer (yay!) and eat hamburgers and hotdogs and enjoy pyrotechnics, but there's something fascinating to me that everybody does it in unison. And they want to do it.

We went to a party at a friend's house tonight for the holiday. We stopped on the way at a couple stores and everyone (strangers) were abnormally friendly. It's surprising that in a country as big as the US, there's still a feeling of togetherness and nationality.

I've probably had two too many beers. <img src="/img/smile.gif">]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2212</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2003-07-05 01:21:29</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2003-07-05 08:21:29</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-fourth-of-july</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>