<item>
		<title>Dumbass and Dumbasser</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2003/06/26/dumbass-and-dumbasser/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2003 21:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2184</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.troyandgay.com/archives/2003/06/001508.php#001508">The gentleman that requested I "fuck off and die" for not publishing his recipe</a> has responded to my response.  (You can read the full argument and further debates on his blog at the link above of click continued here to see the complete email thread.)  Someone has a LOT of misplaced anger and time on their hands.
<!--more-->
Gay,

I understand that there were other mechanisms that
you've put in place to handle corrections.  I'm sorry
that I missed it.

But your form letter is extremely nasty.  It's
accusing me of stealing something.  Most thieves don't
post lines like this, "Stolen from recipe #45911 but
with proper amounts added into the the recipe so the
nutritional qualities come out correctly." in their
description.  I certainly understand why it is better
to fix one record rather than have two records, both
tainted...because record a has bad nutrtional analysis
and record b has the incorrect owner.  But it's not
like you have an improved page from the Correction
link that you're asking me to use.  It's still just a
form that's sending you an email.  Why would you give
a crap which form sends you the email?  It's all
having to be worked on the backend by a real person.

My only guess is that you might have a script that
checks for commonalities between preexisting records
and the requested addition.  It that's the case then I
slightly understand...but your form email still sucks.
 I mean it really sucks.  Let me break down my reasons
why I think it's not nice, since you seem to think
it's appropriate.

a)  You opened the letter with yelling and accusing me
of theft:  "We really do NOT appreciate it when anyone
"steals" recipes."

b)  You again call me a crook and tell me I'm not
nice(ironic point 1 of the discussion):  "It is
copyright infringement and just, well, not nice."

c)  You ignored the details of my post while somehow
remaining really arrogant about the fact you think I'm
a fucking idiot.  I gave you the correct quantities
and the bad recipe number:  "Look if you want the
nutritional analysis, just submit the correct
quantities and we can update the recipe."

d)  You explain to me the reasons why it's a good idea
that I do what I attempted to do, inform you about an
error.  I know that everyone benefits when you have
data that's better in quality.  If I didn't know that
then why in the hell would I ever try and send you
this correction?  "When you update a recipe that is
already here everyone benefits."

3)  You again accuse me of fucking theft.  I'm
beginning to remember why I got so pissed off the
first time I read this.  By the way, what fucking gain
do you seem to think that I was working for here.
Suddenly I'm going to become the fucking chef of the
wild wild midwest by stealing a god-damned tuna
fucking sandwich recipe?  And as for causing more work
for you?  If you cared about that you'd put together a
page with pull-downs for the ingredients corrections
instead of having people fill out a form and then mail
it to you.  Then you wouldn't be stuck sitting around
hand-jamming corrections into your database.  Instead
you could be munching chips and watching TV or working
on your backup schema:  "When you plagiarize other
recipes for you own gain, it hurts everyone and causes
more work for us."

4)  No fucking logic in the next two sentences.
Obviously I've already fucking done it, or else I
wouldn't have been sent this stupid email.  Also very
annoying as I did post with the god-damned recipe ID:
"Please do not do this sort of thing again.  If
you have done it already, please reply with the recipe
ID #s so that I can fix them."

And as I noted in my blog, you're a user-supported
site.  I continue to be amazed that you would send
such an insulting letter.  You're going to get a
better click-through rate for your DietDivas and
Amazon ads when people link to your site or spread the
word about your site.  Being nasty to people isn't
conducive to increasing site traffic.

You should be happy that anyone is trying to help you
update errors on your site, regardless of the manner
in which you're contacted.

I was pretty sure that it was a few people that were
running the site.  And you've produced what is in my
opinion the best recipe site on the web.  You can
create a menu plan from excellent recipes that have
been reviewed and rated by other users.  Then you can
create a shopping list.  And you can make your own
"cookbook" so you don't have to search for your
favorite recipes again.  But what does it matter if
the site is good if you're impolite to anyone who zips
you a correction, albeit in the manner that you don't
prefer?

I'm not getting paid anything to try and get you to
correct a recipe.  I'm just trying to be a member of
the community you've created.  But I feel like I'm in
a strange town in Indiana and I've been pulled over
and bitched at by the local sheriff for telling him
about someone being broken down on the highway who
might need help.

Again, this will be crossposted in my journal.

Sincerely,
Dan

--- Recipezaar Support  wrote:
&gt; Daniel Doughty, thanks for writing.
&gt;
&gt; I replied in your blog too.
&gt;
&gt; I really think you misunderstood me.  There is a way
&gt; to submit a correction to a recipe, but submitting a
&gt; new recipe is not that way...and I felt I needed to
&gt; explain why.
&gt;
&gt; I wouldn't copy text from your blog and put it in
&gt; mine passing it off as my own, as a good net person
&gt; I would post a comment or link to your blog from
&gt; mine.  this is all we are asking you to do on our
&gt; site.  It is the nice thing to do.
&gt;
&gt; Thanks for helping make Recipezaar a better place,
&gt;
&gt; Gay Gilmore
&gt; Recipezaar: Where the Recipes Are
&gt; http://www.Recipezaar.com
&gt;
&gt;
&gt; Daniel Doughty  wrote:
&gt;
&gt; &gt; Uhm, fuck you.
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; I am a unix sys admin and into the web and
&gt; understand
&gt; &gt; how annoying stupid requests can be.  But your
&gt; letter
&gt; &gt; is demeaning and nasty.
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; Fuck off and die.  I kind of like your site since
&gt; it
&gt; &gt; allows for users to rate submissions and submit
&gt; their
&gt; &gt; own recipes.
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; But whoever the dumbass is that you hired and
&gt; allowed
&gt; &gt; "bread" to be entered without the amount on a few
&gt; &gt; sandwiches is a fucking dumbass.
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; And most important of all, your email response to
&gt; my
&gt; &gt; entry is one of the most fucking insulting emails
&gt; I've
&gt; &gt; ever been sent.  I'm serious.  I've been on since
&gt; '92
&gt; &gt; and this is practically the god-damned definition
&gt; of
&gt; &gt; arrogance.  Perhaps since you're not charging for
&gt; you
&gt; &gt; site you may feel empowered.  All I have to say is
&gt; the
&gt; &gt; same thing.  Fuck you.
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; BTW, I'm posting this response in my lj at
&gt; &gt; www.livejournal.com/users/russkiypenguin
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; --- Recipezaar Editor
&gt; wrote:
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; The recipe below could not be published because
&gt; this
&gt; &gt; &gt; recipe already
&gt; &gt; &gt; appears on our site.  We really do NOT
&gt; appreciate it
&gt; &gt; &gt; when anyone
&gt; &gt; &gt; "steals" recipes. It is copyright infringement
&gt; and
&gt; &gt; &gt; just, well, not
&gt; &gt; &gt; nice.  Look if you want the nutritional
&gt; analysis,
&gt; &gt; &gt; just submit the
&gt; &gt; &gt; correct quantities and we can update the recipe.
&gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; Click the link to
&gt; &gt; &gt; "send us a correction" at the bottom of the
&gt; recipe.
&gt; &gt; &gt; When you update a
&gt; &gt; &gt; recipe that is already here everyone benefits.
&gt; When
&gt; &gt; &gt; you plagiarize
&gt; &gt; &gt; other recipes for you own gain, it hurts
&gt; everyone
&gt; &gt; &gt; and causes more work
&gt; &gt; &gt; for us.
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; Please do not do this sort of thing again.  If
&gt; you
&gt; &gt; &gt; have done it
&gt; &gt; &gt; already, please reply with the recipe ID #s so
&gt; that
&gt; &gt; &gt; I can fix them.
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; Title      :Tuna Salad Sandwich With A Bite! #2
&gt; &gt; &gt; ZAAR_Member:59388
&gt; &gt; &gt; PrepTime   :15
&gt; &gt; &gt; CookTime   :0
&gt; &gt; &gt; Serves     :2
&gt; &gt; &gt; Yield      :2 sandwiches
&gt; &gt; &gt; ZAAR_CATID :276,416,21,469
&gt; &gt; &gt; Description:Stolen from recipe #45911 but with
&gt; &gt; &gt; proper amounts added
&gt; &gt; &gt; into the the recipe so the nutritional qualities
&gt; &gt; &gt; come out correctly.
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; 1 can (6 oz.) tuna in water
&gt; &gt; &gt; 1 tablespoon red onion, finely chopped
&gt; &gt; &gt; 1   tablespoon chopped fresh parsley
&gt; &gt; &gt; 1   tablespoon light mayonnaise
&gt; &gt; &gt; 1   tablespoon horseradish
&gt; &gt; &gt; 4 pieces leafy greens
&gt; &gt; &gt; 4 slices of whole wheat bread
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt;   Drain tuna and mix with onion, parsley, mayo
&gt; and
&gt; &gt; &gt; horseradish.
&gt; &gt; &gt;   Adjust mayo and horseradish to personal taste.
&gt; &gt; &gt;   Spread on bread or in a pita, top with leafy
&gt; &gt; &gt; greens and enjoy!
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; &gt; Gay Gilmore
&gt; &gt; &gt; Recipezaar: Where the Recipes Are
&gt; &gt; &gt; http://www.recipezaar.com
&gt; &gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; =====
&gt; &gt; "In three words I can sum up all that I've learned
&gt; about life: it goes on"-Robert
&gt; &gt; Frost
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt;
&gt;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2184</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2003-06-26 14:54:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2003-06-26 21:54:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>dumbass-and-dumbasser</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>