<item>
		<title>Credit Card number stolen</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/03/31/credit-card-number-stolen/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 13:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/03/31/credit-card-number-stolen/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I discovered 14 fraudulent charges on our credit card a few weeks ago totaling over $7,000. Our credit cards were not stolen and the charges were all made at physical stores in the Seattle area, so someone is carrying a physical card that has had the magnetic strip changed to use our number. In 16+ years of using credit cards, I've never had this happen although "it's apparently very common":http://www.bankrate.com/brm/news/cc/20000927.asp.


<!--more-->

I called all the stores where the purchases were made and they faxed me the receipts. Here's their spending spree:

|02/26/2008| 8:25pm|OFFICE DEPOT #907 SEATTLE WA		|$1,306.79|Laptop computer|
{background:#eee}.|02/26/2008| 9:20pm|WHOLEFDS WSL 10216 SWH SEATTLE WA	|  $229.89|Groceries|
|02/27/2008|12:57pm|THE HOME DEPOT 4702 SEATTLE WA		|  $907.34|Chandelier, hardwood flooring|
{background:#eee}.|02/27/2008| 1:07pm|WAL-MART #2594 LYNNWOOD WA			|$1,000.00|2 $500 gift cards (register 18)|
|02/27/2008| 1:23pm|WAL-MART LYNNWOOD WA				|$1,792.41|2 laptops, X-box|
{background:#eee}.|02/27/2008| 1:28pm|NORDSTROM #0001 Q18 SEATTLE WA		|  $119.74|Shoes|
|02/27/2008| 1:49pm|WAL-MART #5195 EVERETT (W) WA		|$1,000.00|???|
{background:#eee}.|02/27/2008| 2:33pm|WAL-MART #5195 EVERETT (W) WA		|$1,587.34|???|
|02/27/2008| 2:49pm|MANOR MARKET AND DELI LYNNWOOD WA	|   $30.54|Lunch? Beer?|
{background:#eee}.|02/27/2008| 3:53pm|SHELL OIL SEATTLE WA				|   $74.72|Gas?|
|02/27/2008| 7:38pm|SHELL OIL SEATTLE WA				|   $17.81|Gas?|
{background:#eee}.|02/28/2008|11:38am|WAL-MART #2594 LYNNWOOD WA			|   $87.95|Camera w/ lens, camcorder|
|02/29/2008| 3:53pm|SHELL OIL SEATTLE WA				|   $52.01|Gas?|
{background:#eee}.|02/29/2008| 4:58pm|SHELL OIL SEATTLE WA				|   $74.64|Gas?|

Unless it's a coincidence that these purchases were made in the same city we live in, the person must have had access to our credit card recently and copied the number. We buy online almost exclusively so there are only three local transactions where that could have happened. And two of those are places we've used a lot without problem, so that left one merchant that is likely to have stolen our number.

I did some internet research about that merchant, a small "mom and pop" store that Gay visited days before the fraudulent charges began. Gay had a conversation with the owner while she was there. The owner mentioned that her husband is a policeman. He has a very unique name so it was easy to Google him. According to King County, he is no longer a policeman and was arrested in December 2007 for stalking and assault and is currently out on bail. Why would she claim her husband is a policeman when he's not and hasn't been for a while? Not that this means he or they did it, but I'll be surprised if it turns out not to be them.

Fortunately, Wal-Mart and Home Depot videotapes all transactions so there should be a decent view of the person in one of the transactions made at these stores. If they can be identified as the people who own the store where we suspect it happened, it should be easy to catch them. But I don't get the feeling the police care much about crimes like this since it's not a violent crime and almost seems like a victim-less crime. We aren't responsible for these charges and the credit card company or the bank aren't responsible either. The stores where these charges occurred end up paying for it and they pass the charge on to their customers in the form of higher prices. The victim is the general public even though most people assume they aren't harmed since they are not responsible for the charges.

The stores themselves are helpless to prevent this, though. The credit card companies should prevent it. I can think of some solutions:

* The magnetic strip on the credit card stores the number only. If the card stored the name on the card too and the authorization system checked the number and the name on the account the charges could be declined. It'd be the responsibility of the cashier to check the ID of the person to see if it matches the name on the card. Fake IDs could be used, but the criminal would need to get a fake ID for every credit card they've stolen.
* Require a PIN or password to be entered by the cardholder at the point of sale. Debit card transactions require this, so the infrastructure is in place already.
* Don't print card numbers on the card. Give cardholders the number that they can store elsewhere for use in online or mail-order transactions.
* Print a different number on the card that is used only for online transactions. A transaction that is done in person would be declined (and vice versa).

But since the credit card companies aren't responsible for fraudulent charges, they have little incentive to do anything.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3310</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-03-31 06:24:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-03-31 13:24:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>credit-card-number-stolen</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>599</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Todd]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>96.231.45.130</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-03-31 22:02:34</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-04-01 05:02:34</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Interesting, and glad you aren't hit directly with the fraudulent charges.

Looking at the record, though, it appears that a single person could not make all those charges in rapid-fire sequence, even if the stores are physically located next to one another.

1:23 -- 2 laptops and an Xbox
1:28 -- Shoes

Wow, 5 minutes to get out of Walmart carrying 3 fairly sizable boxes, and into a shoe store, picking a shoe style, getting the store worker to get find a box out of the back room, and checked out? I don't think I have ever had that level of speedy service at any shoe store in my life.

And earlier: A bunch of flooring at HD at 12:57, then 10 minutes later buying gift cards. Doubtful that they wheeled the boxes of flooring into Walmart.

And then on 2/29, what appears to be 2 full tanks of gas in an hour? According to the trip computer in my car, it takes me about 8 or 9 hours of around-town driving to burn a tank of gas off. And the amount of gas varies considerably, $75 for one, $52 for the other. Probably a medium SUV or truck and a mid-size car were filled.

What I find amazing is that the CC company didn't call you to question the staccato of purchases. Ours always do, even when we buy a bunch of stuff online at Christmastime in just a few hours.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>600</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dottroy@mac.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-04-01 07:43:27</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-04-01 14:43:27</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The Home Depot and Wal-Mart are located very close to each other, so I could imagine one person could get from one to the other in 10 minutes to buy a gift card. The Nordstrom is in downtown Seattle which is a long way from the Wal-Mart and the shoes purchased are women's shoes, so my guess is that the wife made that purchase. I assume the gas purchases were for the cars of their friends and it was a test to see if the card still worked.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>601</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[olabimtan777@yahoo.com is a thief]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/10/07/olabimtan777yahoocom-is-a-thief/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-10-07 12:13:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-10-07 19:13:30</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] is the second time our credit card number has been stolen in a year! The first time was in February. It&#8217;s never happened in 20 years of using credit cards, but now it&#8217;s [...]]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>602</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[CA]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>74.75.227.77</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-01-02 10:26:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-01-02 17:26:08</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I just had a situation in which my card # was used without the card and the card # was given out at The Home Depot store by the clerk who simply looked at a fake ID. Don't assume that home Depot will investigate this a they may be the ones culpable. Is not a co-insidence the Home Depot was the first charge. I all likehood they were able to make charges because they had the information.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>603</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Israel]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.139.41.162</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-06-03 12:05:44</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-06-03 19:05:44</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Its happend to me as well. Did any turn in a police report?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>604</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[mary]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.182.35.162</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-07-23 11:31:32</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-07-23 18:31:32</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Just for your information,it's not the merchantthat takes the loss; it is your fianancial institution or credit card company.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>605</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dottroy@mac.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://troyandgay.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>192.168.0.1</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-07-23 11:46:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-07-23 18:46:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[That's not necessarily true. Visa can (and does) refuse to pay a merchant if they shouldn't have accepted the card, didn't check for ID, etc. But it doesn't matter, the costs are being passed to consumers or merchants in one way or another, either through direct loss or through higher credit card fees. If the merchant can't raise prices to cover it, they eat the loss in profit. There's no free lunch.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>