<item>
		<title>FedEx Home Delivery SUCKS</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2003/10/15/fedex-home-delivery-sucks/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2003 23:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/?p=2415</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I was expecting a FedEx delivery today. At 3pm our dogs barked [Note: the dogs were <b>inside</b> the house, not outside] which usually means someone drove up to the house. I looked out the window to see the FedEx truck driving away so I went to the door to pick up my package. Nothing. There was a sticker on the door, no more than 2 feet from the doorbell, that said no one was at home to deliver the package so they left and will retry tomorrow. He didn't ring the doorbell or knock. He just left.

He did the same thing last week. Fortunately, we are having our house painted and the painter happened to catch him as he was leaving and he explained that we were at home. We're <i>always</i> at home.

So I called FedEx to complain and told them that we've never had a problem with FedEx deliveries in the past and that our signature was on file so they could leave packages when we weren't home so he should have just left it. I was told that FedEx just bought a company called "RPS" (by "just" she meant <a href="http://milwaukee.bizjournals.com/milwaukee/stories/2000/03/13/story5.html">5 years ago</a>) and that part of the contract with RPS was that RPS would not abide by FedEx's policies (such as leaving packages), their computers would not be connected to FedEx's computers, they had no way of contacting the local delivery people or the driver. Strange, I don't remember getting the fax or email that announced FedEx had bought a delivery company and that everything would be different. I guess I need to keep more up-to-date with the corporate doings of FedEx in order to be a good customer of theirs. Idiots. I commented that the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing and she replied "Yes, exactly".

I finally got through to a dispatcher who promised to call me back when he knew more details. 90 minutes later, no call. I called again, explained the situation, sat on hold and then was told that the driver was too far away now and I'd have to wait til tomorrow. I have to wait because the moron doesn't know how to ring a doorbell! And why won't he do the same thing tomorrow? Or next week when I get another delivery? These are the questions I asked and it was suggested that I make a sign and put it on the front door for FedEx that says that we're home and that he should ring the doorbell. That assumes that the delivery guy can read, of course. Funny that I don't have to do that for either UPS or Airborne.

<a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=fedex+sucks&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8"></a>.

By the way, FedEx Home Delivery's web tracking also sucks. They never update it, so you see the 1st item and then when it's delivered (or not), you see all the days between today and the day it shipped. And worse, they don't give you a URL, it's a form POST so to track your shipment you have to repeatedly enter the 92-digit tracking number into their form. Idiots<sup>2</sup>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2415</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2003-10-15 16:59:14</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2003-10-15 23:59:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>fedex-home-delivery-sucks</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>5</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Elizabeth Fullerton]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>laydownsally1@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.30.224.33</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-10-16 08:13:55</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Another reason they suck is because they allowed Mailboxes Unlimited to become the UPS store. At five o'clock in the afternoon on the last day that I can mail my yearbook shipment, I have to drive around town to find a FedEx man and flag him down, if that is possible because now that they refused to pay Mailbox's to keep pickup's at their stores there is no (cuss word deleted) place to drop off a package after hours. I guess we could just send it in a day late or get it ready a day early:that will never happen.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>6</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[George]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Flicka1426@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.209.176</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-11-18 16:41:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Maybe the reason the guy left without knocking  was because there may have been some dogs loose in the yard. That is a big problem many times, I just spoke with a friend and he said the Fed-Ex man that delivered to his home was just bitten that day by a German Shepard.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>7</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Michael]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kmtinnj@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>170.224.224.38</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-11-24 18:27:07</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Very well put.  Fedex home delivery uses idependent contractor's who do not get paid for the stop unless it is delvered, why would they not drop it off?  Saying they suck shows your level of int. put your dogs inside show some safety and concen for someone tryig to make a living.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>8</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy Hakala]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>troyhakala@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.231.34.132</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-11-24 23:49:09</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Nice theory, but there were no dogs in the yard. Maybe there were gremlins or other scary things to FedEx people. Seriously, FedEx themselves admitted that they just didn't know how to find the address and two employees also told me personally they didn't understand the problem because the house was very easy for them to find.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>9</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Jun]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>airjun@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.airjun.blogspot.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.127.70.152</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-11-26 19:21:38</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[as I type this I am sitting here waiting for Fedex Home delivery to get here. My past experience has been fine with fedex ie 2nd day overnight but this time its shiped HOME DELIVERY and it blows ASS!!. I got a note 3 days ago saying i wasnt home, I was!. there has been no second attempts in the last 2 days! How do I know? I sat on my ass waiting no note no anything. Worst its thanks giving I could have been beating all the traffic and be at my moms house. The tracking blows also! the last time it was updated was on the 22nd (put on delivery truck) That didnt show up onthe tracking page until the 23rd!!.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>10</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Steve D]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ashokanm@localnet.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.179.3.92</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-11-29 06:27:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Same experience(s) here..... I live in a rural area.  UPS can find my house, Fedex (regular) can find my house, Airborne can find my house.  Fedex Home can NEVER find my house - doesn't matter how many times we've given them directions or whether they were here last week or not. Waiting for a package now that was "On Fedex vehicle for delivery" on Wed. Tracking comment is once again "Unable to locate address". No calls for directions,(yet). They really do suck.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>11</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Shantanu]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>shanroam@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>156.153.254.42</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-16 17:26:01</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I fully empathize with all your experiences.
The experience everyone out here have narrated
seems so very close to what mine are. UPS never
had problems finding my apartment, FEDEX always did. The supervisors that I talked to in so many
occassions were least interested in hearing my
side; they were busy telling me why the address in
my package was wrong or how they could not find anyone in the apartment.
I am really at a loss, trying to understand why FEDEX can continue with such a bad home delivery system where they have almost everyone complaining about them.
They suck big time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>12</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[S. Lee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>spaceyette@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>4.60.33.41</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-18 19:01:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I don't get a lot of stuff shipped to me via  FedEx but here's what has happened to me before:

June 2002: FedEx claims that they couldn't find my apartment building even though they deliver stuff to our rental office every day.  I have to drive 20 miles to Compton to pick it up.

December 2002: FedEx tracking shows that they delivered a package that was signed and recieved by me.  Kind of funny since I hadn't seen it yet and I was home when they claimed they delivered it!!  After calling FexEx and checking with the rental office and all my neighbors, I wait for a few days to call the company that shipped it to tell them it got lost.  A few days later, it gets delivered.

December 2003:  FedEx does a repeat of December 2002.  The only difference is that I'm still waiting for it to show up......  This time when I called the local FedEx distribution center, they are extremely rude and tell me that they're too busy for me because its the holiday season.  Then they hang up.  Gee, thanks for nothing.  I then called the 800 number twice before I got in contact with someone seemed like they were doing more besides reading off a script.

In any case, don't use FedEx, ship everything UPS, they've never lost anything and they always leave a message on my answering maching letting me know where my delivery is if I'm not home.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>13</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Jared Falvo]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>luposian@cox.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.0.184.113</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-19 17:50:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Today (12/19/03), FedEx "Home Delivery" shows they delivered my package on their site, but there's no package by our door or anywhere!  Says it was delivered to our front door.  Uh, no it wasn't.

Talking to a rep (via a lengthy automatic menuing system), I am told the local office will have to check with the driver and I *might* hear back from them tomorrow (Saturday) or it might be delivered... dunno.

All I know is that I've got $80 hanging in the balance and I'm panicking, because this has never happened to me before.  FedEx, UPS, etc.

Luposian]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>14</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[L S Dumas]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>wmae@earthlink.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>165.121.215.243</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-26 21:24:21</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi. You guys are lucky in some respects. My mother works for Fed Ex Home Delivery, and this onel ady called in with a complaint about a HD worker who threw her package in the front yard everytime she had a delivery made, even if she was on the porch. Maybe it's you the driver doesn't like. Also, some addresses are hard to find, I know because sometimes I ride along to navigate, and dark ass streets don't help. Nor does the lack of addresses. I hardly think we should just sutomatically knw where the hell your address is. Don't forget these are regular people, relying on navigating software, and customer information. And because there are alot of packages, time is critical. There is not alot of time to sit and wait on someone to come to the door. Most packages can be driver released, however some companies, like Old Navy, penalize the company who penalizes the driver if they don't obtain a signature from the delivery recipient, and some don't allow indirect deliveries, like to your painter. Things change. Like everything else, you adapt, or die. (not literal Death in this case, but I'm sure you get my drift.) I have to go now, Fedex is waling into a discrimination lawsuit for violating federal, state, and city laws, and I need to do some reesearch. Good luck on your future deliveries. I like UPS better myself.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>15</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[L S Dumas]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>wmae@earthlink.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>165.121.215.243</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-26 21:28:24</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi. You guys are lucky in some respects. My mother works for Fed Ex Home Delivery, and this one lady called in with a complaint about a HD worker who threw her package in the front yard everytime she had a delivery made, even if she was on the porch! Maybe it's you the driver doesn't like. Also, some addresses are hard to find, I know because sometimes I ride along to navigate, and dark ass streets don't help. Nor does the lack of addresses. I hardly think we should just automatically know where the hell your address is. Don't forget these are regular people, relying on navigating software, and customer information. (Your address on your house and mailbox contibutes to your informational input). And because there are alot of packages, time is critical. There is not alot of time to sit and wait on someone to come to the door. Most packages can be driver released, however some companies, like Old Navy, penalize the company who penalizes the driver if they don't obtain a signature from the delivery recipient, and some don't allow indirect deliveries, like to your painter. Things change. Like everything else, so you adapt, or die. (not literal Death in this case, but I'm sure you get my drift.) I have to go now, Fedex is walking into a discrimination lawsuit for violating federal, state, and city laws, and I need to do some reesearch. Good luck on your future deliveries. I like UPS better myself.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>16</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[jane]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>janeselfe@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>152.163.252.33</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2003-12-31 11:18:25</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[i am, at this moment, violent on the subject of fedex home delivery.
they are not working today. who knew.
they have had a package for me on their truck since yesterday--so now i wont get it until friday.
outrageous.
i cant even pick it up anywhere.
never again]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>17</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[kurt]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kmckenney@mchsi.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.218.57.85</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-01 20:38:12</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Heres my experience. FEDEX was contracted to deliver a time sensitive shipment of computer parts from a retailer in New Jersey to my home in Iowa. They had been paid for priority Overnight shipping, yet the time of arrival passed and the delivery was not even in the state yet. Upon calling them, I was told that I would not recieve my package for 2 more days.

Now I am out the cost of the package, due to this being involved in a RMA, and $500 a day billable. This has been explained to them. They have offered to return the cost of shipping, but are unwilling to accept the responsibility of their breach of contract.

Now, lets think about this for a moment. If I were to contract them for shipping, and I refused to pay them for $1100 in shipping costs, I would likely wind up in jail. However, they cost me $1100 and thats ok?

Heres what I recommend, http://fdx.client.shareholder.com/board.cfm
that is the list of their board of directors. Now, if we all start sending e-mails to them explaining the situations we are facing, and cc to a few news agencies. Then keep repeating until they respond, either the News agencies or FEDEX will be adaquate, as the bad press would likely kill FEDEXs stock value.

I will be doing a bit more research to make the whole process easier, but please remember, stick to the facts, and together we can make FEDEX see the error of their ways.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>18</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Tom]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>aaa.@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.82.9.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-03 18:21:13</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Are you kidding?!?!? I left my house at 4:25 p.m. to go bowling tonight and I get home and my wife tells me there's a note on the door from Fed Ex Home Delivery and looked at the time on the note guess what he was there at 4:15 geez so now I guess I'm not going to get my package after all won't be home the rest of the week gotta work to make a living. Does Fed Ex Home Delivery think money grows on trees? If they do I wanna know how they did it......]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>19</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[T]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>xdelco@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.82.9.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-03 18:22:34</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Are you kidding?!?!? I left my house at 4:25 p.m. to go bowling tonight and I get home and my wife tells me there's a note on the door from Fed Ex Home Delivery and looked at the time on the note guess what he was there at 4:15 geez so now I guess I'm not going to get my package after all won't be home the rest of the week gotta work to make a living. Does Fed Ex Home Delivery think money grows on trees? If they do I wanna know how they did it......]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>20</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Garland Fuller]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>czar73us@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.51.179.19</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-03 20:13:40</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[As a manager at FedEx Home Delivery, I can only express my deepest apologies for your collective service experiences. These actions in no way reflect acceptable business practices. FedEx Home Delivery management, employees, and contractors exist for one purpose. That purpose is to provide superior (on time) service to our customer base. If we have one bad experience, that's one too many. Though I do not provide service to the aformentioned delivery areas, it concerns me a great deal that we have so many dissatisfied customers. I welcome the criticism however because that's the only way that we know where our problems lie. Our official stance as a company is to service every package everyday. I ask that you do not give up on the Home Delivery system as we are constantly seeking ways to improve our customer experience. I personally plan to share this correspondance with my business partners this Tuesday 010503 and my region staff as well. Thank you for your thoughts and your time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>21</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Terry Josleyn]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>CWOjos@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.107.226.76</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-06 17:13:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[As I sit here waiting on a package from Fedex Home Delivery that left for delivery at 9:15am this morning it is now 8:11pm at night still nothing and no messages on the door. This really does suck when you really need the item that was shipped...............]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>22</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Gary]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>gdaniels2002@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.166.23.7</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-10 11:11:49</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've had all the same problems with FedEx as well. When I lived in a rural area FedEx was the only company who could NOT find my address. UPS and Airborne both found it....without even having to call me for directions. Now I live in a major metropolitan area...and FedEx likes to leave notes instead of ringing the doorbell. Just a few months ago, after having this experience one day I decided to literally sit RIGHT BY the door to make absolutely sure I would hear him knocking/ringing. I even left the door partly cracked open. And I would occassionally even open the door and look out just to make sure. Well literally 15 minutes after I had looked out my door and then decided to look out again, I find a note from FedEx on my door!!!! How the #*%@ did he accomplish that??????? Why the hell wouldn't he just knock or ring the doorbell???? What benefit is there to him to walk all the way to my front door but only leave a note????? This doesn't make logical sense. I honestly thought my experiences were a fluke....that there was no way this could be happening to lots of people, otherwise the company would go out of business.  Now I see that I was wrong.

I was even considering buying FedEx stock pretty soon, because I saw a report that online shopping had increased 15% last year....thus online shipping companies should be a good investment. Even with my bad experiences I assumed there was NO WAY this was widespread. But now after reading this site.......I will only buy UPS stock.  Period.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>23</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[G.]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>gdaniels2002@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.166.23.7</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-10 11:12:06</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've had all the same problems with FedEx as well. When I lived in a rural area FedEx was the only company who could NOT find my address. UPS and Airborne both found it....without even having to call me for directions. Now I live in a major metropolitan area...and FedEx likes to leave notes instead of ringing the doorbell. Just a few months ago, after having this experience one day I decided to literally sit RIGHT BY the door to make absolutely sure I would hear him knocking/ringing. I even left the door partly cracked open. And I would occassionally even open the door and look out just to make sure. Well literally 15 minutes after I had looked out my door and then decided to look out again, I find a note from FedEx on my door!!!! How the #*%@ did he accomplish that??????? Why the hell wouldn't he just knock or ring the doorbell???? What benefit is there to him to walk all the way to my front door but only leave a note????? This doesn't make logical sense. I honestly thought my experiences were a fluke....that there was no way this could be happening to lots of people, otherwise the company would go out of business.  Now I see that I was wrong.

I was even considering buying FedEx stock pretty soon, because I saw a report that online shopping had increased 15% last year....thus online shipping companies should be a good investment. Even with my bad experiences I assumed there was NO WAY this was widespread. But now after reading this site.......I will only buy UPS stock.  Period.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>24</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Stephen]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>spratt1@rochester.rr.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.66.157.186</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-10 18:03:21</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[My package is due to be delivered on this coming Tuesday.  This is Saturday.  I saw via the tracking info that the package was at the depot.  I called FedEx at 8:30AM to see if I could pick it up instead of waiting for it to be delivered.  They put me in touch with the local depot who said they would pull it off the truck because it was already loaded for delivery today.  I said really?  You mean I will be getting it early?  They said yes.  So I said great, leave it on the truck.

It's now 8:45PM in the evening.  No package.  I could have picked it up at 9PM this morning!!
....

OMG... This is funny. As I am writing this my dog (inside) barks.  I look out the window.  They are HERE.  They just left the package at my door without ringing the bell or knocking.  It's a good thing I have a dog.  I don't think the guitar that I had shipped would enjoy being in -5 degree temps in a snow bank all night.  So... good service (I got my package early), but poor execution.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>25</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Nancy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>NT125honda@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>152.163.252.33</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-16 19:33:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Well I got you all beat with my complaint with Fedex Home Delivery. I responded to an ad for seasonal help wanted by Fedex Home Delivery in Nov 2003. I was called, sent for a physical, they did a criminal background check and I was told to report for training Nov 16,2003 with 7 others. We were told the hourly wage was 9.47 per hour and that 90% of their seasonal temps stay on past Christmas. We went thru rigorous drivers training with cargo vans and 5 of us passed. We were told we would be called the next day to report. One day, no call, two days, no call. I called the third day and was told to come in Nov 26 to do my observation ride with another driver, which I did. I was told to report back the next day, which I did, 50 miles one way, and was told I was not needed but please come back the next day. I did and was told I was not needed, no offer of compensation for gas or time. I was told they would call me the next day. I'm still waiting. To add insult to injury, I was paid 5.15 for the week I was in training AND NOT PAID for the day I spent doing an observation ride!!!!! I have called repeatedly to get paid for Nov 26 and the manager will not return my phone calls!!!!!!!If that don't beat all. I will NEVER EVER use Fedex for anything.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>26</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Rick]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>theguitarguru@lycos.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.37.234.233</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-22 17:54:44</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[We'll I just had my fun with FedEx and it wasn't pretty. I ordered a big desk. 94lbs. 33"x52". The driver came, left a note on the door and it said they'd be back next day. No problem, but I had to call to request that they come by after 5. The custmer service rep said it would be fine. I waited till 7:30. No phone calls, nothing. So I called them to find out, that they won't deliver to me after 4 p.m. What? Why wasn't I told that? Why didn't somebody call me? I was told that I should have called! I wanted a manager. He hung up on me after he was putting me on hold. Idiots! Idiots!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>27</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[nonWhiner]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nonWhiner@fu.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.fu.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.20.143.6</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-01-30 23:16:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Man -- your nifty "blog" is so full of whiners. Get over it, yourself, etc. Tie up your dogs and your ugly wife, get a real job, and leave these guys alone. Seems like it wouldn't matter who delivered your packages ... you'd whine about it anyway. This is the only page I have seen from your site, but I wonder how many other companies or people you complain and bitch and moan about. Type is Cheap. Act with your wallet and spare google and the rest of the world your fucking sorry story.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>28</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Al Your Pal]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>lststrike@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.35.165.249</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-04 13:13:11</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I live in a gated community.

For a while, it seemed, FedEx was doing the job okay. I order a lot of computer parts and whatnot, so I'm using some form of delivery fairly regularly.

After a short time, when I ordered a part that I really needed to get, it didn't arrive during the expected time frame. Somebody noted the problem of the tracking website not being updated, and I've noticed that. But this time, the package was shown as having reached my city, Albuquerque, NM, and as being ready for delivery... I'm like, WTF? ...

So, I call them up, and ask where my pakcage is, and that the site shows that the package is ready for pick-up. So the lady tells me, - are you ready for this? ... That the driver COULDN'T GET INTO THE COMMUNITY BECAUSE OF THE GATES!!!

Why is this funny?

Well, first, because, I've never heard this particular argument before,... I mean, they've been able to deliver stuff with no problem before, as has UPS, now all of a sudden, it's a problem? Strange.

Second, I figure, if I was in the package delivery business,... I'd make sure I could "deliver the goods" so to speak, before I said I could do it, and took the customer's money to do it. Sound reasonable? I think so.
I mean, how the hell is it MY problem if they can't procure whatever code they need to get through? If it was a problem they should have indicated so, and I would have insisted on UPS, who's never had a problem with this, nor has the Postal Service.

Another funny thing is,... the "Gate" is really a joke, anyway. It doesn't do anything except maybe serve notice to folks that they shouldn't be here unless they have business with someone here. People pass through the gates all the time by simply tailgating through behind the people with authorisation. I mean, it's commonplace, even though your not supposed to.

Thieves, homeless folks, winos, and assorted troublemakers can get through the gates, but FedEx just can't make it happen.

Whenever I possibly can, I use the Postal Service's priority mail. They put the package in the Box next to the mailboxes, and if it's too big, then they come and ring your door.

Otherwise I use UPS.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>29</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Comegetsome]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Comegetsome@yourhole.org</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.35.165.249</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-04 13:31:33</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[BTW, just saw the post from nonWhiner.

And I just have to say, nonWhiner, why don't YOU just STFU, and save everybody the trouble of reading your worthless thoughts?

Better yet, you sound like the kind of dude who has a gun.

Better get cracking and put that thing to use - on yourself.

Do the right thing, and put a bullet in your head.

Not only will you spare yourself unnecessary pain and ridicule, you'll be saving the environment.

Cheers!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>30</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Delivery Girl]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Notallbad@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.40.75.156</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-11 04:08:47</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I will try to make this quick - My father and I deliver for FedEx Home.  An average day is between 100 and 150 stops.  I will definitely agree that a lot of the guys who deliver for Home Delivery do stupid things, like not ringing doorbells, or not delivering everything on their trucks.  Believe me it is horrible to work with and we end up delivering packages that could have been delivered days earlier.  As was noter earlier, contractors are not paid until a package is delivered.  If it takes my dad or myself 3 days to get someone to sign for a package, we get paid once.  I don't know why some drivers don't try to make their deliveries, and I'm sorry for the bad experiences, but there are some drivers who do everything in their power, including driving around until they find streets that their software can't find.  I just would like to point out that the 150 people a day that my dad delivers to, on time, ringing doorbells, searching for addresses, getting to know his customers, are not going to post on websites.  Only the people with bad experiences do.  So if there are 30 people with bad experiences out of the 6,000 packages delivered a day from my local hub, don't totally blame FedEx Home, blame the idiots who didn't do their jobs, not the whole system.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>31</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy Hakala]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>troyhakala@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://recipezaar.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.19.147.254</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-11 09:58:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I just don't buy this FedEx employee claim that it's "just a few bad drivers". That may be true, but FedEx employs them and trains them. They wear FedEx badges and they represent FedEx. It is FedEx as far as I'm concerned. Besides, as has been noted, UPS doesn't have these problems  -- UPS has been perfect, in my experience. How does UPS not hire these "bad drivers"? Maybe there's a problem with FedEx's hiring?

Also, not everyone that has a bad experience complains either, so don't fool yourself into thinking that you only hear about the bad things, there's many more that you don't hear about.

But I will say that all my problems have been with FedEx Home Delivery, not FedEx Express Delivery. They're totally separate and Express is much much better. It's the FedEx Home Delivery (the trucks with the little dog carrying a package next to the logo) that sucks.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>32</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[J. Fenton]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>jlfenton65@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.136.108.212</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-17 21:01:17</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Rather than leave a negative comment (which I could), I'll leave a positive one. The UPS where I live is excellent. In fact, they put cellular phones in their trucks. The driver actually gives you a call as he pulls up to the house. It allows me to stop what I'm doing and be waiting at the gate for him to hand me my package. This sort of service should be standard for delivery services.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>33</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[MRM]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mrm.spam@windowtree.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.38.187.3</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-21 17:47:32</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Waiting for my new camera to arrive. Stayed home all day because didn't want to miss the package and have some idiot leave it on the front porch. Tracking info says it will arrive today. But I'm living a pipe dream. FedEx HD has once again failed to come through on their very own promise of delivery. This costs me time and money waiting on them. Unfortunately UPS sucks too. If I could just find one carrier that was reliable - I'd use them exclusively. But it seems that in this business there's just no pride in a job well done. Promises are worthless to FedEx. Ultimately, they don't give a shit if you wait a whole day for nothing.

Still waiting... maybe tomorrow...]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>34</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[PJ]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-23 09:07:18</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Having worked for FedEx home delivery I can sympathize with your comments. However from a contractor point of view and the rate of compensation in some instances it is not financially "worth it" to spend 10 to 15 minutes on a finding a delivery, going up to the 3rd floor, or going through apts and gated communities. It makes more sense to not attempt or declare you cannot find an address and get on with your day. We work from 6 am to sometimes 8 pm...basically your package is just another number to us.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>35</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Homedeliverywannabe]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>eddie_123@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.34.43.52</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-23 11:45:45</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey everyone,
  I've been looking at entering the FedEx home delivery arena and have been searching for information on it. I have the basics down I just wanted to ask some people who are involved in it or have been a few questions. If someone could contact me at eddie_123@hotmail.com since I don't know if it's allowed to post questions in here. Thanks so much for any help you could give. EddieG]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>36</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TiNy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>w9zro@netscape.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.21.2.64</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-02-28 07:45:33</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FED EX home delivery has the dog on the side?? maybe thats how they deliver strap it to a dalmation and send him off
I recently sent out a package 5:00 PM UPS and it got from Chicago to Indianapolis by 8:30 AM VIA UPS GROUND
I sent a package via FEDEX express same guy Chicago to INDY
at 10:30 AM that same day and it got there 3 days later
it sat in the sort facility for a day and a half
without being touched I called and got the brush off big suprise here right.
maybe they should use carrier pigeons instad of trucks it might be faster.
their estimated time of delivery is a joke
it should say this is when it is NOT going to be delivered.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>37</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[ecc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.137.23</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-01 08:47:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I also have worked for Home Delivery for almost two years. The person in an above comment who said your package is just another number is right. The more being shipped the less I have time to talk to customers. Example. I do 85-145 stops a day. At 85 stops I can ring on every doorbell and WAIT for the customer. At 145 stops the doorbell is rang and I am probably back in my truck and driving away to the next stop. During these peak times (120-150 stops) we work from 7:45am (this is when I start, everybody is different cause we are contractors) and am not done till 6pm or even 7pm. Now do the math. (remember, we are contractors and do not get paid breaks OR lunch-its hard to eat lunch in a vehicle and dangerous). That equals 10 hours 15 minutes of work with no breaks and no lunch (unless you want to be out even later and inturpt everyone who is sitting down for dinner). Many fedex home delivery drivers urinate in bottles in their trucks just so they can contiue on their routes without having to take the time to go to a conv. store or fast food resturaunt. I hope to find another job and would not encourage anyone to take this job unless you love HARD physical labor, no benefits,long hours,low pay,no lunch or breaks, and terrible untrustworthy local managers. The fedex managers ONLY care about themselves, but that is anthor subject.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>38</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.137.22</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-01 08:52:16</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FedEx managers care nothing about your packages, just about their jobs and how much they get paid. I am a fedex contractor and if anyone wants to complain, complain to the local managers at FedEx home delivery. They are losers at best.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>39</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX blows ass]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-01 23:31:14</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I would strongly suggest against becoming a Home Delivery Contractor. Presently you have to buy a new more expensive truck, but you are not given any more daily money towards it...just the same lame 25 a day towards use of it. You only make 1.14 a stop and 22 cents a package, along with whatever your "temporay" core zone rate is. This core zone has been diminished by 10 dollars a day every year as Fed Ex hopes to "phase" this out. Take into account every settlement you'll have to put aside money for your own taxes, fuel, truck payments and maintenance and you'll be lucky to clear 500 weekly after expenses. All this for extending your own good credit for a vehicle, working almost 10 to 12 hours a day daily, no benefits and the risk of paying for an incorrectly delivered customers package. GO Brown!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>40</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Ryan Lankford]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ryan@ryan-lankford.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.216.130.90</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-03 20:46:50</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I hope whoever's in charge in Des Moines, Iowa slides under a gas truck and tastes their own fucking blood.  Their tracking system sucks, thier delivery system sucks, and their customer service section needs to take a massive hit, 9/11 style.  They are all wastes of human sperm, from my experience...

I ordered a package Feb. 24, it was picked up by FedEx feb. 27th, and as of the 28th, according to their tracking page, it's sitting in a center in Rialto, California.  note the date of my post....and it's still sitting in that center, when it's due for delivery tomorrow, in Des Moines, Iowa.  I called FedEx, asking what the deal was, and they tell me that the package "is scheduled to be delivered tomorrow."  Duh, you fucking shiteaters!  How is it going to be delivered in Des Moines *tomorrow* when it's in California *today?*  I then informed them that I will be expecting a full refund of my shipping if the package isn't delivered as promised, and I'll be contacting the Attorney Generals in both Iowa and California.

People, that's the only way to rattle the cages of these godless profiteers...no business wants AG's in multiple states checking them out for multiple breaches of contracts.  As the word gets out that they're under investigation, the price of the stock goes down.  If you're someone who ordered something from a business that uses FedEx, stop doing business with them, too, but tell them exactly why..."because you use FedEx,a nd they provide inferior service.  I'll no longer do business with you until you stop using FedEx."

The anonymous pussy "nonWhiner" is right...hit them in the wallet...their fucking stockholders' wallets!  Nothing shouts "change" louder than a slipping stock value, and investors that are screaming bloody murder.

Would you guys really like to know the difference betwee FedEx and UPS, as to why you get better service from "Brown?"  UPS hires their own union drivers, who actually work for them, while FedEx uses independent contractors who technically don't work for FedEx, to save a buck, customer be damned.

Tell FedEx to eat a dick.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>41</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Daniel]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>danamanda3@cs.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>152.163.243.186</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-08 10:02:41</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ive been a contractor with fedex home delivery for almost 3 years now. My on-time delivery rate is 99%. There is alot going on at Fedex most people don't know.Let me explain how this corporate web traps contractors. First you have to purchase a truck which is around $30,000 or $550 a month. Second you pay for your own gas, I spent around $600 a month. Third you pay for Insurance ( auto+accident ) Which is around $300 a month. Those are the major expenses but also have to pay for maintainence, breakdowns, towing, rental van when truck is being fixed. If that isn't bad enough let me tell you we get NO BENEFITS what so ever. No Health,Dental,Retirement,No raises,No vacation pay,No paid time-off except holidays we get $50 dallars -WOW-. Now let me explain how we get paid. We get 5 cents a package to load our own truck. It usually take me about an hour per hundred packages, so I make $5 an hour to load my truck. After I load my truck and start delivering I make $1.14 per stop and $0.22 per package. I have to work very fast to make a profit. And for the packages that require a signature, If customer is not home to sign, I get paid nothing for my effort to deliver. So after all expences I make $500 a week. Compare that to UPS and you will see that I make half if not less than half of what UPS drivers make with NO BENEFITS. And UPS drivers don't load there own trucks, they hire loaders, and during holidays when volumes increase dramatically UPS puts two drivers per van to counter fatique. The only ones making out in this contracting web is the Fedex executives and with there huge salaries and bonuses. And to mention anything about a Union to Fedex management will put your contract in jeopardy. This is a reality that most contractors don't understand till you are in the company. Then its too late to turn back, You are stuck with the truck you had to buy till its paid off. This is why I think of it a a corporate WEB. Also I would like to mention that if you get seriosly hurt on the job you have two choices, pay someone else to drive your route or claim backrupcy and ruin your credit to get out of your truck payment. For the accident insurace I pay for will cover medical expenses if IM hurt on the job, it will not subsidize any income.
All of us contractors work hard to provide on-time deliverys. In return we get paid far less then others doing the same job. With no protection under the law, contracter are subject to take it or leave it contracts with fedex. Corporate Greed is The only language management speaks of.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>42</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[E Galang]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>myqtpie@adelphia.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>151.200.228.70</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-09 12:56:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Folks, it's really sad that we are all having this bad experience with Fedex.  I just had one.

I purchased an item in Ebay and unfortunately, the seller has no other carrier but Fedex.

The item was shipped on March 1 using ground service from Arizona to Virginia.  Expected delivery was Friday.  Weekend was over and there was no delivery.  Tracking wasn't updated.

Monday, March 8, I called 1-800-GO-FEDEX.  I was told that a note 'Business is close' was posted on the account.  I had assumed that a delivery attemp had been made and nobody was there.  I live in a residential area and Fedex leaves packages all the time. I needed the package so I offered to pick it up myself.  Customer Service said I could pick it up at their Chantilly location (at least 10 miles away) after 5 pm.

I drove there at 7 pm and I thought nobody was there.  Finally, a lady came to me and helped me.  She checked the system and tracked my item.  Item was still in one of their crates and no attempt had ever been made.  I wasted my time driving there and just elevated my disappointment.

I called 1-800-GOFEDEX from my cell phone.  My package couldn't be located.  I told customer service that I needed my package be delivered first thing next morning.

Today is that day.  It's already 4 pm and nothing has been delivered.  I already called customer service again and filed a complain.  Is Fedex listening to us, the consumers who pay their salaries?

LET'S GO WITH BROWN, UPS.  I will ask the ebay sellers to start using the BROWN.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>43</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[ecc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.189.16.102</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-09 18:14:13</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I also agree with Danial above. FedEx is getting away with murder when it comes to how they treat the workers (contractors). I am trying to find a different job and will never go back to fedex.

I encourage all people to STOP using FedEx (this includes Fedex express, Ground and Home Delivery). Any time you buy something on the web, check to see who is shipping it and if it is Fedex, call that company and request it be sent by a different company (UPS, or USPS). COming from an inside point of view, Fedex shareholders and management are ruthless and greedy. Look at it this way:

Federal Express (the original)-common workers with vacation,sicktime,hourly pay, benefits.

FedEx Ground--FedEx said hey we can save money buy making them buy thier own trucks! (ie but all the hassle on them--the overhead on a truck is outragous). Fedex will still load the trucks.

FedEx Home Delivery--You have to buy your truck,, you get no benifits,no hourly wage, no quarentee of any income, no vacation, no insurence, no sick time (paid or otherwise),AND you have to load your own truck in the morning, taking anywhere from an hour to 1 1/2. (during Xmas you might spend 2-3 hours in the terminal and still get only the $5 dollers. So for christmas you may work 12-15 houres with 1-3 of that unpaid!
Its a joke and a crime. FedEx might as well call themselves Enron or Walmart. If you are considering going into Fedex Ground or Home Delivery ask yourself this:
Like long hours?
VERY hard, heavy work?
No vacation?
No paid or otherwise sick leave?
Taking your days off to fix your own truck?
No guarentee of any income?
Then come work for Fedex.
If not then stay very far away!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>44</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX EAT ME]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-12 18:20:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I'm a FedEx home delivery contractor as well. Yep it sucks dick plain and simple. Everyone at my terminal wants out big time. I know if I get another opportunity I"m running out the door to escape. Fuck the truck, fuck FedEx keeping your 500 and last settlement. Anything is better than being a FedEx contractor. They have over 95% turnaround rate..why? Because your basically a third country worker with good credit. Too bad we couldn't all band together and do a walk out....]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>45</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[ecc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.137.8</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-15 07:57:50</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I agree with FEDEX EAT ME (above). We should try to do a National FedEx Home Delivery "day off" and have all contractors at the terminals not come in and see what happens to the fedex system. That would def. get media attention and Get the word out more about FedEx criminal buissnes practices.  DONT do it if you are thinking about home delivery. They encourage (on their website) for "minorities and women" to apply because they are "thought" to be more easily manipulated and eaiser to "control". Any one that is a Fedex Home Delivery COntractor should give this site to other contractors and let them put their two cents in.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>46</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Nicholas Cancelliere]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nickaustin74@mac.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.243.250.240</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-18 12:58:38</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FedEx Home Delivery (HD) is something anyone should avoid like the plague if they can help it.  I never have had such a horrible experience before. I ordered a computer from Apple - and took off the day from work when it was supposed to be delivered.  No one showed - I was home ALL day.  I called FedEx, they said it was showing 2 delivery attempts.  No one showed though, I explaiend to them I was home all day.  They opened a trace and said someone would contact me - perhaps he went to the wrong door they said.  So no one called.  I phoned them the next day - and again told they weren't sure what was going on.  No one was able to talk to the 3rd party, contracted, driver that they were using.  (FedEx HD doesn't use their own people).  So then I was like - "Okay, so what am I to do?"  She said someone would call me.  No one called -- then later on that day I called back AGAIN.  This time the gentleman said he would esclate it to 3 different departments, and apologized to me.  Finally someone called me ... but only to belittle me by going, "So are you going to be home today?"  I explained to her that I *WAS* home all day yesterday and planned to be today.  She said "Very well, we're definatley going to deliver, I'm really sorry."  Well that all said -- I still don't have my package!  I'm about to make my 4th call to FedEx and just go postal.  The problem is they use 3rd party couriers who they are unable to contact enroute and only can deliver messages to them when they return late in the evening.  Totally irresponsible.  My package will now be 3 days late --]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>47</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Dismayed_with_Fedex]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>no@email.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.215.177.230</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-19 20:42:35</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Wow, I have had only terrible experience with FedEx Ground as compared with delivery by just about any other significant competitor (UPS ground is excellent, USPS Priority is very good from other coast, etc.).

FedEx intentionally delays delivery of packages.  Read up FedEx, I will no longer order products from online merchants if I even have an inkling that they ship FedEx.  You are a third-rate shipper in my book.  UPS will deliver a ground package shipped from a local SoCal merchant overnight.  FedEx sits on the package in the warehouse for 4+ days every time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>48</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[bill]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>bill@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://bill.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.20.143.6</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-21 00:01:12</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[it's sad that you continue to erase postings that argue your point. I have posted a few times proclaiming my positive experiences about fedex, but you continue to "exempt" such comments. Sad.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>49</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[bill]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>bill@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://bill.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.20.143.6</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-21 00:01:55</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[it's sad that you continue to erase postings that argue your point. I have posted a few times proclaiming my positive experiences about fedex, but you continue to "exempt" such comments. Sad.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>50</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[bill]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>bill@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://bill.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.20.143.6</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-21 00:02:51</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[it's sad that you continue to erase postings that argue your point. I have posted a few times proclaiming my positive experiences about fedex, but you continue to "exempt" such comments. Sad.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>51</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy Hakala]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>troy@recipezaar.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://recipezaar.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.19.147.254</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-21 09:05:03</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[What are you talking about, bill? I haven't deleted anything other than spam ads for viagra.

Are you the same "bill" who posted asking us if I'm gay or if the "chick" is a lesbo? Hint: her first name is "Gay", not as in "homosexual" but as in "happy". Maybe you're just as equally confused about deleted posts?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>52</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fioricet]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>top@tredgf.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.top-fioricet.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>213.91.217.13</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-22 01:17:05</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ultram Generic Fioricet most likely reduces heart attack risk by irreversibly blocking the enzyme COX-1 online fioricet, thereby impairing the ability of platelets in the blood to form clots, Dr. Tobias Kurth of Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, and others explain in the American Heart Association's journal, fioricet Circulation. NSAIDs buy fioricet also lock on to COX-1, but the effect is reversible. Cheap Generic Fioricet or visit this site: http://www.top-fioricet.com !]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>53</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Narj]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Stimpy@theweb.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>159.250.18.39</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-22 13:55:22</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey folks, I buy and sell lots from home...ever hear of the UNITED STATES POSTAL SERVICE?!?!?

I have shipped HUNDREDS of packages and NEVER LOST ONE, never got DAMAGE.

If you try to do things in a more timely manner, you won't be counting on the failed promises of a one day deliery system run by indentured servants.

Sheeesh.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>54</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[peggie martha]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>MkmCleaning@netscape.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.2.44.253</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-23 15:20:48</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[fedex ground employees weak up and look for lawyers to sue you are being treated like employees,settlements that look like pay checks,you have supervisors you have managers,they glue your trucks with feex ground logo,this trucks are yours you pay for them they need to have your company name on them not fedex ground ,dot number on your trucks are strickly for fedex ground,if you are independent contractor you need to work for other companies not only fedex ground.they do your pay role the only thing not done is taxes. you are employees misclassified as ics thank you.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>55</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[job interview questions]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>top@tredgf.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.job-interview-questions-tips.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>213.91.217.13</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-24 01:21:22</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Do you know the difference between a failed interview and an amazing interview? Do you want to be able to answer even the toughest, meanest, and most low-down interview questions that you could ever be possibly asked? Do you want to go though your interview with confidence? Do you want to feel prepared, impress the interviewer, and win the job interview of your dreams? We provide you with job interview tips, visit http://www.job-interview-questions-tips.com]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>56</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Finally free]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-24 17:16:28</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Free at last....Free at last...Thank gawd almighty I am Free at last!!!  Translation...got a real job with benefits and regular hours. No more FedEx Home Delivery for me. Course now I have to get rid of the albatross around my neck...the FedEx Box Truck  If your thinking about being a FedEx contractor...don't FedEx is the most unprofessional and dirty handed mo fo out there. Take a real job cause the "partnership that works" only works for FedEX]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>57</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[quitcrying]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>srsmith55@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.202.125.84</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-25 09:24:02</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[For all of you who continue to compare UPS to FedEx you need to realize that UPS drivers get paid hourly, benefits, vacations and the FedEx drivers don't. Also you need to realize that there is anywhere from 2-12 UPS drivers covering the same area that 1 FedEx driver covers. It is complet nonsense to say that a driver came to your door and didn't leave the package ring or knock just left a note, FedEx drivers don't get paid for undelivered packages UPS does.  Now if the driver couldn't find your house try putting numbers on your mailboxes for your house, and if you have numbers make sure they can be seen. When ordering online make sure you enter all information correctly and if there is a place to put your phone number make sure you do so the driver can call if they can't find your house. Some people think that delivery drivers have some super human power that they know where every street and every house is located well I will bet that not one person who has complained on this site could deliver half the packages that a delivery driver does in one day.  For the contractors on this site badmouthing FHD it all depends on your manager some are good and some are bad, and you say you never get a raise what about every new fiscal year you do get some sort of raise.  Make sure you know your facts before spouting off at the mouth.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>58</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[knowyourfactsmister]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-25 17:23:37</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To quit crying....I know my facts. I'm doing the job now till tomorrow when I quit. Last year we went from $1.13 to $1.14 per stop in July. In November they decreased the daily core zone by $10 every day. So if you delivered like 100 stops you would make an extra dollar then lose 10 dollars in November for a net loss of 9 dollars a day. Obviously you are not a contractor probably some FedEx manager protoplasmic sperm dropping.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>59</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[quitcrying]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>srsmith55@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.202.125.84</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-26 06:46:39</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Knowyourfacts....Actually I'm not a manager I am a contractor, been for 3 years with FHD.  It must be either your region or your particular building with core zone decrease.  In our building 90% of core zones have stayed the same or gone up some, the termial manager can make all the difference in the world when it comes to core zones.  In your particular instance I can see where you would lose money if your zone dropped and your stop and package count didn't go up, also don't forget your ccs and service account bonus that you get that is basically free money there.  Protoplasmic sperm dropping I have encountered plenty of managers that would fall into that catagory, before our current manager our turnover rate was through the roof but the new manager has made a tremendous difference and we haven't lost anyone in probably a year.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>60</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX EAT ME]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-26 18:39:14</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Our terminal manager is a loser. You call the terminal around 2 and no one is anywhere to be found...I know cause my route is the same city that the terminal is in and I've gone back several times just to see the place locked up. You ask him to check on something and he just ya ya's you to death. But when he wants something watch out. Regardless the "business" model is skewed towards FedEx. All it takes is some maintenance or a claim and your making shit. You bust your ass all week, work a ton of hours and make a little more or less than a temp. Currently when I walked out today we have 9 contractors for 15 routes.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>61</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Anonymous Coward]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>.@com.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.115.36.10</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-03-29 14:38:16</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ordered a package FedEx Express on the 26th, their site said it would be here the 31st. Today is the 29th and they just left a notice even after I had properly filled out the release form after the last time they pulled the same shit. If you want no hassle shipping then I would go with USPS Priority Mail most definately.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>62</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[anonymous employee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>yankee479@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>128.206.193.185</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-09 08:53:45</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I read a lot of the comments on this blog, and as a 2nd van driver for a contractor, I thought I might offer a couple of reasons (not excuses) why some of these situations occur.

FedEx Home Delivery has TERRIBLE mapping software. A computer is supposed to plot each days delivery addresses on printed maps, along with turn-by-turn directions. Unfortunately, 10-20% of the address don't plot, and another 5-10% are plotted incorrectly.

Yet, that in and of itself probobly doesnt explain the whole story.

Rather, the story lies in the fact that FedEx Home Delivery and Ground relies on contractors, who are then allowed to hire almost anyone, to actually deliver the packages. Many of the contractors pay their drivers very little, and barely train them at all on their routes. As a result, turnover is very high, and customer service is very poor. One of the most popular ways contractors pay their home delivery drivers is per stop. Now, if your pay is based on how many addresses you can deliver to in a day, how motivated are you to provide good customer service? Most drivers deliver the bare minimum of customer service, basically just enough to prevent complaints. Many do not knock on doors or ring doorbells unless the signature is required because that takes an enormous amount of time.

UPS and Airborne drivers of course are paid by the hour, and quite a bit more I might add, so they are far more likely to deliver better customer service and adhere to special requests as far as delivery times and places.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>63</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX EAT ME]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-10 03:27:15</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To the person above:  Having been a fedex home delivery sucker....err I mean contractor...I agree with most of your statements. All the contractors in my terminal were delivering themselves as with what little you are compensated, you could never afford to pay another person. As a contractor I seldom rang bells or knocked on doors and hardly every filled out a door tag. Financially it was just ridicoulous to do that. Until FedEx steps up to the plate and pays people accordingly instead of the current way of treating them like 3rd world workers, they will always have a turnaround. No one is going to contract for Fedex long when they invest in a 30K plus truck,work 50 to 60 hours a week min and bring home around 500 a week clear after expenses. That is not a "partnership that works" that is a recipe for personal bankruptcy. If you are extending your own good credit, maintaining and paying for a delivery vehicle and busting your ass you should be paid accordingly not based on 1950 era wages. That is why turnaround in all the terminals are so high and why it will continue. I've seen contractors just walk out and say fuckit without even having another job lined up...It's that miserable and unrewarding. The big majority of contractors even go as far as signing customer names for signature required stops...just so they can deliver said packages and get compensated. I found it to be the most foolish, ridicoulous, asinine working environment I have ever come across. I am glad to be out of it, glad to have gotten rid of my truck and moved on. Knowing firsthand how fedex runs and conducts their business, I will never ever use them as a carrier. They are fucktards at best.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>64</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[choices]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>coopatcneez@msn.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.3.199.53</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 09:39:15</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi
 As a contractor for Home Delivery I understand both  the bitter comments about Fedex Home and the positive ones.Or maybe I should say the 1 positive comment.
 I have been a contractor for 2 years and have had both a rural route and a city route. I can tell you from experience that rural routes for a new contractor are HELL sometimes. Until you get to know your area and customers it's impossible  to give great service,and the customers could care less whether the contractor has time to drive around finding unmarked addresses on unmarked roads. I must comment that most of my customers were very understanding, and the occassional upset customer had good reason to be upset because the deal is Fedex is supposed to be on time. But as contractors there's not a thing we can do when everything is unfamiliar. There was no training for this route either, and the mapping system was zero help.
 The fact that it's impossible to drive 300 miles a day and make any money is a factor, not to mention constant 14 hour days. After about a month on this route I had it down though and was given a much better route in the city. If you can call it that...13.5 hour days are still common with 110 to 140 stops a day. Yes the gross pay looks awesome to an uninformed outsider but the fuel and maintenance expenses are unreal.
 The point is some of the dissatisfied customers are rightly upset considering Fedex promises superior service no matter what.
 I don't expect to win any customers back...that's not my mission. As far as I'm concerned UPS and Fedex are a lot the same, from the drivers point of view.We are friendly and helpful to each other. The fact that Fedex has several different ground services is very confusing to some customers, I have to admit.But I've heard plenty of complaints about UPS from my own customers. I keep my mouth shut.
 I do know there are some crappy contractors out there. I believe Fedex would be much better off with employees instead of contractors because there's only so much the management can do to motivate the contractor to shape up or ship out, except not renew the contract when it's time. And all the contractors I know who got the boot were relieved, not upset.
 It is an extremely tough job, and the opportunity is there to learn how to run a business under not the greatest conditions. My route is currently for sale because my 38 year old female body is wearing out, but I don't regret the experience because I plan to put it to good use in my next business venture. Perhaps I'm too honest with potential buyers warning them of what they're getting into.
 I know there are Fedex Home managers checking out this website and I hope you read my long note, along with all the angry customers.
 Fedex Home is a growing company, and growth is a mess sometimes. You know what I'm talking about.
 Strong terminal management makes a huge difference. We recently got a new TM and in some areas there have been big steps in improving conditions for drivers and customers already.
 In closing I will say to the angry customers,contractors and Fedex managers:
We all have choices. We are all in a position to improve conditions for ourselves and our clientele. The key is asking the right questions to the right people. It works for me, and it will work for you. Anger gets attention, but it does not get results,it only promotes fear.
 Thank you for your time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>65</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.137.23</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 15:54:41</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[It all comes down to money sometimes. FedEx (the company) wants to run its buissness as CHEAP as possible. Cant do that with regular employees (time off, vacation,sick time,employee comp, plus having to deal with all that from an admin point of view) so they create FedEx home Delivery and sell people on the idea of owning their own buissness. I have been doing this for two years now (fedex home delivery) and let me tell you, it is FAR from owning your own buissnes. You own a truck and thats it. Fedex tells you how, where, and when to do everything. The only way I make money is by working very fast and getting done because that is how you make a good hourly wage. Deliver 2000 stops a month, 1999 of them good to excellent and make one mistake or a box gets stolen, they take it out of your check!! Nothing is ever said about the 1999 you delivered awsome. People steal boxes and when I go to investigate tell them that it will come out of my paycheck. Once the guy said he did  not no that and he never resubmited the claim (prob cause he had got the box and submitted a claim to get some money, but then learned it comes out of our checks).This job is good for a few years, but long term (5-10 or longer) FORGET about it. If your route grows fast they dont care, it just means more hours for you. Allready work 7:30am till 6:30pm? No big deal. Fedex says your work hours are 9:ooam till 8:00pm! thats 11 hours plus the hour to 1 1/2 hours it takes to load. Like Christmas? Forget about it at Fedex Home delivery. 7am till 10 or 11pm for weeks. Contractors have been out till after midnight setting packages on peoples porches. Turnover? please! I became the 3rd oldest person in our terminal after only 6 months. 9 out of 11 routes have turned over in less than a 1 1/2 years. Too much work, too little reward. Wanna take vacation? Get a supplement to work for you and hope he dosent lose or get some boxes stolen while you are away. Come back from vacation and might have to pay OUT $200-or more dollers for inexperienced supplemnet drivers. Or worse they wreck your truck in some way. (remember they only do this part time or even only a few times a month) The supplements have broken down crying out on route from the overwhelming box numbers. Regular contractor works 9-12 hours a day (usually does not take lunch or eats while driving) How long do you think a supplement who does not know the route that well will be out? Midnight? Fedex says "oh well its your route--just get those F*cking boxes delivered". Training for Contractors AND supplemnets is almost non existent. (terrible at best).]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>66</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.190.72.122</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 15:55:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[It all comes down to money sometimes. FedEx (the company) wants to run its buissness as CHEAP as possible. Cant do that with regular employees (time off, vacation,sick time,employee comp, plus having to deal with all that from an admin point of view) so they create FedEx home Delivery and sell people on the idea of owning their own buissness. I have been doing this for two years now (fedex home delivery) and let me tell you, it is FAR from owning your own buissnes. You own a truck and thats it. Fedex tells you how, where, and when to do everything. The only way I make money is by working very fast and getting done because that is how you make a good hourly wage. Deliver 2000 stops a month, 1999 of them good to excellent and make one mistake or a box gets stolen, they take it out of your check!! Nothing is ever said about the 1999 you delivered awsome. People steal boxes and when I go to investigate tell them that it will come out of my paycheck. Once the guy said he did  not no that and he never resubmited the claim (prob cause he had got the box and submitted a claim to get some money, but then learned it comes out of our checks).This job is good for a few years, but long term (5-10 or longer) FORGET about it. If your route grows fast they dont care, it just means more hours for you. Allready work 7:30am till 6:30pm? No big deal. Fedex says your work hours are 9:ooam till 8:00pm! thats 11 hours plus the hour to 1 1/2 hours it takes to load. Like Christmas? Forget about it at Fedex Home delivery. 7am till 10 or 11pm for weeks. Contractors have been out till after midnight setting packages on peoples porches. Turnover? please! I became the 3rd oldest person in our terminal after only 6 months. 9 out of 11 routes have turned over in less than a 1 1/2 years. Too much work, too little reward. Wanna take vacation? Get a supplement to work for you and hope he dosent lose or get some boxes stolen while you are away. Come back from vacation and might have to pay OUT $200-or more dollers for inexperienced supplemnet drivers. Or worse they wreck your truck in some way. (remember they only do this part time or even only a few times a month) The supplements have broken down crying out on route from the overwhelming box numbers. Regular contractor works 9-12 hours a day (usually does not take lunch or eats while driving) How long do you think a supplement who does not know the route that well will be out? Midnight? Fedex says "oh well its your route--just get those F*cking boxes delivered". Training for Contractors AND supplemnets is almost non existent. (terrible at best).]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>67</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[tired and pissed]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>vdbarber@juno.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.136.26.225</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 23:50:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been a FedEx Home Delivery contractor for over four years.At one time my family owned four routes in two states. We are now down to two and will soon be down to zero. I can't believe how poorly the contractors are treated compared to four years ago and how little the pay has increased. Anyone looking to join should grab their wallets and run as fast as they can in another direction. i do not see this situation getting any better in the near future. Four years ago I was so jung ho and now I can barely say the name without becoming very angry. WAKE UP FED EX WE ARE THE PEOPLE THAT WILL MAKE YOU OR BREAK YOU.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>68</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[tired and pissed]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>vdbarber@juno.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.136.26.225</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 23:50:47</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been a FedEx Home Delivery contractor for over four years.At one time my family owned four routes in two states. We are now down to two and will soon be down to zero. I can't believe how poorly the contractors are treated compared to four years ago and how little the pay has increased. Anyone looking to join should grab their wallets and run as fast as they can in another direction. i do not see this situation getting any better in the near future. Four years ago I was so jung ho and now I can barely say the name without becoming very angry. WAKE UP FED EX WE ARE THE PEOPLE THAT WILL MAKE YOU OR BREAK YOU.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>69</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[tired and pissed]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>vdbarber@juno.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.136.26.225</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-11 23:51:40</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been a FedEx Home Delivery contractor for over four years.At one time my family owned four routes in two states. We are now down to two and will soon be down to zero. I can't believe how poorly the contractors are treated compared to four years ago and how little the pay has increased. Anyone looking to join should grab their wallets and run as fast as they can in another direction. i do not see this situation getting any better in the near future. Four years ago I was so jung ho and now I can barely say the name without becoming very angry. WAKE UP FED EX WE ARE THE PEOPLE THAT WILL MAKE YOU OR BREAK YOU.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>70</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.190.72.247</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-12 06:58:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I also agree with "tired and pissed". Fedex Contractors or potential contractors should look on the web for Fedex buissness practices and how they treat employees. Check google for Fedex+RLA (Railway Labor Act). They are very hostile towards employees and labor movement, so you can imagine how they treat the Contractors! The fedex name makes me mad just seeing it. They are trying to set employees back to the early 1900's. Check the web for how Fedex uses all its resources to lobbby for what it wants, and how it can screw its employees. Fedex Sucks. Fedex Home Delivery sucks. Do not become a contractor with them. I want to get rid of my route and find anohter job! You should see the looks I get when I go to the UPS store or the Post office and ship my personal packages. People ask "dont you get a discount for shipping with Fedex"? I say " yea, but I dont trust them with my box so I ship Post office first, UPS second, Fedex....never." They get a look of shock till I tell them Im a contractor and dont give a s*hit what I say about fedex. Yea its shooting myself in the foot cause that person may not ship with fedex and It may cause us to loose buissnes, but its that bad.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>71</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Erik]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>noneofurbusiness@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-12 14:44:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[im 12 years old and i orderd 2 small little ******* games and ive been waiting for weeks!!it said one to 2 days !!!!! how long does it take to drive to a ******** house and put a ****** video game on a doorstep?! i can ******* do that]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>72</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Erik]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>noneofurbusiness@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-12 14:44:38</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[im 12 years old and i orderd 2 small little ******* games and ive been waiting for weeks!!it said one to 2 days !!!!! how long does it take to drive to a ******** house and put a ****** video game on a doorstep?! i can ******* do that]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>73</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Erik]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>noneofurbusiness@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-12 14:45:18</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[im 12 years old and i orderd 2 small little ******* games and ive been waiting for weeks!!it said one to 2 days !!!!! how long does it take to drive to a ******** house and put a ****** video game on a doorstep?! i can ******* do that]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>74</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[evil twin]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Fedex@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>165.121.211.204</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-13 13:46:36</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[All you Fedex Ground/Home Delivery wimps!  Why don't you quit complaining and get a new job.  Why don't you apply to FedEx Express where you don't have to buy your truck,uniforms,etc.. and Fred Smith even gives you a decent Health coverage. I work for FedEx Exp.  Every day we don't have enough Drivers to cover our stations area but that equiates to $$$OVERTIME!
HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHHAHAHA]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>75</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Bite me]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>suckmedry@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-15 03:14:24</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To the above posting....evil twin. Enjoy it while you can. Your still a cardboard delivering fool probably with the iq of a shelled walnut. As you can see by the above statements the Fed Ex contractors are doing just that..getting a new job. It's not complaining it's just stating the facts. You can suck Fred Smith off dry.....hope you still have a job in a few years when your alot older and less productive. You won't be singing their praises then.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>76</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[all true]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>alltrue@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>151.197.202.36</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-15 17:18:05</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Being a contractor for Fedex: biggest mistake I ever did. Everything I've read here is true.
F Fedex Home Delivery.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>77</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[ScrewedInMA]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>nonoe@none.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.96.247.120</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-20 09:18:02</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Well, I have been screwed by Fedex. I ordered an item off of ebay. The item was sent via fedex ground. The day it was supposed to be delivered, I noticed it wasn't at my house....? I checked the tracking number and it said it was delivered at 9:55AM. So, they must have delivered it to some other house.
So - I call them that night. They tell me I will be contected in 24 hours. So 24 hours later, I hear nothing and call again. They said, oh wait, it could take 48 hours. So I wait another 24 and call again. Then they said, ohhh, well why don't you call back in 4 days....!!!!! So its been 4 days and I called back today. They said it appears as if the local fedex in Hartford CT has done nothing. So they setup a Tracker who is supposed to call me. But they did however mention it will take the tracker 48 hours minimum and don;t be surprised if it takes longer. So, for 1 1/2 weeks my package has been sitting somewhere. Maybe someone had it delivered to their house and they decided not to find me. Either way, Fedex has screwed me. They said I can't do anything about this and its too bad for me. Thanks Fedex, go to hell.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>78</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Terri]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>jodilab@bright.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>65.238.61.225</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-20 16:37:17</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[In case you didn't already figure it out - FedEx Home Delivery utilizes Independant Contractors.  You can't blame the entire FedEx workforce because of one person's mistake.  Maybe he couldn't hear anyone was home because of all the barking.  I have 3 dogs and they LOVE my FedEx man.  As a matter of fact all the dogs on his route love him - he always has plenty of bisquits.  I think he is wonderful and always does his best to deliver EVERY package EVERY day.  He has several awards from FedEx to prove this.  So they are NOT ALL BAD!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>79</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FED EX HIRE CAMEL JOCKEYS]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fedexsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-20 18:01:05</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Fed ex ground and home delivery do use independent contractors. They are treated like slave labor with good credit in order to purchase the truck. They pay all of their expenses, maintenance, gas etc along with any claims from stolen packages or douche bags saying they are stolen. In return for this they earn about 1.14 a stop and .22 a package. Until fedex wakes up and pays contractors like they should there will be a tremendous turnaround and an attitude of fuck it.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>80</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[gary]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ne1uo@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.96.77.226</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-29 16:34:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[My buddy, "Big Mark Fortezzo" drives for FedEx. here in So. Cal.  He laughs as he tells us how FedEx folks toss our boxes around (unless the boss is walking thru) ... and the chuckle it brings when the sound of breakage is evident.  I'm in the middle of a "return-from-hell" with FedEx right now.  The FedEx URL shows their truck picked up our box for return at 4:32am (right!) when in fact they didn't pick up 'till nearly noon.  Then our box was magically zoomed back to rural KS by the next day ... just 18 hours, 3/4 of the way, across the USA ... ground deliver (right!)  Skumbags.  The only thing more pathetic are the folks above, wanting to rationalize for FedEx ... "oh, gee, maybe the driver was having a bad day".  You've got to be kidding.
Anywho ~ the last FedEx dirtbag who came by left our box, even though it had a gaping hole ... the broken / cracked contents hanging out the hole.  The wife yells at the driver, "hey don't leave this here all broken!"  The driver acts like he doesn't hear ... jumps in the truck &amp; zooms off.  Gee, maybe he was having a bad day ... maybe that's why he was laughing.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>81</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.136.199</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-30 09:04:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[One needs to look at the above comments by "gary" and ask whether it is a FedEx Express Driver, A fedex Ground driver or a Fedex home delivery driver.  I work for fedex home delivery and have NO PROBLEMS what so ever delivering a damaged or abused box to a customer. When they look at the box and ask what the hell happened to it I just say I am an independent contractor and the way the person sees the box right then is how I received the box that morning at the terminal from the fedex managers.

Let me give everyone some good advice. (Customers that is) Listen well. 99.9% of the time that box that you have has been damaged by the cross country trip or the automated loading systems. The driver again 99.9% of the time has nothing to do with how it was damaged. Yelling, abusing, degrading the driver will do ABSOLUTLY nothing to remedy the situation. It just means the driver will prob MAKE sure your next pacage IS damaged or comes up missing or will provide sh*ty customer service. So who is to blame?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>82</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.69.136.199</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-04-30 09:04:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[One needs to look at the above comments by "gary" and ask whether it is a FedEx Express Driver, A fedex Ground driver or a Fedex home delivery driver.  I work for fedex home delivery and have NO PROBLEMS what so ever delivering a damaged or abused box to a customer. When they look at the box and ask what the hell happened to it I just say I am an independent contractor and the way the person sees the box right then is how I received the box that morning at the terminal from the fedex managers.

Let me give everyone some good advice. (Customers that is) Listen well. 99.9% of the time that box that you have has been damaged by the cross country trip or the automated loading systems. The driver again 99.9% of the time has nothing to do with how it was damaged. Yelling, abusing, degrading the driver will do ABSOLUTLY nothing to remedy the situation. It just means the driver will prob MAKE sure your next pacage IS damaged or comes up missing or will provide sh*ty customer service. So who is to blame? Easy! Fedex managers and the head cheese at the regional offices. Call and ALWAYS ask to speak to a manager. Get his name first, then if you are pissed off start yelling. But make sure you get his/her name and who they work for (i.e. Home, Ground, Express, Custom Critical, Etc.). Then lay into them. Read next post.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>83</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[K-dog]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kb32c@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.159.130.114</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-05-05 23:43:01</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Wow, now I know not to attend the fedex independent contractor job fair i saw in the paper. This sounds even worse than my current job! Thanks guys!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>84</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Keeping it real]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.41.102.13</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-05-06 14:36:04</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[K-Dog...best decision you could have ever made. Even in a down economy fed fuck is having a hard time filling their positions. All it takes is a couple of former contractors spreading the word. Run very fast and very far away from Fed-Ex...unless you like long hours, shitty compensation and no benefits.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>85</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fedexhasnoscruples]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ebbtide196@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-05-10 05:07:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Well got my last settlement check. Walked out at the end of March with no notice. So of course they automatically keep the 500 they make you pay into an escrow account for that very same reason. Got deductions for my uniforms ($70) I didn't return (who cares at this point) and $109 for some claim I have no idea about!?!?!?! FedEx can't even settle without trying to screw you out of some more money. What a shitty ass company. I hope Fred Smith and quite frankly any Home Delivery terminal managers acquire some type of cancer and fucking die. They'll get theirs in the end those bunch of worthless, lying, douche-bag pukes.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>86</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Jon Hoffman]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mailhoffmanDERAZETHISFORSPAM@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.116.68.239</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-05-11 16:45:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Fedex Home has done the same thing multiple times to me. I really wonder why they do this. I work at home. I get UPS/Fedex overnight/Fedex Home (documents, boxes, equipment) an average of 3 times a week for five years. The only time something was late with UPS was when it snowed or a train derailed. Never had a problem with a delivery attempt.

Fedex Home/Ground consistently mis-routes the shipments and claims delivery attempted when it wasn't. It's mystifying as to how this helps them, the shipper, or the customer. Maybe the driver is on a UPS-like bonus and gets it just for claiming s/he stopped? Fyi, I have an x10 camera and motion detector on my porch that have never lied, can't say the same for Fedex.

I love the Fedex site, they "commit" to a delivery time but they don't guarantee anything. I've had to stop buying from absolutely fabulous vendors when they won't ship any other way but Fedex. Newegg.com is an example. In the past year I've  moved $25k in revenue away from them (and therefore some revenue away from Fedex).

This latest adventure is a package that shipped from San Diego 5/4 from Overstock.com. Like a fool I went with the Fedex service because it was promotional at $2.95. It needed to go to Upland, which is roughly 100 miles (a 2 hour drive max). On the 5th, it was in Los Angeles (this is further from San Diego than Upland, but's a hub so it makes sense). On the 6th it went to Portland, OR. Yes, Portland, OR! On the 10th its back in LA. On the 11th, it's out for delivery but here I sit 8 hours later and still no package.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>87</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[ThankYou]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>name@website.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>167.127.24.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-05-14 09:02:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks to all FedEx Home Delivery contractors who shared their experience. Im glad I found this information before my husband fall into this sh*t!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>88</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[superkevx]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>superkevx@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.169.42.109</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-11 11:01:10</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[im using express saver. I have only used this about twice. First time i ordered from Newegg.com about 1400$ worth of comp parts. most of it got here in CA in 2 days since and the other parts were from ohio which got here in 3 days. i was pretty happy with the speed. But jus a few days ago i ordered from newegg again with exp. saver. and newegg split it into two packages. both of them were on the same route and scedule until one of them got put on a truck while the other one was "not due for delivery" I didnt understand, it was two packages going to the same address yet they decided to deliver one today and one tomorrow. man i was pissed. i really dont want to use fedex again but i dont want to penalize newegg because of something fedex did.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>89</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.190.72.75</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-14 06:33:23</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The above (by superkevx) prob has to do with one going to Home Delivery and the other maybe going to Ground. This happens all the time. Its a way to spread the wealth to the different companies under fedex. Order two items from a company going to the same address and one may get delivered by Home Delivery and the other by Ground. Why? Just like I said. It helps keep the numbers up for both divisions. Also Ground works MONDAY - Friday and Home delivery TUE - SAT.  SO you could get one box on Sat and the other next tue. Its a mess and fedex doesent know what ist doing.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>90</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[brendan501932]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mixmastaheavyb@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>167.1.120.20</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-16 11:20:58</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[k i work for fedex, and whoever posted this is a retarded moron..we are forced to listen to your perspective and your interrputation of the situation which sounds like its a crock of shit..before you ship ANYTHING, you are instructed to read the service guide..this clearly explains all of our policies and regulations..if something is being shipped to you, call the shipper ans get you r facts straight, before i have to take your call and prove your retarded]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>91</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Steve]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kas@earthlink.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.248.121.64</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-16 16:11:47</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[¶ It's true -- FedEx Home Delivery systematically pretends to make delivery attempts, but really, they only look to see if you're waiting outside for them.

 ¶ After Christmas of 2003, a DVD/VCR machine was shipped from Idaho to my home in Portland, Oregon. Unfortunately, the staff at Mailboxes, Etc shipped it 'FedEx Home Delivery' though my
family requested that it be shipped UPS.

 ¶ I live in an apartment with 2 phone lines, one connected to the front door intercom. Both lines have CallerID, and both lines have a messaging service. There is also a large note by the intercom for delivery drivers, in case they don't know how to use this intercom.

 ¶ The first delivery attempt was a genuine attempt -- my CallerID proved it. I then waited all day at home the next day, and the next day....

 ¶ At the end of the 2nd &amp; 3rd days, I found a slip on the front door stating that I wasn't home. I complained on the telephone to FedEx, stating that I have CallerID and I KNOW the driver did not even try to deliver the package. I persuaded them to do a 4th delivery attempt (since there was no place I could go to pick it up).

 ¶ On the 4th day, I was sitting outside when the driver appeared. He acted very friendly &amp; happy that he "finally found me at home". I asked if he was the same driver who came on the previous days. He said all but the first day (the only real delivery attempt).

 ¶ Then I asked how he tried to contact me. He said he called, of course. I said I have CallerID, 2 lines, and no calls from the door were recorded.

 ¶ He said: "Oh yeah, I did run into a neighbor who let me in the door, so I just knocked on your apartment." I said that I didn't hear him knock, so I asked him to show me which apt he knocked on, then he became defensive and said he didn't have time to show me (my apt is very close to the front door). I finally asked if he could just explain why he tagged to apt complex door and not my apt door.

 ¶ Finally, he ran out of lies and became defensive, though I had been calm until that point. I too finally became angry and accused him of lying to me. He yelled that I would "never get a package again from him" (as if he were a little kid on a playground refusing to share his toy). Of course, I just ask my family to use UPS now.

 ¶ By the way, the box I received was completely rippled with water damage. It had been raining the previous days, though I have no idea why it would have been left in the rain. (This is Portland Oregon, so surely their loading docks are covered!)

 ¶ Anyway, FedEx Home Delivery DOES SUCK! But it has nothing to do with any companies they buy. The workers just know that FedEx really just cares about business customers. A large company office or warehouse would never be treated like I was treated -- the Home Delivery workers know that they can just drop-off notes when they want to speed through their day ...no important customers will complain.

 ¶ Steve]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>92</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Yeah Yeah]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fedexsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.41.102.181</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-16 18:05:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To above person. Steve having been a Fed Ex Home Delivery driver I can relate to the driver you are complaining about. For what we as independent contractors are getting paid it's not worth our time or effort to ring your intercom. He's probably burning more gas than he's making delivering your package. I used to just do the easy deliveries, it wasn't monetarily worth it to goto apts, multi-family homes etc. Not to mention the fact that alot of the customers are dishonet douche bags....ones that actually get their package then put claims in thinking their screwing Fed Ex when the independent contractor actually pays for these claims. Many people in my terminal just take shit home rather than deliver it, cause they know they run the strong possibility of paying for it anyways.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>93</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[not alone]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>zurn06@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-16 21:03:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[being A contractor with Home,I was saddened to hear about and read these neg comments,HOWEVER I felt much better after doing an online search and finding that UPS had just has many if not more wed sites with neg comments about there service!! However one comlaint is to many! I think There is a saying that when a person has a neg experience they will tell at least 5 people about it, while someone with a positive experience will tell noone. being guilty of some of these things I will have visions of this site dancing around my head if the though ever comes again Thanks for the eye opener*** but I would have got the point with out the foul fingers]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>94</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[not alone]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>zurn06@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-16 21:06:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[being A contractor with Home,I was saddened to hear about and read these neg comments,HOWEVER I felt much better after doing an online search and finding that UPS had just has many if not more wed sites with neg comments about there service!! However one comlaint is to many! I think There is a saying that when a person has a neg experience they will tell at least 5 people about it, while someone with a positive experience will tell noone. being guilty of some of these things I will have visions of this site dancing around my head if the though ever comes again, Thanks for the eye opener*** but I would have got the point with out the foul fingers]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>95</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Info Needed]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>aim805@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>208.209.61.3</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-17 08:01:18</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I am interested in becoming a FedEx Home Delivery Contractor.  Is there anyone who can give me the pros and cons they have had so far with being a contractor for FedEx.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>96</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Chris]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>chris@dreamix.tv</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.64.232.216</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-18 01:51:27</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ill post my positive :) Its actually the reverse of what everyone is reporting here. I used to live in Southern Indiana, and UPS has its main hub in Louisville, KY - 20-30 miles from me. I got packages faster from FedEX and cheaper. My experiences with UPS have always been bad. its very  weird. Usually UPS is delivering packages to me at 8:30pm and FedEX was always 12:30pm all the time and consisent. Never a complaint. I even told everyone about my experiences and recommended them doing business with them as well, no complaint. I moved near Lexington, KY - it seems UPS has very little movement around here and since its closer to Memphis, TN (FedEXs main hub in this region) my packages as before, I recieve same service. Packages always here on time, earlier and at 1:30pm in afternoon. So I think like anything it depends on service (Ground is slower i know than express but even like UPS, it sits in the warehouse and never moves until 1-2 day before delivery required). UPS  2 day is alot better service, but ground is terrible as I have many bad attempts with UPS even here. I do all my business with FedEX because of this reason. So I really believe the region i am in right now seems to have their act together when it comes to the UPS vs FedEX war. Ive read everyones comments :) I do believe your all right, FedEX with the Home Delivery practices are very shitty! Thats just sad they would do that, but like corporate america, they all want that extra buck.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>97</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Chris]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>c-h-r-i-s-@d-r-e-a-m-ix.t-v-REMOVE</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.64.232.216</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-18 01:52:13</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ill post my positive :) Its actually the reverse of what everyone is reporting here. I used to live in Southern Indiana, and UPS has its main hub in Louisville, KY - 20-30 miles from me. I got packages faster from FedEX and cheaper. My experiences with UPS have always been bad. its very  weird. Usually UPS is delivering packages to me at 8:30pm and FedEX was always 12:30pm all the time and consisent. Never a complaint. I even told everyone about my experiences and recommended them doing business with them as well, no complaint. I moved near Lexington, KY - it seems UPS has very little movement around here and since its closer to Memphis, TN (FedEXs main hub in this region) my packages as before, I recieve same service. Packages always here on time, earlier and at 1:30pm in afternoon. So I think like anything it depends on service (Ground is slower i know than express but even like UPS, it sits in the warehouse and never moves until 1-2 day before delivery required). UPS  2 day is alot better service, but ground is terrible as I have many bad attempts with UPS even here. I do all my business with FedEX because of this reason. So I really believe the region i am in right now seems to have their act together when it comes to the UPS vs FedEX war. Ive read everyones comments :) I do believe your all right, FedEX with the Home Delivery practices are very shitty! Thats just sad they would do that, but like corporate america, they all want that extra buck.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>98</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Leo Perez]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>Bucsfan9889@Hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>4.247.206.181</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-19 18:24:14</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've read all the negative comments from both customers and former contractors I would like to put my two cents in. As far as you customers go the contractors don't get paid unless the package has been delivered so it doesn't make sense for them not to do everything they can to get that package delivered. I'm sure there are bad contractors as there are bad employees at UPS and every other company. For you former contractors complaining. I can see that most you can't even spell so I doubt you asked the right questions and did the right research that should be done before anybody goes into any business venture. I am currently finishing my training and will soon get a route. I interviewed quite a few contractors at 2 different terminals. I went on several rides without pay to see what the work was actually like. I completely understand the compensation and the work involved and I can't wait to get started. So go back to your office put in your 50-60 hrs a week go home sit on your couch and drink your beer and cry to your fat wife about how much you hate your cubicle.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>99</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FED EX HIRE CAMEL JOCKEYS]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>anothersuckerhired@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-22 04:01:41</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To the above Leo the lion....You go for it girl...you don't think you'll be working in excess of 60 hours a week at FedEx? Wait till your bringing home 500 a week after expenses and your shitbox truck breaks down. Yep like anything else new you'll like it for about 2 weeks...I pretty much took the job on account of being out of work...but I unlike yourself are intelligent enough to know that it's a losing propostion...hence why I left as soon as I got a real job. Hurry up Leo, it's 7 PM and you've got 15 more stops to go...one a signature..cubicles rule FedEx and Fred Smith and yourself my dear chap suck donkey balls]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>100</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TrexDee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>63.190.64.186</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-23 13:11:26</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[No need to get vulguar. But Camel Jockey is right. I went from a decent day 75-80 stops, off by 3pm. Now its hard to get off by 5pm and that is all day NO BREAKS, NO LUNCH. STraight work from 7:30am till 5pm. That amounts to 9 1/2 hours everyday, 5 days a week. Do the math. That is 47 1/2 hours a week. Most people who work 50 or 60 hours a week get lunch and are not breaking their backs hauling a TV to a third floor apartment in the winter or hot summer. And take into consideration that that 50 0r 60 hours worked includes down time, coffe breaks, talking to other employees. Plus the big thing is you never learn anything new. Same old thing. Unless you also go to school at night, your brain will feel usless after 2-3 years at that. (unless you want a no name chalengless job where you dont have to think). I mastered my route in less than two years and could do it blind folded. If they switced me to a different route, it would be ok for about 6 months then i would master it. This job is boring, and it will come to u also.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>101</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[CCR]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>royalfusilierccompany@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.195.235.221</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-25 07:28:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Troy coul'nt be more right.
Last saturday, I ordered a set of wheels for my car (Not ghetto wheels).  First they were going to be here thursday, then Friday, and finally saturday.  Then I get an E-mail from the shipper saying two of the packages were lost.  HOW DO YOU LOSE A 30-POUND #$%*ing RIM?  2 of them nonetheless?  It just baffles me how careless a company can be with such expensive packages.  Now I'm getting 2 wheels tommorow, two wheels next Monday (Yeah, right)]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>102</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fed ex die!]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fredsmithsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-29 02:49:51</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To Trexdee above,

You sound like you have a clue about the whole contractor thing. Why are you still doing it? Get a real job/career and get out of a losing proposition.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>103</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fed ex die!]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fredsmithsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-29 02:49:58</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To Trexdee above,

You sound like you have a clue about the whole contractor thing. Why are you still doing it? Get a real job/career and get out of a losing proposition.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>104</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fed ex die!]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fredsmithsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-06-29 02:50:03</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To Trexdee above,

You sound like you have a clue about the whole contractor thing. Why are you still doing it? Get a real job/career and get out of a losing proposition.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>105</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fedex ghetto]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ghetto@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.194.7.68</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-09 10:12:07</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[on a side note, i have lots of problems with not only with fedex home delivery but also their express crap.  i was supposed to get a priority overnight package, which somehow stretched to 2 days, which truly infuriated me.  which doesn't make ANY sense, because i live in NYC, which isn't like some bumblefuck rural route.  they also never rang my bell, so i have to wait over the weekend for the stupid package...

i really wish everyone would switch over to UPS.  i can complain about UPS air deliveries, cause they seem to never come in the mornings, ever...  But I've found my UPS guy to be pretty reliable, and seems to always come at the same time, around 6-7pm, which means I'm always home to get my deliveries....

fedex, meanwhile, loves to come somewhere between 11am to 4:30pm...  what steams me is when i have a pickup, they always seem to torture me, making me wait till 4:29pm, at the very last minute to pick up my packages.  truly aggravating....

and another note, there used to be some contractors around my hood.  i think they got fired, cause i used to see these 2 fedex home delivery dudes "drag" racing their trucks down the streets all the time.  i don't wanna know what happened to their packages.  prob the same shite, all trashed before they get there.

well, now that i've got that off my chest, i'm very satisfied to see solidarity amongst so many ppl who hate fedex.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>106</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FedEx Hell]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>groovin@iname.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.67.211.150</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-10 11:37:59</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I read these problem and right now I'm in the middle of a Fed Ex Home Delivery problem...

I live in a more rural area...UPS, DHL, and everyone else finds us and when they don't they call...

I was to receive a package yesterday (Friday)...I waited at home all day doing odd jobs around the house...no one came...kept checking the progress of my shipment until 8PM...said it was still out for delivery...THE NEXT MORNING (today) I check and lo and behold it says it was "delivered" to my "backdoor" at 5:47PM...the problem is that I don't have a back door AND I was home all day...no delivery...

Called the central number this morning...I was told that the Hagerstown, MD hub is closed today...ok...then found out it wasn't...called Hagerstown and I'm waiting for a call back...but given what I've been reading I'm not expecting anything and I'm feeling like a claim will be contested because it said it was delivered...

This whole "free-lance" style delivery system is fishy and opens up holes for a lot of bad service OR outright fraud.  What if the homeowner states that signature service is not required and the delivery person (who gets paid for deliveries) decides to just leave it anywhere OR keeps it and claims delivery?  Sorry, there just doesn't seem to be any accountability in the Fed Ex Home Delivery system at all.

I'll keep everyone posted but I guarantee that if I order something from a company I'm checking to see whether it's Fed Ex or not - if it is - I'm asking for a different shipper OR not buying the product...you're choice of a delivery system is an extension of your business.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>107</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Fed Ex Hell]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>groovin@iname.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.67.211.150</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-10 13:27:32</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[OK...GET THIS...

I CALLED THE CENTRAL FED EX NUMBER AGAIN THREE HOURS LATER AFTER NOT HEARING FROM FED EX WHEN TOLD I WAS GOING TO BE CALLED...RIPPED THE CLAIMS OFFICER AND HE IN TURN CALLED THE HAGERSTOWN, MD TERMINAL AND MUST HAVE RIPPED THE PERSON IN CHARGE ON THE OTHER END...

SUDDENLY I GOT ALL KINDS OF "COOPERATION"...BUT WAIT...IT GETS BETTER...

THE MAN AT THE TERMINAL CALLED THE "CONTRACTOR" AT HOME AND SHE TOLD HIM THAT SHE BECAME CONFUSED...WHAT DID SHE DO?...DID SHE CALL THE HOUSE?...DID SHE MATCH UP ADDRESSES?...NOOOO....

SHE DELIVERED IT TO THE NEAREST HOUSE SHE COULD FIND JUST TO DELIVER IT!!! NOT OUR HOUSE!  ABSOLUTELY RIDICULOUS...

SO, THE MAN ON THE PHONE ASKED IF I COULD GET THE PACKAGE (THAT'S RIGHT - I HAD TO GET IT)...BECAUSE HE HAD NO DRIVERS IN THE AREA...SO...IT GETS BETTER!!....

I DRIVE DOWN TO THE HORSE FARM TO SEE IF THE PACKAGE IS THERE...IT'S NOT EVEN A HOUSE...IT'S A CABIN THAT THEY USE ON THE HORSE FARM SO THEY DON'T CHECK FOR PACKAGES...

WE WENT OUT ON THE DECK AND LO AND BEHOLD WHAT DO WE SEE?...THAT'S RIGHT...WE SEE THE PACKAGE...BUT WAIT...NOT JUST ONE PACKAGE BUT TWO!!!!  NO TELLING HOW LONG THE OTHER WAS SITTING THERE!

WELL, TO MAKE A LONG STORY SHORT I CALLED BACK THE MAN AT THE TERMINAL WHO APOLOGIZED PROFUSELY AND THEN CONTACTED THE SELLER TO LET THEM KNOW...THEY WEREN'T HAPPY...

CHEAPER IS NOT ALWAYS BETTER FOLKS!!!

THAT'S MY TWO CENTS!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>108</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Dave]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>atomicmac@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>209.209.248.9</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-20 10:24:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[My sad story.  I ordered fiberglass saddlebags for my motorcycle, the box was huge, about 3 feet square.  I bought them on ebay and the guy shipped Fedex.  The box got lost in the middle of trasit somewhere and it took me a full month to get my money back.  I was told by Fedex that I should contact the seller and have them send out another one.  Well, unfortunately ebay is not always filled with manufacturers selling products.  I bought them from a private seller.  Then Fedex told me that I had to prove how much I paid for the item, even though the package was insured.  As far as I'm concerned, if I send a box of cleanex and I pay insurance on it for $1000 then you owe me a grand if you loose the package.  The next set of saddlebags I bought I insisted the seller use UPS.

Next sad story.  I have been buying stuff from a very good online retailer, and I have spent a fair amount of money with them...  Maybe 5 grand.  The first delivery, my wife was home all day, with the back door open and the Fedex guy didn't even knock on the door.  The delivery was delayed for two days.  The second delivery was ontime and the guy actually carried the box inside for my wife.  This one went well.  The last delivery I was home and the guy just left the door tag with a sticker, nothing else.  So I signed the tag and left it for today.  Then I check tracking and they say I wasn't home.  No shit.  That's why I left the tag.  When I called customer service, they told me that they can't accept the tag signature.  I compained that there is a section on the tag to check off if that is the case and it wasn't filled out.  Now I have to drive a half hour to pick up the package myself.

I am not going to do business with this retailer any more unless they will send me stuff by UPS.  Fedex doesn't care and doesn't try.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>109</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Dave]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>atomicmac@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>209.209.248.9</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-20 10:24:32</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[My sad story.  I ordered fiberglass saddlebags for my motorcycle, the box was huge, about 3 feet square.  I bought them on ebay and the guy shipped Fedex.  The box got lost in the middle of trasit somewhere and it took me a full month to get my money back.  I was told by Fedex that I should contact the seller and have them send out another one.  Well, unfortunately ebay is not always filled with manufacturers selling products.  I bought them from a private seller.  Then Fedex told me that I had to prove how much I paid for the item, even though the package was insured.  As far as I'm concerned, if I send a box of cleanex and I pay insurance on it for $1000 then you owe me a grand if you loose the package.  The next set of saddlebags I bought I insisted the seller use UPS.

Next sad story.  I have been buying stuff from a very good online retailer, and I have spent a fair amount of money with them...  Maybe 5 grand.  The first delivery, my wife was home all day, with the back door open and the Fedex guy didn't even knock on the door.  The delivery was delayed for two days.  The second delivery was ontime and the guy actually carried the box inside for my wife.  This one went well.  The last delivery I was home and the guy just left the door tag with a sticker, nothing else.  So I signed the tag and left it for today.  Then I check tracking and they say I wasn't home.  No shit.  That's why I left the tag.  When I called customer service, they told me that they can't accept the tag signature.  I compained that there is a section on the tag to check off if that is the case and it wasn't filled out.  Now I have to drive a half hour to pick up the package myself.

I am not going to do business with this retailer any more unless they will send me stuff by UPS.  Fedex doesn't care and doesn't try.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>110</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[The Wife]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>shari9999@sbcglobal.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.252.39.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-26 20:13:47</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Dear Leo Perez:
I'm the wife of a dedicated FedEx contractor who puts in 40 - 60 hours a week trying to make a paycheck from FedEx Home Delivery.  He delivers 99.9% of his packages every week, but still can't make ends meet because FedEx Home Delivery sucks every penny they can out of his paycheck one way or another.

Let me offer you some words of wisdom.  We thought we did all the research too; my husband rode on a route for several weeks, investigated the compensation plan, did the math, talked to drivers, thought he had it all covered, but that still wasn't enough.  He read the contract over and over and it seemed to cover all the bases.  In fact, it covered so many bases, they didn't leave a stone unturned.  Those FedEx lawyers made that contract read so well, everything is to their advantage.  They can change or alter anything they want, anytime they want.  It's all up to interpretation...theirs.

My husband was just ecstatic when FedEx made him buy a truck for $30K.  It turned out to be such a  worthless piece of dog shit and so far this year, it has been in the shop more than it's been on the road.  Of course, that wouldn't be because the truck isn't heavy duty enough to handle the job or anything!!  Oh no.  FedEx spec'd the truck in and said it would be perfect for this type of work.  The funny part is, they're certainly not offering to pay any of the $1,000.00 a month we're spending on repairs!!  Neither is Chevy. I could go on and on and on about that story.  But wait...it gets better.  Between the claims, repairs, gas prices, taxes, insurance, uniforms, truck payments and all other associated expenses, last year my husband made about as much money as a gas station attendant.  Our accountant thinks we've lost our minds.  But I'm sure you'll be able to put aside a good 10% of your pay so you have a retirement account someday.  I'm sure FedEx will gladly match .50 cents on the dollar too.  I hear the contractor pension is awesome.  Why don't you research THAT?

Does the Core Zone they're offering you look good today?  Well, mentally, try to hold onto that picture because soon, you can kiss it goodbye. Eventually, the core zone will disappear and then they'll change your route around on you so that your daily miles will go from 110 miles per day to about 230 and your stops will decrease by 20%. But I forgot...you completely understand how FedEx works so this is old news to you.

I'm sure you're also aware that contractors CAN get medical insurance if they pay astronomical premiums too.  Or, they can hope that their spouse has really good insurance that covers chiropractic or medical care when they hurt their back... which probably happened when they were carrying that 120 lb. package up someone's icy staircase, which of course the owner's didn't bother to shovel or sand, they lost their balance, slipped, fell down the stairs and landed on their ass in the snow.  After digging around to find their glasses and scanner which had sunk a foot below the snow, they went back on their merry way delivering packages in 20 below weather hoping they didn't catch pneumonia because their clothes were soaking wet. I'm sure they also had a "back-up" driver on stand-by just waiting for a phone call telling them that they had work this week because they were bed-ridden and couldn't make it in.  You know...you'll have those days when you're in the bathroom with a stomach bug so bad you wish you could rip your guts out...but you know you're tied to that FedEx contract,... and you know "the deliveries must get done".  So you shake it off, take some Pepto and hope and pray to God you're near a McDonald's in a hour when Montezuma's revenge hits again.  Yeah, my husband thinks it's great to be a contractor.

Trust me, in 6 months, you're going to be wishing you had a cubicle to go back to. While you're at it, why don't you get a supplemental driver for the holidays too??  That way you can put a second truck on and make some really GOOD money.  I'm sure you've figured out how much extra money you can make on an additional driver and an additional route.....until that additional driver just doesn't show up for work one day because you're not paying him nearly enough, you can't find a replacement driver and you're stuck paying 2 truck payments, can't afford the insurance, have no savings account, they foreclose on your house, your wife leaves your sorry ass because you're broke and your kids have to go on welfare.  Good luck with FedEx.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>111</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[The Wife]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>shari9999@sbcglobal.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.252.39.25</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-07-26 20:13:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Dear Leo Perez:
I'm the wife of a dedicated FedEx contractor who puts in 40 - 60 hours a week trying to make a paycheck from FedEx Home Delivery.  He delivers 99.9% of his packages every week, but still can't make ends meet because FedEx Home Delivery sucks every penny they can out of his paycheck one way or another.

Let me offer you some words of wisdom.  We thought we did all the research too; my husband rode on a route for several weeks, investigated the compensation plan, did the math, talked to drivers, thought he had it all covered, but that still wasn't enough.  He read the contract over and over and it seemed to cover all the bases.  In fact, it covered so many bases, they didn't leave a stone unturned.  Those FedEx lawyers made that contract read so well, everything is to their advantage.  They can change or alter anything they want, anytime they want.  It's all up to interpretation...theirs.

My husband was just ecstatic when FedEx made him buy a truck for $30K.  It turned out to be such a  worthless piece of dog shit and so far this year, it has been in the shop more than it's been on the road.  Of course, that wouldn't be because the truck isn't heavy duty enough to handle the job or anything!!  Oh no.  FedEx spec'd the truck in and said it would be perfect for this type of work.  The funny part is, they're certainly not offering to pay any of the $1,000.00 a month we're spending on repairs!!  Neither is Chevy. I could go on and on and on about that story.  But wait...it gets better.  Between the claims, repairs, gas prices, taxes, insurance, uniforms, truck payments and all other associated expenses, last year my husband made about as much money as a gas station attendant.  Our accountant thinks we've lost our minds.  But I'm sure you'll be able to put aside a good 10% of your pay so you have a retirement account someday.  I'm sure FedEx will gladly match .50 cents on the dollar too.  I hear the contractor pension is awesome.  Why don't you research THAT?

Does the Core Zone they're offering you look good today?  Well, mentally, try to hold onto that picture because soon, you can kiss it goodbye. Eventually, the core zone will disappear and then they'll change your route around on you so that your daily miles will go from 110 miles per day to about 230 and your stops will decrease by 20%. But I forgot...you completely understand how FedEx works so this is old news to you.

I'm sure you're also aware that contractors CAN get medical insurance if they pay astronomical premiums too.  Or, they can hope that their spouse has really good insurance that covers chiropractic or medical care when they hurt their back... which probably happened when they were carrying that 120 lb. package up someone's icy staircase, which of course the owner's didn't bother to shovel or sand, they lost their balance, slipped, fell down the stairs and landed on their ass in the snow.  After digging around to find their glasses and scanner which had sunk a foot below the snow, they went back on their merry way delivering packages in 20 below weather hoping they didn't catch pneumonia because their clothes were soaking wet. I'm sure they also had a "back-up" driver on stand-by just waiting for a phone call telling them that they had work this week because they were bed-ridden and couldn't make it in.  You know...you'll have those days when you're in the bathroom with a stomach bug so bad you wish you could rip your guts out...but you know you're tied to that FedEx contract,... and you know "the deliveries must get done".  So you shake it off, take some Pepto and hope and pray to God you're near a McDonald's in a hour when Montezuma's revenge hits again.  Yeah, my husband thinks it's great to be a contractor.

Trust me, in 6 months, you're going to be wishing you had a cubicle to go back to. While you're at it, why don't you get a supplemental driver for the holidays too??  That way you can put a second truck on and make some really GOOD money.  I'm sure you've figured out how much extra money you can make on an additional driver and an additional route.....until that additional driver just doesn't show up for work one day because you're not paying him nearly enough, you can't find a replacement driver and you're stuck paying 2 truck payments, can't afford the insurance, have no savings account, they foreclose on your house, your wife leaves your sorry ass because you're broke and your kids have to go on welfare.  Good luck with FedEx.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>112</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[A Fedex HD Subcontrator]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>rpx@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.12.116.70</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-02 10:23:11</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[As a subcontractor for FDX HD, I can concur with some of the complaints and some i dont. But in my defense ALOT of address' are hard to find.  Many times people's houses are labled clearly. Also i find that many door bells dont work.

I HAVE BEEN BITTEN BY A CUSTOMERS DOG! The customer did absolutely NOTHING! I didnt have my pepper spray on me so i hit and kicked it. If I see a dog, I weather bag the package and leave a note letting them know it wasnt place at your dooor due to your dog.

Also we are on a time restraint.  Many times we have 110 stops or more.  I personally ring the doorbell and greet my customers. This lets them know the to look for the package at the door.  Alot of time the sound of doorbells ringing attracts dogs. PEOPLE YOU NEED TO GET CONTROL OF YOUR ANIMALS!

Be aware of both sides of this scenario. Many drivers go BEYOND their duty delivering to stops 2 times a day if it requires a signature to make sure their customers are happy. WE ARE PAID BY DELIVERED VISTITED STOP. I personally leave my cell number for my customers to call. If im in the area i will reattempt. I even call my customer at the start of the day to let them know i was coming. .

As with any shipping company, UPS, DHL, FDX, some packages cant be left because of high claims.  If a package is stolen or lost that requires a signature the driver is liable. I will knock several times, leave a door tag saying why i couldnt leave it.

As far a tips to help...

make sure your address' are correct and clearly labled.  we get many apt complexes with no apartment numbers.  request your rental office or  a neighbor to accept packages if your are unavalialle and leave a note for the driver. Track your package to approximate your time of delivery.  Watch your animals, you are liable for dog bites.

Thats my take]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>113</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[former contractor]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ctfulco@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>205.188.116.70</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-04 23:11:36</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I am a former ground contractor straight truck i just left, everthing [the wife]  said is correct 100% my terminal is currently trying to get the teamsters in the shop I had two 24 ft straight trucks just to double my trouble,s I am out of work. but i am so happy to be out of fed-ex jail that contract they have is so lopsided it's a joke. we are just employees that pay for everthing.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>114</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[tired and pissed]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>vdbaber@juno.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.136.27.227</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-07 02:04:32</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I wrote earlier this year that my family was down from four routes to two. well I just got a call from my nephew and he has turned is his resignation. Now we are down to one route. There must be a reason. Its simple, low pay, no respect from management, and no likelihood of things getting better in the near future. If your thinking about joining the happy FedEx Home Delivery family...... think again. ITS JUST NOT WORTH IT.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>115</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX EAT ME]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fedexsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-08 07:26:46</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[You got that right. Whole bs they bill about "running your own business" is shit. They would outsource to third world countries if they could. We should email this link to fed ex management....not that they would care just to give them a big fuck you.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>116</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FEDEX EAT ME]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fedexsucks@fedex.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.21.230.81</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-08 07:26:50</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[You got that right. Whole bs they bill about "running your own business" is shit. They would outsource to third world countries if they could. We should email this link to fed ex management....not that they would care just to give them a big fuck you.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>117</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Trex Dee]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ocokillian@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>67.22.30.111</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-11 20:06:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Once again I agree. Own your own buissness! yea right! Indentured Servitude is more like it.  This is worse than owning a franchise. Band together everyone that reads these posts and lets try to get the FedEx HD name stopped. Dont buy from companys that ship with them, and let potential employees see the real truth. The part about we are "empoyees" and not contractors is true.....Let me emplain it like this. You (the contractor) went into this buissness (ha ha) looking at it from a contractor  point of view. But someone forgot to tell the local Fedex managers that you are a contractor, NOT an employee of theirs!! They view you as just one of the other slobs around the terminal getting paid. Just today the Manager had the nerve to say to someone "just take care of it, it wont take that long". What? We dont get paid by the hour. It dosent matter if it took 1 min or 60 mins. Everyone in the sound of my voice take heed..................... AVOID FEDEX HOME DELIVERY LIKE THE PLAGUE!!!!!! (i have one route and want to seriously get rid of it and go back to a respectful job).]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>118</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[DougD]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ddemars@snet.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>204.60.42.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-15 15:16:11</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I was a Fedex Home Delivery contractor for 3.5 yrs. Had two routes,covered 22 different towns. Both trucks ran an average of 250 miles per day, not including "to home". Used to avg $1200/month for fuel. Sure, I made some money, before the trucks started breaking down!!!Price of gas up to 2.15/gal, guess who eat's that? I went from 70-80 stops per day 3 yrs ago to 130-160 this yr"2004".Yeah they cut or core zones, you have to do 15 stops more per day to make back the $10. How much more is that going to cost you in gas and maintenance? Anyway, went on vacation in May, spent a week in Aruba with the wife, she said I needed to go before I went in and shot the asshole manager. Got a guy to work for me for the week,who used to be a sub for someone else. The management sat on my guy's applcation for over two months, didn't want me to go on vacation!! The guy worked 4 out of 5 day's. Had a wedding to go to on Friday night, didn't come in on Sat. Managment talked my other driver into taking out my route, and they would do his!!! Tuesday am I go to work, @ other guy's are loading my stuff. Management pukes tell me "You abandoned your route, we gave it to them. Now you have to service an area 70 miles in the other direction." Two words for them, and it wasn't "happy birthday". Pulled both my trucks, went home had a beer. Called my lawyer, started my lawsuit proceddings. Contract say's you have to give me five day's written prior notice, guess what you didn't!! So we will see what happens. If your looking into this as a job, "I wouldn't". If you want to gross 150,000 a yr and pay out about 120,000, go for it!!! By the way the IRS loves it when you gross big money, especially as a contractor, you pay your own social security, medicare, and penalties for being self employed. Not tot mention your employee's taxes. Yeah I had 2 temps work for me at "peak" they made $550 a week under the table, plus the cost of renting 2 trucks, and fuel. My net after expenses, about $200 bucks. Sure we moved a ton of stuff for FEdEX , they made big money off all of us. Worked form 8am to 9-10pm. Each of us delivered about 175 stops per day. Talk about the royal screwing!!. I order all my stuff now thru UPS or DHL. Spent 5 yrs at the post office too before this, should have stayed. I'd have the full time job now, not $20,000 debt for two trucks that are pretty much beat to crap. Was planning on retireing from this ,46 now, kind of glad I'm not there anymore. Any of you guy's need a truck, I have two and know of atleast three other ex-contractors looking to unload their trucks. Fedex Home Delivery can kiss my butt!!!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>119</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[DougD]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ddemars@snet.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>204.60.42.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-15 15:16:35</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I was a Fedex Home Delivery contractor for 3.5 yrs. Had two routes,covered 22 different towns. Both trucks ran an average of 250 miles per day, not including "to home". Used to avg $1200/month for fuel. Sure, I made some money, before the trucks started breaking down!!!Price of gas up to 2.15/gal, guess who eat's that? I went from 70-80 stops per day 3 yrs ago to 130-160 this yr"2004".Yeah they cut or core zones, you have to do 15 stops more per day to make back the $10. How much more is that going to cost you in gas and maintenance? Anyway, went on vacation in May, spent a week in Aruba with the wife, she said I needed to go before I went in and shot the asshole manager. Got a guy to work for me for the week,who used to be a sub for someone else. The management sat on my guy's applcation for over two months, didn't want me to go on vacation!! The guy worked 4 out of 5 day's. Had a wedding to go to on Friday night, didn't come in on Sat. Managment talked my other driver into taking out my route, and they would do his!!! Tuesday am I go to work, @ other guy's are loading my stuff. Management pukes tell me "You abandoned your route, we gave it to them. Now you have to service an area 70 miles in the other direction." Two words for them, and it wasn't "happy birthday". Pulled both my trucks, went home had a beer. Called my lawyer, started my lawsuit proceddings. Contract say's you have to give me five day's written prior notice, guess what you didn't!! So we will see what happens. If your looking into this as a job, "I wouldn't". If you want to gross 150,000 a yr and pay out about 120,000, go for it!!! By the way the IRS loves it when you gross big money, especially as a contractor, you pay your own social security, medicare, and penalties for being self employed. Not tot mention your employee's taxes. Yeah I had 2 temps work for me at "peak" they made $550 a week under the table, plus the cost of renting 2 trucks, and fuel. My net after expenses, about $200 bucks. Sure we moved a ton of stuff for FEdEX , they made big money off all of us. Worked form 8am to 9-10pm. Each of us delivered about 175 stops per day. Talk about the royal screwing!!. I order all my stuff now thru UPS or DHL. Spent 5 yrs at the post office too before this, should have stayed. I'd have the full time job now, not $20,000 debt for two trucks that are pretty much beat to crap. Was planning on retireing from this ,46 now, kind of glad I'm not there anymore. Any of you guy's need a truck, I have two and know of atleast three other ex-contractors looking to unload their trucks. Fedex Home Delivery can kiss my butt!!!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>120</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[DougD]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ddemars@snet.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>204.60.42.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-15 15:18:42</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I was a Fedex Home Delivery contractor for 3.5 yrs. Had two routes,covered 22 different towns. Both trucks ran an average of 250 miles per day, not including "to home". Used to avg $1200/month for fuel. Sure, I made some money, before the trucks started breaking down!!!Price of gas up to 2.15/gal, guess who eat's that? I went from 70-80 stops per day 3 yrs ago to 130-160 this yr"2004".Yeah they cut or core zones, you have to do 15 stops more per day to make back the $10. How much more is that going to cost you in gas and maintenance? Anyway, went on vacation in May, spent a week in Aruba with the wife, she said I needed to go before I went in and shot the asshole manager. Got a guy to work for me for the week,who used to be a sub for someone else. The management sat on my guy's applcation for over two months, didn't want me to go on vacation!! The guy worked 4 out of 5 day's. Had a wedding to go to on Friday night, didn't come in on Sat. Managment talked my other driver into taking out my route, and they would do his!!! Tuesday am I go to work, @ other guy's are loading my stuff. Management pukes tell me "You abandoned your route, we gave it to them. Now you have to service an area 70 miles in the other direction." Two words for them, and it wasn't "happy birthday". Pulled both my trucks, went home had a beer. Called my lawyer, started my lawsuit proceddings. Contract say's you have to give me five day's written prior notice, guess what you didn't!! So we will see what happens. If your looking into this as a job, "I wouldn't". If you want to gross 150,000 a yr and pay out about 120,000, go for it!!! By the way the IRS loves it when you gross big money, especially as a contractor, you pay your own social security, medicare, and penalties for being self employed. Not tot mention your employee's taxes. Yeah I had 2 temps work for me at "peak" they made $550 a week under the table, plus the cost of renting 2 trucks, and fuel. My net after expenses, about $200 bucks. Sure we moved a ton of stuff for FEdEX , they made big money off all of us. Worked form 8am to 9-10pm. Each of us delivered about 175 stops per day. Talk about the royal screwing!!. I order all my stuff now thru UPS or DHL. Spent 5 yrs at the post office too before this, should have stayed. I'd have the full time job now, not $20,000 debt for two trucks that are pretty much beat to crap. Was planning on retireing from this ,46 now, kind of glad I'm not there anymore. Any of you guy's need a truck, I have two and know of atleast three other ex-contractors looking to unload their trucks. Fedex Home Delivery can kiss my butt!!!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>121</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Nearly Fucked]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>NearlyF@snet.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.177.4.63</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-18 13:10:33</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks everyone.
I live in a rural area and have been unable to make my current small business profitable. I read the Fedex HD ad and it sounded interesting, but something prompted me to do some more digging. After Googling, I found this BLOG and needless to say I will not be attending their meeting tonight!
Or maybe I will!!!
I could have a few hours entertainmenmt at this important 'business partner meeting' asking the recruiter probing questions about core zones, rates per drop, vehicle expenses, number of drops per day etc..... and then after being kicked out, waiting at the exit of the parking lot with copies of this URL and BLOG to give to the prospective business partners as they leave!!!!
What should I do??.....]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>122</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[John prkrine eater mucher]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>922dancealot@neonutz.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.42.219.179</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-19 14:09:40</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[fedex is gay]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>123</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[I love UPS]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ups@rules.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.190.176.22</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-24 20:10:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey listen up FEDEX Managers because I know you're reading this:

I ONLY PATRONIZE Vendors who Ship UPS.  I REFUSE to allow any of my packages to ship FEDEX.  I have been Fucked over time and time again by FEDEX...

NO MORE!!! FEDEX YOU SUCK SO FUCKING MUCH!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>124</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[UPS IS NOT THE ANSWER!!!]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ups@sucks.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.68.245.105</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-28 01:42:52</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hello all, I was poking around the net to check-up on fedex since UPS screwed me over by "losing" my critical shipment and my shipper was kind enough to reship the same parts (at no cost) via fedex instead of the brown turd.  I will make it a point to leave a note for the fedex (ground) guy.  Unfortunately, I operate a small business out of MY APARTMENT and I've never used fedex before....hope they don't screw me over like UPS did although reading through some of these posts doesn't do much in the way of boosting my confidence.

Now I have a very interesting link for all you people who think UPS is the right answer to fedex. http://www.unitedpackagesmashers.com/bbs/index.php

Guys and gals, as a former postal employee of 2 years at an area distribution center, I can honestly say that the USPS is still the way to go.  It is extremely rare that a package "vanishes into thin air".  It typically takes about 3 working days(including Saturday) for a parcel to work its way through the system....even coast to coast as long as it's first-class or priority.  Make sure you don't send any hazardous materials though as this will almost guarantee the parcel's returned to the sender or at worst, shipped by ground only.  Also, make sure your valuables/breakables are packaged correctly.  During the shipping process through the USPS (speaking from experience), the maximum force exerted on a parcel is 2 to 3 g's.  Postal employees are constantly monitored by the postal inspection service so if any sports are played using the parcel as the ball, it's goodbye mr. quarterback.  Another important point, if you reuse boxes to ship stuff through the USPS, that's fine but make sure it doesn't bare the "consumer commodity" symbol on it (it's a rectangle with the letters "ORM-D" inside of it).  Such parcel will be treated as HAZMAT regardless of its contents. Also, whenever possible, include the ZIP+4 as in some cases this may trim one day off of the delivery time.

In closing, I have never used DHL/Airborne so no comment there.  As far as FedEx, I have a package which supposedly shipped today so no comment on them YET.  UPS = sh*t as the color of their trucks, airplanes, and uniforms suggests.  You say you want your package fast and are considering UPS?  You have better odds gambling in Las Vegas.  UPS almost guarantees problems as well as headaches and disapointment.  USPS(first-class, priority) = reliable, relatively quick, dependable, and even a little bit cheaper.  You don't have to take the day off from work only to find a damned note stuck to your door written by a lying sack of sh*t saying no one was home.  At worst, you may find a slip of paper in your mailbox if the package doesn't fit.  Then you can either pick up the package, or make other arrangements to have it delivered.  That's my 2 cents ... well, maybe more like 2 dollars.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>125</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[PGH]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>123@456.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.179.23.4</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-31 17:14:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have to say this is the most interesting site about fedex i've come across yet.  As a full time employee in the Home Delivery Mid America region I have seen almost all of these problems in my time.  If you really want to understand the way FedEx Home Delivery works here it is.  They only delivery to residential addresses, but on occassion small businesses.

The drivers are independant contractors meening they own their vans and pay for everything to keep it running, the only thing fedex reimburses them for is uniforms, scanners, maps, and gas prices over 1.69$ a gallon.  They get payed about 1.25 per DELIVERED stop and 25 cents per DELIVERED package, not hourly or anything of that sort and if you arent home, no matter how far they drove or how many times theyve been there, they get nothing until it gets delivered and they only get the 1.25 and 25 cents one time, not each time they attempt delivery. On top of the per stop and per package pay they get whats called a core zone, each zipcode is assigned a price that the driver gets payed to deliver in that area, and all the ones they delived to get averaged together, the average is 90$ a day. So if you deliver to 60 stops 80 packages you've made 185$ but then you get about 15$ for gas and 30$ for "van availability" so ok you made 1150$ (this is highly accurate) this week and $4850 this month, pretty sweet huh, well then you have 50$ a day in gas which is 1050$ a month, then your 700$ a month truck payment, 200$ a month for insurance, then figure every 2 weeks you have an oil change and other maintnance which is about 500 monthly. So that leaves you at about $2400 a month or $575 a week before taxes, if you figure the average on road time of 11 hours not including any breaks, as a fedex home delivery drive you make 10.45$ an hour with no benefits.  Which ok not that bad... point is, these drivers are hard working people, and yes there are the exceptions, but they try their best, they will leave your package at your door if it doesnt require a signature and your neighborhood looks safe, and when they do leave it they will try to conceil it so it doesnt get stolen or damages, but if it comes up lost or damaged they get charged everything up to 100$ and the local delivery terminal gets charged everything beyond the 100$.  So when they leave that sticker and not your box its because they are making sure you actually get your package safe.

So thats the whole driver issue, heres the part we all relate to, the tracking info.  It is delayed 1 business day, why you ask, Home Delivery doesnt make pick ups, so drivers take their vans home with them, so the computer doesnt know whats going on with the packages until the next day until management comes in and service scans any non-delivered packages then reconciles the manifests from the scanners with the previous day makeing sure that the packages the driver says are delivered arent sitting in the back of his truck, then once thats done everything from the day before shows up on the tracking.  So when your packages says "unable to driver release" that meens either its signature required, you are in an apartment with no office that will accept your delivery or its a bad neighborhood with high claims.  An "unable to locate" is just that, the driver went down the street, passed 110, then 114 but you live at 112, wheres 112? He called the phone number on the box, no one answers... Worst case the package comes back to the terminal, we cant find your address with a reverse phone number lookup because you have an unlisted number and the shipper says thats the address you gave, the map shows thats where your house should be, so we send a post card to the address you gave us, if after 10 business days we get no responce we have to send it back to the shipper.  The reason a driver cant leave a signature package is because we dont know whats in the box, the shipper paid extra to get a signature, there could be prescriptions or wine in the box, a kid gets it, then what happens?  Most of the time places are found the first time, and the package gets delivered, but there are cases when it doesnt happen that way, and thats where management steps in and needs to work with the driver to find out what the problem is, and worst case is the driver doesnt improve and he loses his contract, he gets stuff with a 50,000$ truck loan payment and no income... when you think the driver doesnt care... think again.  We want to make the delivery just as much as you want us to... the first time every time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>126</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[PGH]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>123@456.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.179.23.4</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-31 17:15:01</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have to say this is the most interesting site about fedex i've come across yet.  As a full time employee in the Home Delivery Mid America region I have seen almost all of these problems in my time.  If you really want to understand the way FedEx Home Delivery works here it is.  They only delivery to residential addresses, but on occassion small businesses.

The drivers are independant contractors meening they own their vans and pay for everything to keep it running, the only thing fedex reimburses them for is uniforms, scanners, maps, and gas prices over 1.69$ a gallon.  They get payed about 1.25 per DELIVERED stop and 25 cents per DELIVERED package, not hourly or anything of that sort and if you arent home, no matter how far they drove or how many times theyve been there, they get nothing until it gets delivered and they only get the 1.25 and 25 cents one time, not each time they attempt delivery. On top of the per stop and per package pay they get whats called a core zone, each zipcode is assigned a price that the driver gets payed to deliver in that area, and all the ones they delived to get averaged together, the average is 90$ a day. So if you deliver to 60 stops 80 packages you've made 185$ but then you get about 15$ for gas and 30$ for "van availability" so ok you made 1150$ (this is highly accurate) this week and $4850 this month, pretty sweet huh, well then you have 50$ a day in gas which is 1050$ a month, then your 700$ a month truck payment, 200$ a month for insurance, then figure every 2 weeks you have an oil change and other maintnance which is about 500 monthly. So that leaves you at about $2400 a month or $575 a week before taxes, if you figure the average on road time of 11 hours not including any breaks, as a fedex home delivery drive you make 10.45$ an hour with no benefits.  Which ok not that bad... point is, these drivers are hard working people, and yes there are the exceptions, but they try their best, they will leave your package at your door if it doesnt require a signature and your neighborhood looks safe, and when they do leave it they will try to conceil it so it doesnt get stolen or damages, but if it comes up lost or damaged they get charged everything up to 100$ and the local delivery terminal gets charged everything beyond the 100$.  So when they leave that sticker and not your box its because they are making sure you actually get your package safe.

So thats the whole driver issue, heres the part we all relate to, the tracking info.  It is delayed 1 business day, why you ask, Home Delivery doesnt make pick ups, so drivers take their vans home with them, so the computer doesnt know whats going on with the packages until the next day until management comes in and service scans any non-delivered packages then reconciles the manifests from the scanners with the previous day makeing sure that the packages the driver says are delivered arent sitting in the back of his truck, then once thats done everything from the day before shows up on the tracking.  So when your packages says "unable to driver release" that meens either its signature required, you are in an apartment with no office that will accept your delivery or its a bad neighborhood with high claims.  An "unable to locate" is just that, the driver went down the street, passed 110, then 114 but you live at 112, wheres 112? He called the phone number on the box, no one answers... Worst case the package comes back to the terminal, we cant find your address with a reverse phone number lookup because you have an unlisted number and the shipper says thats the address you gave, the map shows thats where your house should be, so we send a post card to the address you gave us, if after 10 business days we get no responce we have to send it back to the shipper.  The reason a driver cant leave a signature package is because we dont know whats in the box, the shipper paid extra to get a signature, there could be prescriptions or wine in the box, a kid gets it, then what happens?  Most of the time places are found the first time, and the package gets delivered, but there are cases when it doesnt happen that way, and thats where management steps in and needs to work with the driver to find out what the problem is, and worst case is the driver doesnt improve and he loses his contract, he gets stuff with a 50,000$ truck loan payment and no income... when you think the driver doesnt care... think again.  We want to make the delivery just as much as you want us to... the first time every time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>127</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[PGH]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>123@456.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.179.23.4</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-31 17:15:27</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have to say this is the most interesting site about fedex i've come across yet.  As a full time employee in the Home Delivery Mid America region I have seen almost all of these problems in my time.  If you really want to understand the way FedEx Home Delivery works here it is.  They only delivery to residential addresses, but on occassion small businesses.

The drivers are independant contractors meening they own their vans and pay for everything to keep it running, the only thing fedex reimburses them for is uniforms, scanners, maps, and gas prices over 1.69$ a gallon.  They get payed about 1.25 per DELIVERED stop and 25 cents per DELIVERED package, not hourly or anything of that sort and if you arent home, no matter how far they drove or how many times theyve been there, they get nothing until it gets delivered and they only get the 1.25 and 25 cents one time, not each time they attempt delivery. On top of the per stop and per package pay they get whats called a core zone, each zipcode is assigned a price that the driver gets payed to deliver in that area, and all the ones they delived to get averaged together, the average is 90$ a day. So if you deliver to 60 stops 80 packages you've made 185$ but then you get about 15$ for gas and 30$ for "van availability" so ok you made 1150$ (this is highly accurate) this week and $4850 this month, pretty sweet huh, well then you have 50$ a day in gas which is 1050$ a month, then your 700$ a month truck payment, 200$ a month for insurance, then figure every 2 weeks you have an oil change and other maintnance which is about 500 monthly. So that leaves you at about $2400 a month or $575 a week before taxes, if you figure the average on road time of 11 hours not including any breaks, as a fedex home delivery drive you make 10.45$ an hour with no benefits.  Which ok not that bad... point is, these drivers are hard working people, and yes there are the exceptions, but they try their best, they will leave your package at your door if it doesnt require a signature and your neighborhood looks safe, and when they do leave it they will try to conceil it so it doesnt get stolen or damages, but if it comes up lost or damaged they get charged everything up to 100$ and the local delivery terminal gets charged everything beyond the 100$.  So when they leave that sticker and not your box its because they are making sure you actually get your package safe.

So thats the whole driver issue, heres the part we all relate to, the tracking info.  It is delayed 1 business day, why you ask, Home Delivery doesnt make pick ups, so drivers take their vans home with them, so the computer doesnt know whats going on with the packages until the next day until management comes in and service scans any non-delivered packages then reconciles the manifests from the scanners with the previous day makeing sure that the packages the driver says are delivered arent sitting in the back of his truck, then once thats done everything from the day before shows up on the tracking.  So when your packages says "unable to driver release" that meens either its signature required, you are in an apartment with no office that will accept your delivery or its a bad neighborhood with high claims.  An "unable to locate" is just that, the driver went down the street, passed 110, then 114 but you live at 112, wheres 112? He called the phone number on the box, no one answers... Worst case the package comes back to the terminal, we cant find your address with a reverse phone number lookup because you have an unlisted number and the shipper says thats the address you gave, the map shows thats where your house should be, so we send a post card to the address you gave us, if after 10 business days we get no responce we have to send it back to the shipper.  The reason a driver cant leave a signature package is because we dont know whats in the box, the shipper paid extra to get a signature, there could be prescriptions or wine in the box, a kid gets it, then what happens?  Most of the time places are found the first time, and the package gets delivered, but there are cases when it doesnt happen that way, and thats where management steps in and needs to work with the driver to find out what the problem is, and worst case is the driver doesnt improve and he loses his contract, he gets stuff with a 50,000$ truck loan payment and no income... when you think the driver doesnt care... think again.  We want to make the delivery just as much as you want us to... the first time every time.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>128</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[kc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kandrcorkery@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>152.163.252.165</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-31 23:35:37</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been with ground for 9 years, I have the hardest route in the building.  If you are looking at becoming a contractor,  go for an outride with another contractor to see if this something you want to do.  If you are going to buy a route ask to see his or her books, all costs involved.  Gross dollars mean nothing!!!  Trust me,  you will not make it if you are driving 250 miles-plus per day.  It just won't work,  half of the home drivers are currently looking at finding a diffrent way to make a living.  Not because they don't like delivering, they are tired of not having enough money left after all bills are paid.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>129</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[kc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kandrcorkery@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://?</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>152.163.252.165</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-08-31 23:37:00</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been with ground for 9 years, I have the hardest route in the building.  If you are looking at becoming a contractor,  go for an outride with another contractor to see if this something you want to do.  If you are going to buy a route ask to see his or her books, all costs involved.  Gross dollars mean nothing!!!  Trust me,  you will not make it if you are driving 250 miles-plus per day.  It just won't work,  half of the home drivers are currently looking at finding a diffrent way to make a living.  Not because they don't like delivering, they are tired of not having enough money left after all bills are paid.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>130</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[independent?]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>daver618@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.39.202.7</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-07 15:03:19</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[To all my fellow home delivery drivers, are you aware that about a year a two contractors from Califorina sued fedex and won. The judge found that were legally employees and not indepentant contractors. The trial is in phase 2 where they are going to decide what compensation they will receive. Maybe there is so hope on the horizon,for the rest of us]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>131</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[groundvhome]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>travel@fcc.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>151.205.171.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-16 08:29:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I noticed most of the ics were from home, is ground just as bad?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>132</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[kc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kandrcorkery@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.12.116.70</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-17 20:47:06</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[is ground just as bad...well every route is different some have better routes than others...this is how, the best ground route contractor drives very few miles, has a lot of stops, and packages.  This would be a city route,  a rural route you gross sometimes just as  much money, but your expenses are much higher example, wear and tear on truck,  fuel, freqincy of tire replacement, oil changes/ service bumper to bumper, most important it takes alot of time to drive and deliver a 200 mile route.  Then to get told once a year your route has grown so now we can take some of your core zone pay away.. guess what they keep you making the same amount of money while expenses keep going up.  Oh by the way a brand new Freghtliner p-1000 truck costs just shy of 50k.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>133</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[kc]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>kandrcorkery@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.12.116.70</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-17 20:48:30</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[is ground just as bad...well every route is different some have better routes than others...this is how, the best ground route contractor drives very few miles, has a lot of stops, and packages.  This would be a city route,  a rural route you gross sometimes just as  much money, but your expenses are much higher example, wear and tear on truck,  fuel, freqincy of tire replacement, oil changes/ service bumper to bumper, most important it takes alot of time to drive and deliver a 200 mile route.  Then to get told once a year your route has grown so now we can take some of your core zone pay away.. guess what they keep you making the same amount of money while expenses keep going up.  Oh by the way a brand new Freghtliner p-1000 truck costs just shy of 50k.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>134</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[fhd guy's girlfriend]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>goodchickens@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://notofhd.blogspot.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.38.224.53</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-18 05:23:55</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I sympathize with the rest of the FHD contractors points here.   My boyfriend is a FHD contractor and had we been able to find a site at the time where contractors were sounding off, he wouldn't have taken on the route.  I've started a blog talking about some of the things that I've been seeing/understanding about this "business venture" at http://notofhd.blogspot.com/.  All my facts may not be 100% accurate but I wanted to get something out there that talks about some of the realities vs what they "told you up front".  If there was enough interest, I would even consider creating a BBS system so that you all could have a place to compare notes since talking amongst the ranks at the terminal just may prompt little "talks" in the manager's office.

And to the "happy" contractor out there (some of whom I belive get kickbacks from management to spy on the rest of the guys).  I'm sure that some terminals are better than others.  The terminal manager at my boyfriends place though sounds like nothing but a bobble head, yah yah yahing everyone to death.  The QA guy, fresh from QA school doesn't seem to understand that driving 1/2 hour out of the way for an appointment delivery means that contractors most likely LOOSE money on the delivery.

Its very unfortunate that customers are getting caught in the crossfire of the FHD politics because to them it just looks like bad service and nothing more.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>135</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[carlos]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>hwac@gwu.edu</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>132.194.210.15</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-18 19:19:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[i have been sitting in my house for the last 10 hours because i was assured my package, which i need tomorrow, would be delivered today by 800-gofedex, even though yesterday i called to pickup my package myself today, which they assured i would be able to. after it was not delivered as promised, i called back and was assured i would receive a call next week about how to get the package, and i was assured (sound familiar?) that the package would not be returned to the shipper. i notice their website only has a customer support link, not customer service. fortunately i have never shipped anything myself via fedex, and now i will never patronize a service that ships with fedex.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>136</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Phil]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>unknown.ca@ca.unknown.ca</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.230.190.131</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-21 09:24:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've had nothing but a great experience with Fedex here in Canada, its UPS that is horrible. I won't go in to the details, but I once was bugged for customers charges for over 3 months on an item that was a repair item (Item was sent over border back to me after it was fixed), and the list of crap like paying more in FEES then the item itself is worth..on top of paying for shipping, and to date this only happened with UPS. GO FEDEX, and DON'T GO BACK!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>137</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FHD screwed me 2]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>fhd@j2c3.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>146.115.28.82</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-21 18:00:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Majority of comments /stories are all true:
- Fedex regular service is great
- UPS ground is great
- Fedex Home Ground sux ass

My local FHD guy will:
- fake scan items to make sure they don't look undelivered including:
- scanning items as 'delivered' that aren't, then back that out the next day
- scanning items into a 'hold for pickup' status when he doesn't want to deliver. yet calling Fedex, they can't find the package or any record of it.
- he will also claim 'nobody home' without trying (someone home all day practically staring out the window for him to show up)
- be in the neighborhood without trying deliver - today I saw him turn the corner a 1/2 block away when my package status was 'out for delivery' - i.e. on his truck...

From the copious comments above, obviously Fedex offers a crappy compensation deal to contractors, which is causing the problems. As some douchebags have noted, we all need to vote strongly with our cash. Insist if you can on your eBay or other vendor NOT shipping Fedex ground. But contrary to said douchebags, it is well worth complaining and spreading the word.

Fedex Home Delivery blows. Avoid it at all costs and tell everyone you know.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>138</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Alternative to UPS/FEDEX]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>charitable@adelphia.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.164.105.243</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-09-24 12:58:12</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Love this thread!! thanks to all who join in. In my business I have shipped many many packages for many many years with Fedex and UPS and learned to live with their shortcomings. Now that DHL is truly a player I have been using them for about 6 months (about 400 packages) and LOVE IT.

Hint - the key is to use a good reseller, which you cannot do with UPS or Fedex. Resellers give the best rates and can solve service issues fast without dealing with the normal #800 garbage. Some resellers suck, but United Shipping has given me GREAT rates and SUPER service. If you ship on a regular basis I highly recommend them (800-706-0736)]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>139</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[TP]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>12.154.212.118</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2004-10-10 23:33:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2004-10-11 06:33:29</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have been a FHG contractor for 3.5 years and when I read this blog I get pissed off.  Owning your own business is not having FEDEX hand you everything.  Yes you do have to work a little hard at first, what business owner Doesn't?  When I first started I Commuted 100 miles to a local terminal then drove back to the town where my route was, then returned back to terminal, and then drove back home.  My day started @ 4:00 am and ended @ 8:00 p.m. Why did I do this, because I did my homework and knew in the long run I would  be successful in owning my own business.  3.5 years later my volume has increased 75%, my core zone has decreased Approx 50%, I no longer have to commute.  I have bought and sold routes and enjoy being a fedex ground Contractor.  I do not drive daily anymore only as a fill in on heavy volume days or during peak.  My drivers are happy, I pay them pretty good money.  I utilize all of the financial options available to me for creating extra revenue.  My Point is I am successful because I want to be.  Apart from the daily phone calls from terminal manager tracking packages, I am my own boss.  SO if you find that you cannot make it doing what you are doing QUIT. dont expect FEDEX to make you succesful. Quit whining and move on.  Most of my customers are repeat customers and I havebuilt a very good relationship with them.  Not a**hole sounding people on this forum.  OH yeah when you order and ship FEDEX it doesn't always mean overnight.     Happy with FEDEX]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>140</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[IMPORT FLAVOUR]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>importflavour@importflavour.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.importflavour.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.112.227.112</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-02-21 07:33:28</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-02-21 15:33:28</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Fedex damages packages, drops them at your door and leaves without ringing the doorbell so that the box can be opened by the
local kids and stolen.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>141</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[FedEx EXPRESS driver]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>69.105.142.99</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-02-22 20:03:44</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-02-23 04:03:44</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[OK, so youre all on here complaining about FedEx right? Well, if you look at the original post, the complaint was about FedEx HOME delivery. FedEx has many different branches, which is stupid I agree because I have to deal with the BS of customers everyday that dont know who they gave their package to or cant read the name on trucks and uniforms. However, for those of you who don't know, FedEx Express is the main corporation with hired employess who provide everything we need on the daily to do our job (trucks, uniforms, tracking equipment), FedEx Ground is independently owned and FedEx Home works under FedEx ground. They have to buy their own vehicles and also buy the area they work in, then hire any and everybody to work under them. I agree FEDEX HOME and FEDEX GROUND SUCK big time. I work for FedEx Express and cant even get info on a package sent thru Ground because they are on a completely different network. All Im saying, is dont throw all of FedEx in your hate mail, just the branch that cant get their shyt straight.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>142</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[RJ]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mherman@post.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.174.0.253</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-04-18 10:38:02</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-04-18 18:38:02</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[What you need to know, and the Fedex manager won't tell you, is that the Fedex drivers (Ground and Home Delivery) are independant contractors who work 10 hours a day delivering packages that are not all a part of their route but are "flexed" to them by management (Fedex driver have no say in whether they deliver these packages unless they want to "risk their contract"). Your poor driver most likely had so many packages that day that he couldn't spend the extra  minute it would take to wait for you (and about 50 other people) to make it to the front door. Drivers are under the conrtol on the Department of Transportation and can not exceed the maximum daily hours. Yet, under their contract, if a driver has too many DNA's (did not attempt) or brings back too many packages they will loosing their contract and the money they have invested in purchasing it. So what do you do if you are the driver? Run to the door, stick a note on it and pray for a lighter day tomorrow....]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>143</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Tim Thongpanith]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>lkjs@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.importflavour.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>70.25.121.24</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-11-01 11:43:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-11-01 19:43:20</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hey I work for Quick-EX and we open and steal merchandise on a daily basis. Make sure you label the packages in some generic format as I have personally stolen mp3 players and all that crap from ebay. Once we see an ebay packing slip or electronics boxes we take that sh&amp;*it home with us. I have about 30 dvd players for sale at my house in newmarket. If anyone wants to buy it let me kmow. If you losers want secure stuff ship it with the post office. Oh by the way, we just claim it as lost and you can't do S*HI(T about it!! LOL
Anyway, all you internet nerds shipping your ipods with fedex watch out, you might get a cardboard box with a brick in it one day. Just remember Tim Thongpanith from Import Flavour owned by Roberto Ibale told you!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>144</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[UPS]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.227.32.249</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2005-11-07 16:09:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2005-11-08 00:09:08</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[UPS has the same problems!!!!!!!!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>145</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[J. Waite]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.155.79.239</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-11-14 14:04:37</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-11-14 21:04:37</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have another one for you. I have been 'tracking' (if you can call it that) my Fed Ex shipment online and noticed yesterday when I came home that the shipping address was incorrect and that they didn't have my APT #. So I made the call to their 'customer service' (again if you want to call it that) and gave them my APT# and had him repeat it back to me 3 times to make sure it was correct so that package would arrive the next day. (today) So after sitting home all day AGAIN to sign for this package I decided I would go online and 'track' it. Now I see a notice that says 'Customer not available or business closed'. So I call back the customer service AGAIN and they tell me that he it is possilbe that they couldn't get in because I live in a gated apartment. I then explained to them that UPS never had a problem going into the clubhouse at the MAIN entrance and asked to be let in. I even went one further and explained to them that the front office is allowed to sign off on packages for me because I signed a form allowing them to do so. They then told me that they would contact the local dispatch and let them know that I AM in fact home, the business is NOT closed, and they CAN get in. I asked it I could be called if they would deliver the package today and she informed me that the drivers rarely use their personal cell phones for work purposes. Aparently the :30 call costs too much or I (the customer) am just a burden. Regardless, I am disgusted with this service and will never BUY, SELL, or ship anything that has to do with FedEx being a part of the transaction. Ridiculous!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>146</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[C. Thomas]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>trainman@ireland.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.255.25.161</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2008-12-20 13:01:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2008-12-20 20:01:54</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FedEx Home is evidently hiring the products of the American education system now.  Four days ago, I returned home to find that my expected package had not been delivered.  The reason?  Signature required!  The driver had not been able to open the gate and had just thrown the "attempted delivery" ticket on the ground inside the fence.  Following the instructions on this ticket, I signed it, fully expecting to receive my package the next day.  Not to be, since the driver, on the next day, went to the front door around the corner which, by the way, has a large sign on it saying "ALL DELIVERIES TO THE BACK DOOR", the door where the delivery ticket had been left on the previous day.  Affixed to this front door, directly beneath the "ALL DELIVERIES TO THE BACK DOOR" sign!  Once again on the next day, one of these mental midgets did the same thing, almost covering up the sign with his ticket.  Calling FedEx is nothing more than a fools errand, their form of mental masturbation I suppose.  From this point on, if a shipper even hints at sending anything by FedEx, they have lost the sale!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>147</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Aaron]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.240.67.61</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-02-28 06:37:28</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-02-28 13:37:28</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ive had two bad experiences with Fedex.  First the overnight delivery didn't make overnight it because of weather. Some thunderstorms.  But my mail man made it on time and delivered a few packages the same day FedEx overnight was supposed to.  And now, something that's coming from 4 hours driving distance away is going to take four days to get here.  I called and they just don't know why. "Mighta been a miss- sort."  "We just don't know."   Nice.  I wish it was coming through the regular mail because I would have had it when I needed it.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>148</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[David T.]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dthatcher7@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>70.164.108.158</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-06-04 13:43:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-06-04 20:43:54</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The FedEx Home Delivery guy just delivered something to one of the people downstairs in our complex, but didn't deliver our package, even though the tracking site says it is out for delivery today. He obviously didn't want to take the time to go up the stairs. Oh and he was driving a non-descript white truck with no labels or livery. I am going to get the tracking number off of the package downstairs then call FedEx and rip them up over this.

Sad part about this? My 3-mo old son needs his special formula, being shipped by a home health supply company (North American Home Health) contracted by his HMO (Anthem Blue Cross). Why anyone would ship critical medical supplies via FedEX HD is beyond me.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>149</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[NerdSteve]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>siverson@sjm.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>136.237.60.105</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-08-18 11:11:24</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-08-18 18:11:24</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I had a similar experience with Fedex Home Delivery and will never use them again.

June 10th: I sent a folding bicycle from myself in San Francisco to myself in Chicago (my second home). I printed the shipper from my home computer (like I always do for my business items) and delivered the 30 by 30 by 16 box to my neighborhood Kinkos. They told me it would arrive in Chicago on June 16th - "perfect!"

June 16th: When June 16th came with no delivery, I decided to give Fedex a call. I was told that the package was on the truck and that everything was fine for delivery the next day.

June 18th: When June 18th came with no delivery, I decided to give Fedex another call. I was told that they put the package on the wrong truck, but that it would be there on June 19th. The explaination was that they were not fimiliar with the zip code on my package - I then told them it was for downtown chicago and wondered how they could not know the zip code for one of the most common delivery locations in the USA. They said that it would be delivered on June 19th - "I heard that one before!"

June 20th: When June 20th came with no delivery, I decided to give Fedex another call (as you can imagine I was not very happy by now). They said that they decided to return it to the shipper since they could not read the barcode. Would have been nice to get a fucking phone call.

The package was now in Utah being shipped back to CA. I asked them why they didn't give me a call (strange?). Since my vacation was ending, I said fine, ship it back to the sender - which was me and re-gave them my address in San Francisco just to make sure they had the return shipping address.

June 25th: When June 25th came with no delivery back at my home in San Francisco, I decided to give Fedex another call. They told me that they shipped it back to the Fedex Account number location (which is in Los Angeles). I honestly could not believe this! I told them that I specifically said a week earlier to ship it back to the shipping address and gave them the address.  What they did was ship it back to company's headquarters in LA since that is where the billing number orginated from - fucking dumb shits!

July 1st: On July 1st I finally received my package back - 21 days after I shipped it. They tried to deliver it two different times in LA.

In the end, the package was in pretty good shape - only one broken fender on my bike.  I was just happy to get the bike back - it had a better vacation that me.

I will NEVER use Fedex Home Delivery again. The multitude of stupidity and screw-ups were mind boggling. I talked with 10 different people - all fucking stupid.  If you want your packages on-time do not use Fedex Home Delivery.

I'm also looking at switching over my overnight delivery service to someone else more reliable - the US Post Office! Can you believe that?

If you don't believe me take a look - Tracking number: 112251010000090.

Fedex Home Delivery - "You Suck"!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>150</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[baretruth]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://fedexhomesucks.blogspot.com/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>24.17.214.37</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-09-26 15:30:51</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-09-26 22:30:51</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FedEx Home is extremely poor

Never use FedEx Home for sending any packages. It is the worst package service that I have ever encountered. FedEx sub-contracts it out to independent contractors and it has absolutely no control over the tracking of the package or any committment it makes to the customer.
I was expecting a package (Door Tag # DT 7510 7129 7858) to be delivered to my home on a Thursday. Since I knew that I cannot be at home on Thursday I called FedEx that could they hold my package or re-route the package to my office address:
Pain #1: No re-routing available on the FedEx Home service. I could understand this being an economical version of FedEx might not have that functionality
Pain #2: My request to hold the package could not be entertained until 24-48 hours has passed because the packages are given to independent contractors and they have no way to connect to them
Pain # 3: I called repeatedly (6 times) on Friday and Saturday to find whether the package has been held at their facility (15miles from my address) and everytime the answer was that it is not there. We cannot guarantee we when will it be there
Pain #4: We do not work on Sunday and Monday. My package that was supposed to be delivered on Thursday will need to be collected 15 miles from my place only next Tuesday, IF I AM LUCKY

Everytime I called FedEx I would learn a new factoid about this FedEx Home service. Please use USPS or a UPS Ground service but never never FedEx Home. It sucks!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>151</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Irmin]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>iwehmeier@comcast.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>64.234.166.89</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-10-13 08:52:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-10-13 15:52:54</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[FedEx Home is completely lame. The regular FedEx facility here is located in a large customer friendly building in an easily accessible part of town. If I miss a delivery I can pick it up anytime after 4:30. FedEx Home on the other hand is located in a dingy rat hole of a warehouse on the outskirts of town. I ordered something from Amazon on Oct. 5, it ships on the 6th for delivery on the 9th. Nothing on the 9th and no tracking info past the 7th. I call on the 13th and they don't know where it is and it will take 24-48 hours to investigate. Amazon won't re-ship for ten days before considering it lost. That's over two weeks for something that originated a ten hour drive from here.  Next time I see FedEx home on an invoice I'll cancel the order right away. I'll be refusing shipment on this one and order from Newegg that guarantees  free UPS 3 day delivery .]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>152</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Never purchase a FEDEX route]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>murdamewzik@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.174.248.29</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-10-14 20:25:03</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-10-15 03:25:03</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[For people thinking why service sucks let me tell you what us drivers have to deal with. I was an aspiring contractor, wanted to work a route for a year to learn this business before I dropped down my money for one.

Its all nickels and dimes. Go deliver a big monster 150 pound desk up 3 flights of stairs in a building and you might make like an extra buck. Go to 130 places a day with 250-300 packages and then go do another 200 packages of pickups to bring back.

Right before you drive back to the terminal, a customer calls saying they just got home and need their package, you got to drive all the way back it doesnt matter how far away you are. I had to do a delivery with my car a few times because people got home late from work and needed their packages or you got angry managers.

There is a reason Fedex (Ground) is getting rid of single route contractor owners. For those who have money, they hire slave labor workers for about 120 bucks a day to deliver a fully loaded stocked out truck and drive to all those places. 120 bucks a day for 10 hours a day is 12 dollars an hour. 12 bucks! No overtime. No health insurance. The person I replaced at my job broke his ankle on the job and that was that, poor guy probably spend all his savings for the hospital on 12 bucks an hour.

Fedex managers then give a route that "freed up" aka firing someone, and giving it to someone who already owns a couple of routes. I have seen terminal managers, and the big boss, at a barbeque party for some contractor who was "given" 2 or 3 routes by management. In about 2 years of working there, I have seen many hard workers with families who spent thousands of dollars on routes have it taken away from them, and given to a multiple-route contractor who then hires a driver for 120 and thats that.

People come and go in Fedex. Drivers don't usually stick around after a year. Contractors replace them with some new sucker being fed lies of how great it is, wash, rinse and repeat. Oh, and if you're a driver, before you leave, your boss (contractor) that you work for might decide to hold your last pay check to mess with you and see if you go the distance for that 120 bucks a day.

 If a driver gets a parking ticket sometimes the contractor makes the driver pay for them by withholding money on days u get paid cash . God forbid you get into a fender bender while you are racing to all those 130 places. As a non-contractor, you have no rights and get worked to the bone. This is why every driver is young, in their 20's, doing deliveries if they arent contractors. They dont last.

Why dont we last? When my contractor did not want to pay me for my last week of working for him, I went to the managers to ask for proof that I worked those days by giving me photocopies of the paperwork I sign off to at the end of the day.

Know what these managers, who go to barbeque parties of contractors they favor told me? NO. Its confidential. You must speak to a lawyer and get a subpena so we can release that information to you in order for your contractor to pay you.

Why ON EARTH would I want to drop thousands of dollars to buy a route and work for these people again??? This is a joke job. Buying a route and becoming a contractor just gets you buy. You need to get 3 routes to make decent money, then hire slave labor drivers for 120 bucks a day/12 bucks an hour to do the work. Make them pay for some of the tickets and partial truck damages; AND BE ABLE TO GET AWAY WITH IT NO UNION FOR DRIVERS.

If you do decide to buy a fedex route, then begin worrying if they target you after a year to give your route to someone they really like. For all you know, the big boss probably gets a kickback for handing a route to someone and you just lost your livelyhood and investment.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>153</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Never purchase a FEDEX route]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>murdamewzik@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>68.174.248.29</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-10-14 20:43:52</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-10-15 03:43:52</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[So, if you are a customer, and I were still a slave labor driver that got suckered to work at fedex ground, come and ask me if I really give a crap about your package..when I worry about my boss not paying me, 100 dollar parking tickets that takes me a full days work to pay off, managers who wont stick up for me..being over dispatched, having to worry about not just 1 route..but many routes..when you're working for a contractor, if he has 15 routes with 15 drivers..if some of them are sick or take off, alot of extra work gets loaded onto your back..the packages dont even fit in the truck they SPILL all over the passenger side if the contractor you work for is shorthanded. You wont even get a ham sandwich for a tip for doing all that work for 120 bucks day/12 per hour.

If you are a driver that works for a contractor, your boss will basically teach you to do scams to make 1 stop into 2, so he can make double the money. You start doing this so he can view you as a great worker then will screw you when it comes down to it with your pay, or putting in a bad word for you to managers if you want to become a contractor if GOD FORBID you ask for your pay money when you decide to call it quits.

Yeah, come ask me if I care for your package.

I worked for Fedex Ground to see if it was worth becoming a contractor. I was clean cut, straight as an arrow. I left the place as corrupt as you could possibly think of, screwed by the person I worked hard for by being taught to scam to make him extra money, being screwed by management that wont give me my proof I worked for those days in question, screwed by people I thought were my friends.

But, at least I have my money! I got away from fedex good if you ask me. Others got suckered into buying a route and became single route contractors who are deer in headlights for multiple-route contractors looking to gobble their routes up and hire slave labor, and by management; who is looking to keep the union out by giving more routes to multiple route owners because owning one route is nickels and dimes for the money you are spending. Money's just not worth it for single route contractors, theres even many of THEM that want a union instead. Deer in headlights, man.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>154</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Daniel]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>dtobin123@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>98.201.105.130</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-10-31 11:11:39</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-10-31 18:11:39</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Time after time FedEx Home Delivery drivers have left me "delivery attempt" notices without actually attempting to deliver a package. These are times when I've been home and heard the truck, but the driver intentionally did not ring the bell or knock. Twice, while running outside to try and get the damn package, I've witnessed the drivers shuffle to their trucks without a package in hand. Obviously they hadn't bothered to even take the package out of the truck knowing that its much faster to simply write up the door tag while in their truck, stick on the door, and hightail it out of dodge before the customer can see them. Well, the sad part is that if in my case you do see them trying to get away and you attempt to get them to stop, they pretend they can't hear you and keep going.

Why would FedEx, with is normally trustworthy service want to associate itself with Home Delivery which is utterly impotent? Home Delivery without question has a shoddy reputation and this can't do much to help the FedEx brand as a whole.

Before I ever had encountered Home Delivery I would normally have paid extra money to use FedEx services because of their reliability, but after several nightmarish incidents with Home Delivery I would never use any FedEx service, even though I am well aware that Home Delivery is entirely separate from traditional FedEx service given that it's run by contractors. The fact that FedEx would create such contradictions in their brand is enough to make me boycott it all together, and by reading many of these posts it sounds like this push back is fairly common.

FedEx was certainly capable of having a decent ground service to compete against UPS, but in implementing a business model to maximize profits by cutting corners they have seriously tarnished their overall reputation.

I was often ambivalent and spiteful towards the USPS and UPS for service that was sometimes lacking, but FedEx Home Delivery is so terrible that I have grown to appreciate these other more friendlier options.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>155</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>65.201.163.11</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-11-20 08:09:53</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-11-20 15:09:53</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[9612804801215074743123

This is my tracking number.  Hopefully I will get my package today, a week late, at my office after paying to have it delivered to my house.  And that really sucks because I Metro to work and lugging all that other crap home with me tonight is gonna be AWESOME.

My package is getting a scenic tour of the DC metro area apparently, when they could have just left the damn thing in front of my door, the way I instructed them to when I called the Customer service number after they claim to have attempted to deliver it on Saturday.  No you didn't asshole, I was HOME all day!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>156</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[WC Jones]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>98.169.187.243</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-02-15 10:42:50</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-02-15 17:42:50</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I feel the same way fed ex home delivery was supposed to deliver my computer on 2/13/10. The truck never came. So i figure that they would come on Monday..... WRONG they are closed on Monday. They was no inclement weather Saturday I seen other fed ex trucks delivering the whole day. I cant stand Home delivery. I cant pick it up since they are closed also the tracking is awwwwful it does not update as it should. This is crazy just have one company and not all of these Subdivisions of people who cant communicate with each other. NEVER again i will be checking from each retailer to see if that is who they use to ship out their products. I have never had any problems with any of the other companies but this home delivery is the worst]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>157</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Roche]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>roche789@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.200.116.11</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-03-06 18:43:57</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-03-07 01:43:57</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Anyone want to sell their Home Delivery route?]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>158</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Duke]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>DukeXV@Prodigy.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>199.196.144.11</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-03-18 05:13:11</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-03-18 12:13:11</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I hate it when vendors use FEDEX Home Delivery. Where I live if you miss them you can't pick it up at the local FEDEX terminal (like UPS), you have to drive 30 miles to another state and maybe it'll be there.

A while ago, I bought a vintage rifle at auction and the auction house shipped via FEDEX Home.  Well there was a mystery attempt to deliver it on Friday and I went to the terminal to pick it up on Saturday.  The clerk tried to find it, but couldn't and told me it was lost. He suggested I contact the auction house and file a claim.  I told him that because it was a firearm and I was a federally licensed collector, I would have to call both the local police and the BATFE (part of the US Justice Dept)immdeiately. The clerk jumped up, ran to the manager's office and they disappeared into the terminal. Fifteen minutes later they emerged with my package.

Now,I ask dealers not to ship via FEDEX Home and to use UPS, the extra charge is worth it!  The regular FEDEX seems to be ok - still.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>159</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Troy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>66.30.40.7</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-03-25 19:10:40</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-03-26 02:10:40</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I agree. Fedex drivers a menace and the Trade commission or whom so ever overseas package delivery drivers who are a danger to consumers should be taken to court.

While walking my pet, on the other side of the street from my home, I saw the driver jump out, with a white note in his hand, trying to post it on my mailbox.  He had made not even attempt to deliver the package or even knock! Not one knock on the door!  Then, when I called out out to him, he pretended to be just delivering the package.  Then he proceeded to be extremely rude to me.  So that I had to complain about him not only to their headoffice.  I am also thinkin of also complaining to the police because I feel threatened by this guy.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>160</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Alan]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>douglas@newtechniques.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.newtechniques.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>207.237.210.242</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-04-21 09:42:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-04-21 16:42:08</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I use regular Fed-Ex frequently. One day the online site suggested that a location "qualifies" for Fed-Ex Home delivery so I tried it - HUGE MISTAKE !

My doorman apparently handed the box to someone from Fed-Ex. The doorman can't remember if it said "Fed-Ex" on his short or maybe "Fed-Ex Home delivery". Either way it Fed-Ex comes to our building everyday and the doorman handed it to a representative of Fed-Ex.

I've heard this is a complete separate company - really? It says Fed-Ex in the name - idiots !

10-12 days later I get the package back with "returned for postage", the address crossed out in thick black marker (probably so it can't be mailed again), and what looks like official style post office stamps in smeared, blurred red ink stating "REFUSED" and "POSTAGE". (with the little hand and finger pointing at the address. This looks like the postage service somehow was handed the box.

The box was 5 lbs and big so it's wasn't the mailman that accepted it - it's against their policy to accept packages over 1 lbs. UPS won't take a box marked for Fed-Ex, so it was a guy from Fed-Ex that took it from my doorman.

What an absolute joke!

I call Fed-Ex and the package only shows that I printed the label - it was never entered into the Fed-Ex tracking system. I called fed-Ex and they repeated this message 10 times to me. One person forwarded my phone call to the local depot in Brooklyn, and guess what - hey "the package hasn't been scanned into our system" - really?  no shit?  I never heard that one before.

*Fed-Ex Home Delivery is actually a fraud*. I can't want until some enterprising lawyer gets a hold of enough information and makes a class action run at "Fed-Ex Home", ditto for Senator Chuck Shummer.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>161</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[rich]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.87.214.189</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-05-05 18:52:08</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-05-06 01:52:08</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I have had all above problems, I test my doorbell bebore every delivery, OK.Last three no show, no ring. Paper slip yes. Whats UP!!!!!!!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>162</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Mike]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>lafue108@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>98.227.37.226</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-06-10 17:07:46</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-06-11 00:07:46</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I had the same problem and hate when online sellers use FedEx.  I live in an apartment without a drop box....UPS man leaves packages at the neighboring business for me so I can pick them up after work.  FedEx man makes me drive 15 miles to their pick up station out in the middle of nowhere.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>163</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Johnson]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>166.205.138.239</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-09-25 15:53:41</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-09-25 22:53:41</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The exact same thing happened to me. I was expecting my new 23" tv monitor. There is no tracking number or what so ever. They do not knock the door or ring the bell. I was at home for the whole day. Ok, that is The first attempt on friday, so i decided to sign the tag so they can leave the package in front of the door. On Saturday , I got another tag, this time is worse, they don't even care to stick the tag on the door, they just left it on the floor. One thing I can't help wondering--- are they some kind of retard who don't even know how to use the door bell? I was so angry, and called the station, the man with Indian accent just keep apologizing like fcking machine. He told me then I have to go the station to pick up the item myself on Tuesday(three days later). WTF, the station is 15 miles away,  Who the f is going to pay the gasoline. I will never use fedex again. It fcking sucks.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>164</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[John L]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>jlindsey@ptd.net</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>70.44.224.116</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-10-06 09:52:15</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-10-06 16:52:15</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Seven years since this article was posted and nothing has changed. Every time someone ships me something via FedEx Home Delivery, it seems like it goes out on the truck and then back to the depot. Sometimes this happens 3 or 4 times before it finally gets delivered.

Whatever happened to "When it absolutely, positively has to be there overnight." ??]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>165</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[swing driver]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ricebike@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.125.145.152</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-10-13 21:21:01</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-10-14 04:21:01</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've run different routes in my state, trying both branches of ground and home delivery... with HD, at least you get a map &amp; turn-by-turns with your packages plotted so you know what's in your vehicle before you go out and drive. I prefer to sort/load my own truck so I know where every package is in my vehicle, but we need to get paid for that as well.

True, it depends on the driver and amount of stops per day allotted. I limit myself only a certain amount of stops per day, to allow for some misplots on my map. If I'm done early, I'll try a 2nd attempt the same day, so I can get paid for a SUCCESSFUL delivery.

TIPS:

Having a house number clearly visible helps ALOT, or if you're in a wacky street that even today's online maps/gps can't find, please leave some extra info on the 2nd line of the address form.

If you're a business, please leave the name of the business &amp; suite # if necessary.

If you know the tracking number &amp; it needs a signature, you can go online and print out a signature release form from the site. or I tell my customers I'm servicing to leave a note with their signature on it &amp; I'll release the package to their front/ side/ back door / porch/ etc...

----------------------------------------------------

I've been bitten by small dogs, but they didn't draw blood... which is lucky.

It's a good experience to pad your resume while you're looking for a REAL job.

I agree that Fedex HD should be paid hourly &amp; I'm considering going back to being a paid TEMP driver than one under a contractor (by the stop), because when bad weather comes (snow/ice), my productivity goes out the window.

One of my coworkers gave his 2 weeks notice to a contractor recently because he's burnt out after 3 years of constant RUNNING and being overloaded everyday. good for him &amp; If I can get a better job in this economy, I'll follow his footsteps]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>166</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Henry]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email/>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>173.88.234.79</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-10-23 23:58:39</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-10-24 06:58:39</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Yet another bad experience with Fed Ex Home Delivery. I was waiting for a package to come (scheduled to be delivered today, Saturday), only to find that the delivery man was unable to deliver, and just left the door tag. I live in an apartment, but there is a buzzer on each apartment. He was able to fill out the door tag but wasnt able to just push the buzzer so my wife could come out (maybe 10 feet from the door) to get the package. My wife does not work and is therefore home all day and she knew i was waiting for a package. Honestly will never order anything that uses fedex home delivery again, now i have to wait til tuesday because i apparently cant pick up the package and customer service was a joke of course. 2nd day delivery my ass. If the fedex delivery man had no hands i can understand how he couldnt ring the buzzer but in that case he shouldnt be driving a truck. Otherwise no reason why my new phone i ordered shouldnt be in my own hands right now.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>167</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[to henry]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ricebike@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.251.138.212</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-11-19 07:29:45</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-11-19 14:29:45</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[this branch of FedEx (Home Delivery) doesn't offer "2nd day delivery"

sign the door tag and leave a note to make sure to ring the correct doorbell... sometimes those door bells aren't labeled &amp; i would ring them ALL :P until someone comes to the door to unlock it]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>168</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[to Santi]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>santidarkg@yahoo.es</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>160.33.43.15</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-11-19 17:47:01</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-11-20 00:47:01</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Canon sent my CAnon 5d camera to my house. I am living 45 mins away from Irvine (Canon is there).

Fedex sent my camera to Atlanta, what the hell..... by ground. I have been calling them everyday, where is my camera, because the stupid tracking didn't updte in 4 days... of course, my camera was in its way to Atlanta.

I lost three clients this week, this means, I have to feed my family and I am losing money right now.

I am calling everyday and they say somebody is going to call me............ and nothing. Now seems my camera is coming back to California, BY GROUND again. Another week, more problems with my clients, etc.

I dont know how I can complaint but this week has been very bad for my family too.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>169</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[art]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>art@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>76.93.23.207</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-11-20 16:43:49</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-11-20 23:43:49</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[im tracking my package and it was delivered to the wrong person in the wrong city...
i call then and they read back my mailing adress then i get a call saying they did deliver the package and email me a name that i have never heard of  when i tell them  that name does not tell me anything they say the driver says that's me... i tell them when i track it it shows it was delivered in the wrong city??? paid extra to get my stuff on a Saturday noww
i have to wait until Monday for them to figure out wtf happen to my package...

i didn't know fedex was employing that many retards]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1345</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:49:29</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:49:29</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[you think fedex home delivery is bad, try fedex ground]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>156</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292874570]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292874570.6355";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1344</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:43:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:43:20</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[everyone thinks there is one fedex, if your saying overnite, that is fedex express............you also have fedex ground and fedex home delivery and there is no overnite involved]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>164</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292874200]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292874202.5505";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1343</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:34:38</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:34:38</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[if its 2nd day delivery then thats fedex express not home delivery, i dont know why a driver would not ring your bell because he has to come back and reattempt and with it being a phone, that is definitely fedex express]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>166</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292873678]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292873678.5213";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1342</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:29:43</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:29:43</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[if its home delivery its tues thru saturday, if you say your paying extra for saturday delivery then thats fedex express]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>169</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292873383]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292873383.5431";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1341</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:27:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:27:31</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[if its just a indirect signature you can leave a note on your door that you give authorization to fedex to leave your package and then the driver will take your note as your signature.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292873251]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292873251.0748";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1340</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[billy]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>golfgod_00@hotmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>108.73.25.107</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-20 11:25:20</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-20 19:25:20</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[you guys must have some crappy drivers, I'm a fedex home delivery driver in kansas and run rural route, i run 100% service everyday for the past 5 yrs.....i know not all door bells work, so i will push it and knock on the door, if it requires signature, i try by all means to get it delivered because i do not like taking packages back, that means i have to come back the next day, if there is a phone number on the package i will call, i like to come back with a empty truck, now if there is a neighbor i will try to get them to sign for your package, theres never been a address i havent been able to find, most are repeat customers so i know right where you are............here in kansas weve had more problems with fedex ground than home delivery, they cry if they have to go out into rural areas. as for me i keep a notebook of addresses and if i catch a business with a name i will write the business down, so if i have a home address with a signature, rings a bell in my head....oh they are this business, then i will just go to the business, instead of going to the house when no ones there...........like i said i do whatever it takes to get it off my truck and make the customer happy.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1292873120]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1292873120.4079";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1438</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Frank smith]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>tdawg7@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url/>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>174.27.171.39</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2011-03-18 19:04:22</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2011-03-19 03:04:22</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I don't buy it. I work for home delivery and we don't get paid unless we deliver the package. It is pointless to put a note on a door day after day for free. You had to have left or been out of hearing range of the doorbell. I can't tell you how many times I get a call from my manager asking me to return and try delivering again. And while delivering the package the customer admits to having left for a short period of time or was in the backyard working. This makes more sense. I hate working for free.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>22</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1300503863]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1300503863.7133";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1371</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[swing driver]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>ricebike@yahoo.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://fedexaminer.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>71.251.135.190</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2010-12-29 07:16:09</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2010-12-29 15:16:09</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[boo hoo, the only things i find online are complaints... never seen compliments on websites on the GOOD Fedex Home Delivery drivers... 

customers, we slap those stupid post it notes on your doors for a reason... call the # 800 to weed out the bad drivers from the good ones

I've seen too many bad/lazy drivers still working at the terminals that I work with &amp; without your input to the company directly, instead of airing your complaints on a message board, they'll never know to reprimand or suspend that driver you guys are observing

I've switched to the temp service to get paid by the hour &amp; now 1/2 of my customers have my cellphone number; I told them that i'm just a temp and you won't see me past Xmas... hopefully the regular driver can keep them happy when the new year rolls around and we are let go.
Happy Holidays]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type/>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1293635770]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
			<wp:commentmeta>
				<wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
				<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:15:"1293635771.0293";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp:meta_value>
			</wp:commentmeta>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>