<item>
		<title>Obama-McCain Debate Part 3</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/10/16/obama-mccain-debate-part-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 18:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/10/16/obama-mccain-debate-part-3/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[McCain's did well in "last night's debate":http://www.cnn.com/2008/POLITICS/10/15/debate.transcript/index.html with his eloquence and calm demeanor:

bq.  Now, we have allocated $750 billion. Let's take 300 of that billion and go in and buy those home loan mortgages and negotiate with those people in their homes, 11 million homes or more, so that they can afford to pay the mortgage, stay in their home.

Good idea. All the people who can pay their mortgage obviously have enough money to pay the mortgages of others. It's only fair.

bq. Now, I know the criticism of this.

Criticism? Who could criticize this?! Don't listen to critics or those high-fallutin' economists, John.

bq. Well, what about the citizen that stayed in their homes? That paid their mortgage payments? It doesn't help that person in their home if the next door neighbor's house is abandoned. And so we've got to reverse this. We ought to put the homeowners first. And I am disappointed that Secretary Paulson and others have not made that their first priority.

Yes, everyone should pay their neighbors' mortgage because if they can't afford their mortgage and have to move or abandon their house, I can't sell my house. Ever. Any time you sell a house the first question potential buyers ask is "Has your neighbor ever lost their home?". We can't have that. It's patriotic to pay the mortgages of others.

<!--more-->

bq. Joe wants to buy the business that he has been in for all of these years, worked 10, 12 hours a day. And he wanted to buy the business but he looked at your tax plan and he saw that he was going to pay much higher taxes.

Joe the Plumber is going to make $250,000/year in personal income and no way, no how can he hire people rather than take all that money as personal income. That's just not the way LLCs or S-Corps work, not at all. You are required to not spend profits on your business, you have to take the profits as income. John really knows his stuff.

bq. Fifty percent of small business income taxes are paid by small businesses. That's 16 million jobs in America. And what you want to do to Joe the plumber and millions more like him is have their taxes increased and not be able to realize the American dream of owning their own business.

50% of small business taxes are paid by small business. That's way too high. Small businesses should not be paying half of their taxes. Small business taxes should be paid by medium-sized businesses, medium-sized business taxes should be paid by large businesses and large business taxes should be paid for by tax-payers. Go McCain!

bq. You know, when Sen. Obama ended up his conversation with Joe the plumber -- we need to spread the wealth around. In other words, we're going to take Joe's money, give it to Sen. Obama, and let him spread the wealth around.

We need to spread the wealth around to people who can't pay their mortgages.

bq.  The whole premise behind Sen. Obama's plans are class warfare, let's spread the wealth around. I want small businesses -- and by the way, the small businesses that we're talking about would receive an increase in their taxes right now.

Class warfare would be bad. That's why McCain's plan to keep the rich rich and the poor poor and prevent any movement between the classes prevents class warfare. We need to just keep people in their places.

bq. Who -- why would you want to increase anybody's taxes right now?

And for that matter, why would we want to decrease the national debt right now?!

bq. The fact is that businesses in America today are paying the second highest tax rate of anywhere in the world. Our tax rate for business in America is 35 percent. Ireland, it's 11 percent. Where are companies going to go where they can create jobs and where they can do best in business?

To Ireland? Ireland has had the world's lowest tax rate "since 1954":http://www.kpmg.ie/inv_irl/why/corpo.htm, there's hardly any company not in Ireland today. They're just flocking to Ireland where the population is so huge there's plenty of people to work for American companies there.

bq. We need to cut the business tax rate in America. We need to encourage business.

Poor American businesses, all discouraged.

bq. Now, of all times in America, we need to cut people's taxes. We need to encourage business, create jobs, not spread the wealth around.

We should let the wealth trickle down, not be spread around. Trickle, not spread.

bq. OK, what -- what would I cut? I would have, first of all, across-the-board spending freeze, OK? Some people say that's a hatchet. That's a hatchet, and then I would get out a scalpel, OK?

Ok, that's better. A scalpel after the hatchet. I'm going to go clean up my garage, with a bulldozer and then I'll take a broom to it. I like the way you think, John.

bq.  Because we've got -- we have presided over the largest increase -- we've got to have a new direction for this country. We have presided over the largest increase in government since the Great Society. Government spending has gone completely out of control; $10 trillion dollar debt we're giving to our kids, a half-a-trillion dollars we owe China.

By "we" you mean "you", right? You did a great job presiding over the largest increase in government, John. You've done such a good job with increasing the size of government, I bet you can do an even better job at decreasing the size.

bq. I know how to save billions of dollars in defense spending. I know how to eliminate programs.

You sure do! And just like fixing the economy and catching Bin Laden, you'll tell us how to do it only after you get elected. Career First!

bq.  I would eliminate the tariff on imported sugarcane-based ethanol from Brazil.

More importing!

bq. Yes. Sen. Obama, I am not President Bush. If you wanted to run against President Bush, you should have run four years ago.

Good one John!! You aren't Bush at all. You're old enough to be his father and short enough to be his son. You're nothing like him. You may vote with him and agree with him on everything he does, but that's where the similarities end.

bq. I'm going to give a new direction to this economy in this country.

Just like you give your campaign a new direction every few weeks.

bq. Well, this has been a tough campaign. It's been a very tough campaign. And I know from my experience in many campaigns that, if Sen. Obama had asked -- responded to my urgent request to sit down, and do town hall meetings, and come before the American people, we could have done at least 10 of them by now. So I think the tone of this campaign could have been very different.

Obama deserves the negative campaigning for not agreeing to 10 townhall meetings that you wanted. Revenge is sweet!

bq.  And the fact is, it's gotten pretty tough. And I regret some of the negative aspects of both campaigns. But the fact is that it has taken many turns which I think are unacceptable. One of them happened just the other day, when a man I admire and respect -- I've written about him -- Congressman John Lewis, an American hero, made allegations that Sarah Palin and I were somehow associated with the worst chapter in American history, segregation, deaths of children in church bombings, George Wallace. That, to me, was so hurtful.

Stop it, John. I'm tearing up. That big meanie John Lewis made your feelings hurt. How dare Obama, I mean John Lewis, do that to you. You were just minding your own business running for President and, sniffle, someone says things that you didn't like. There there, Johnny. What can we do? If we elect you President will you feel all better?

bq. And, Sen. Obama, when he said -- and he signed a piece of paper that said he would take public financing for his campaign if I did -- that was back when he was a long-shot candidate -- you didn't keep your word.

Obama didn't use tax-payer money to run for President? What kind of evil person wouldn't take tax-payer money to run for President? What'd he do, go collect money from people who wanted to donate to his campaign? That's un-American! Tax-payers should pay your bills, John. And the way you've used those dollars so efficiently to run a brilliant campaign is more proof that you'd use tax-payer dollars so efficiently as President.

bq. Well, if you'll turn on the television, as I -- I watched the Arizona Cardinals defeat the Dallas Cowboys on Sunday. Every other ad -- ever other ad was an attack ad on my health care plan.

What?! Obama advertised during a football game when your Cardinals beat the Cowboys? That's not fair. Is there no decency in this campaign? Ads should only be run when your team is losing.

bq. Well, Americans have gotten to know Sarah Palin. They know that she's a role model to women and other -- and reformers all over America.

She is a role model. She's not unethical, she doesn't abuse her power, she doesn't ask for earmarks, she raises kids who get pregnant, she is highly-educated and speaks so eqloquently, she forces women to pay to prove they were raped. I wish more women could be just like Sarah Palin.

bq. She's a reformer through and through. And it's time we had that bresh of freth air (sic) -- breath of fresh air coming into our nation's capital and sweep out the old-boy network and the cronyism that's been so much a part of it that I've fought against for all these years.

She is a freth bresh! We need her to sweep out the old-boy network in Washington. Any Congressman that has been there for, say, over 25 years should be swept right out!

bq. She'll be my partner. She understands reform. And, by the way, she also understands special-needs families. She understands that autism is on the rise, that we've got to find out what's causing it, and we've got to reach out to these families, and help them, and give them the help they need as they raise these very special needs children.

Yeah, she's been a huge supporter of special needs children from way back... way way way back... back to several months ago when she gave birth to a special needs child. Nobody knows more and has done more for special needs children than Sarah Palin. Just like she's the most knowledgeable person on energy, she's the most knowledgeable on special needs children, way more knowledgeable than people who have had special needs children for years. Who could doubt that?

bq. Her husband's a pretty tough guy, by the way, too.

Good point. It's very important to mention that.

bq.  We can eliminate our dependence on foreign oil by building 45 new nuclear plants, power plants, right away. We can store and we can reprocess. Sen. Obama will tell you, in the -- as the extreme environmentalists do, it has to be safe.

Those environmentalists as extreme! Safety? Please. Americans are tough people, just like Sarah Palin's husband, they can withstand a little radiation. No biggie. Safety is the last thing we should be concerned about with nuclear energy. Those crazies who were scared of Three Mile Island and those people who died in Chernobyl are extremists.

bq. Look, we've sailed Navy ships around the world for 60 years with nuclear power plants on them.

And Navy ships sail right through major cities in America. You know, those big American cities in the middle of the ocean. Those people are fine. What could go wrong?

bq. I would consider anyone in their qualifications. I do not believe that someone who has supported Roe v. Wade that would be part of those qualifications. But I certainly would not impose any litmus test.

That's not a litmus test at all. You won't even let someone take your litmus test based on their Roe v. Wade views. How can anyone call that a litmus test? Clearly, Roe v. Wade doesn't even enter into your decision about Supreme Court justices.

bq. We have to change the culture of America. Those of us who are proudly pro-life understand that. And it's got to be courage and compassion that we show to a young woman who's facing this terribly difficult decision.

We need to have the courage and compassion to change the culture of America. America's culture and beliefs are just plain wrong, we need to change it, just like a good Democracy does.

bq. Just again, the example of the eloquence of Sen. Obama. He's health for the mother. You know, that's been stretched by the pro-abortion movement in America to mean almost anything. That's the extreme pro-abortion position, quote, "health."

Health! Stupid liberals care about health and the safety of the mother's life. Screw the mother, her life isn't worth nearly as much as that baby's life. Damn extremists caring about health of people. That's as dumb as caring about safety of nuclear energy.

bq. Of course, we have to work together, and, of course, it's vital that we do so and help these young women who are facing such a difficult decision, with a compassion, that we'll help them with the adoptive services, with the courage to bring that child into this world and we'll help take care of it.

Yes, let's just think about solving problems that have happened. Trying to prevent the pregnancy in the first place is pointless. What good would that do?

bq.  So choice and competition amongst schools is one of the key elements that's already been proven in places in like New Orleans and New York City and other places, where we have charter schools, where we take good teachers and we reward them and promote them. And we find bad teachers another line of work.

Those who can, do. Those who can't do, manage. Those who can't manage, teach. Those who can't teach, well, I don't know what they'll do, but don't worry, we'll find something for them to do.

bq. We need to encourage programs such as Teach for America and Troops to Teachers where people, after having served in the military, can go right to teaching and not have to take these examinations which -- or have the certification that some are required in some states.

This is a good idea. Take people out of the military and put them right in the classroom, without any sort of examinations or certifications. If you can fire a gun, you can teach a kid. It's as simple as that.

bq.  America needs a new direction. We cannot be satisfied with what we've been doing for the last eight years.

We are all very satisfied with what we've been doing the last eight years. But John's right, we shoudn't be. If there's anyone who can bring us in a new direction it's the guy who has been taking us in the same direction for 26 years.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3510</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-10-16 11:52:25</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-10-16 18:52:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>obama-mccain-debate-part-3</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>