<item>
		<title>Sunday beer</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2009/04/12/3634/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2009 18:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/?p=3634</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[For Saturday evening I wanted to have a special beer so I looked into the beer/wine fridge for something new to try. I decided on the <a href="http://www.ommegang.com/index.php?mcat=1&amp;scat=6">Ommegang Ommegeddon</a> because Ommegang is a great beer-maker and even though it has brettanomyces in it, which I don't like, if it can be used for a good beer Ommegang should be able to do it. And it's dry-hopped, which I really like.

<!--more-->Ommegang's description:
<blockquote>Ommegeddon is 8% ABV Belgian-style ale with a wild twist -- a dose of Brettanomyces yeast and a blast of dry hopping. It's a strong blonde ale with a sharp citrus flavor that, like the other Ommegang ales, has a dry finish. Its dryness and funkiness begat the name of Ommegeddon -- for the time when the forces of light and dark battle for world dominion. It's time for you to pick your side.</blockquote>
Unfortunately, it's bottle-conditioned and the bottle was on its side in the fridge so the yeast sediment had not settled at the bottom. So I put it in the regular fridge for Sunday instead.

It's a very light-colored beer and I didn't detect any hop aromas at all. I figured it was too cold and I'd let it warm up a little. But then it smelled like a musty basement. Blech. The taste was nothing special although it wasn't as sour as I'd have expected with the brettanomyces.

<a title="Ommegang Ommegeddon by troyh, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/troyh/3439099376/"><img class="centered" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3305/3439099376_a8f8b60bc6.jpg" alt="Ommegang Ommegeddon" width="500" height="333" /></a>

I ended up not finishing the little bit I poured and decided to treat myself to something I knew I'd like: Dogfish Head's Black &amp; Blue. I had this <a href="http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/06/01/dogfish-head-black-blue/">last year in June</a> and really liked it. But that day was hot and today was cold and rainy so I didn't expect it to be as enjoyable. It didn't beat my memory of the last one I had and it tasted more like a fruit-punch beer, but I liked it a lot.

<a title="Dogfish Head Black &amp; Blue by troyh, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/troyh/3438287837/"><img class="centered" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3299/3438287837_9457964244.jpg" alt="Dogfish Head Black &amp; Blue" width="333" height="500" /></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3634</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-04-12 11:31:31</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-04-12 18:31:31</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>3634</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>