<item>
		<title>Levi Johnston's bright future</title>
		<link>http://troyandgay.com/2008/10/13/levi-johnstons-bright-future/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 21:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>troyh</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://troyandgay.com/blog/2008/10/13/levi-johnstons-bright-future/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Bristol Palin's baby dadda, Levi Johnston, "corrects the stories about him":http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/P/PALIN_WASILLA_HEARTTHROB?SITE=CTDAN&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT:

bq. The baby is due Dec. 18. Johnston has dropped out of high school to take a job on the North Slope oil fields as an apprentice electrician.

Good idea! A high school education will only stand in your way of earning a good living to support your baby. Always think about today because tomorrow may never come. And what better place to learn to be an electrician than an oil field? Levi Johnston is a wise <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">kid</span> man. Stupid me, I learned to be a software developer at a software development company... I should have learned computer science at a textile mill.

<!--more-->

bq. For starters, he said his much-maligned MySpace page was a joke - the one that claimed he said: "I'm a ... redneck," and "I don't want kids." Johnston said his friends created the page a few years ago and he had nothing to do with it.

Sure they did. What friends wouldn't spend their time making up a MySpace page for you that has such hilarious jokes like "I don't want kids"? That's what makes it so funny -- high school kids making friendly jabs at their friends like saying they don't want kids. It's funny because everyone knows high school kids, especially boys, are all about babies. It's really all they think about... that and their fairy tale wedding. Clearly, Levi isn't a redneck either, far from it! It's just another clever joke by his friends.

bq. Johnston said he has dated Palin since his freshman year in high school. "We were planning on getting married a long time ago with or without the kid," he said. "That was the plan from the start."

I'm sure. All 9th-graders are thinking marriage. And 10th-graders spend a great deal of time thinking about retirement. That's just what high school kids do.

bq. [A friend] doesn't think anyone pressured Johnston into marriage. "If he thought it wasn't the right thing to do he probably wouldn't do it," he said.

Just like he thinks dropping out of high school is the right thing to do. I mean, he _probably_ wouldn't do it if it wasn't the right thing to do.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3504</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2008-10-13 07:29:42</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2008-10-13 21:29:42</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>levi-johnstons-bright-future</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password/>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
	</item>